<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Projects | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/projects/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-16T19:43:58-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design: UniCycle]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/unicycle/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-09T15:22:52-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/unicycle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For HCDE 518 the theme of our projects was &ldquo;UX for Good.&rdquo; I teamed up with three others (Joshua Coppola, Irene Huberman, and Matt Yukubousky) who were interested in solving climate change, and after admitting that &ldquo;solving climate change&rdquo; was going to be out of scope for the quarter, we searched for ways that we could encourage people to make better environmental choices.</p>

<p>One problem in encouraging environmentally friendly choices is that the immediate results of such choices are often negative. Good environmental decisions don&rsquo;t pay off for the actual environment immediately, and often your only tangible &ldquo;reward&rdquo; is the fact that you&rsquo;ve spent more time or money being good, as in the case of going to farmer&rsquo;s markets to buy organic or local produce. (Though for some I know the payoff of farmer&rsquo;s markets is better-tasting food, and forming relationships with the community, etc.)</p>

<p>We were all interested in designing <em>something</em> for our nearby community, and at some point someone finally brought up the concept of &ldquo;freecycling,&rdquo; which is the term for a community that gives and gets items from each other for free. (In this sense, it&rsquo;s really more like &ldquo;free-reusing&rdquo; than &ldquo;free-recycling.&rdquo;) We realized that such a system is perfect for implementation in a college campus, where living situations are temporary and fluid, requiring people to predictably give and get furniture like beds and couches when the academic year turns. Additionally, undergraduates in particular, lacking free-flowing cash, have a need of used items like textbooks and whatever other paraphernalia required of them in classes, like clickers. Groups in Seattle exist already for freecycling, such as <a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/freecycleseattle/info">Seattle Freecycle</a>, but none geared specifically for students who might need to quickly get rid of a bed before move-out, or require a specific edition of a book for a class.</p>

<p>Realizations in hand, we established our design question: <strong>How can we use technology to encourage reuse of goods within the University of Washington community?</strong></p>

<p>And after Bruce Perry came up with the perfect name for our project — <em>UniCycle</em> — we were all in.</p>

<h2>Surveys</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/surveys.png" alt="Screenshot of some survey responses."/></p>

<p class="caption">screenshot of some survey responses</p>


<p>We developed a (somewhat long-ass) survey to kick off our user research, and distributed it across our social networks, the UW group we found at Reddit, and a Facebook group devoted to &ldquo;UW Textbook Exchange.&rdquo; The feedback we received overall to the idea of &ldquo;a site where people can easily exchange textbooks&rdquo; was very positive:</p>

<blockquote>“This idea is great and I hope it takes form soon! It eliminates the middle man like buffalo exchange that rips off the sellers and charges more for certain items to buyers to make profit." - /u/huskygurll</blockquote>


<p>On the bright side, we learned that there are some clear pain points when students try to get rid of their stuff. Though many students desire to sell their textbooks and furniture, many do not because they don&rsquo;t want to go through the hassle of setting up prices, haggling, meeting up with people. In the case of female students, there was also the extra overhead of making sure they were safe when interacting with strangers.</p>

<p>Though we initially wanted to create a site that was devoted to <em>just</em> students giving each other things for free, students' reported consciousness of money made this unfeasible. Survey participants reported occasinally that, if they could not get enough money for Item X, they&rsquo;d rather keep it. With this in mind, we decided to design a hub for students to not just give each other things for free, but also sell or barter them away. &ldquo;Free items&rdquo; could continue to be our main headliner, however, something to draw people in the same way that Priceline draws customers with their &ldquo;name your own price&rdquo; system.</p>

<h2>Design Mapping</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/designmapping.png" alt="Team UniCycle design mapping, and a close-up photo of the design mapping."/></p>

<p class="caption">design mapping</p>


<p>One design technique that was new to be this quarter was <strong>design mapping</strong>, which involves thinking through a user flow and taking note of everything that comes up using sticky notes. Green notes can stand for goals, pink notes for concerns, yellow for extra considerations, blue for possible new features — and so on. One thing I love about design mapping is that you are able to keep track of everything. When talking about how to support Yosh&rsquo;s desire to buy an old couch online, we don&rsquo;t need to silence the person that starts talking about bed bugs, and chastise them for going off-topic — we just add it to the map, and continue forward.</p>

<p>Design mapping helped us get a grip on the kinds of behaviors that we wanted to support with UniCycle: buy a used item, put a used item up for sale, contact a seller, and so on.</p>

<h2>Sketches</h2>


<p>We did a ton of sketches. Just, tons of them.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/sketches2.png" alt="Sketching UniCycle UI on a whiteboard."/></p>

<p class="caption">here are just a few of them</p>


<p>I have to admit that it was hard to come up with so many ideas individually and then have to figure out how to actually move forward. It took us most of the afternoon, a huge whiteboard, and a lot of back-and-forth to decide on the almost-final interface that we wanted to go with, Once we did decide, it was tough to decide who was going to have the responsibility of moving forward with creating a paper prototype, or creating a digital prototype with something like Axure, which some of us wanted experience using.</p>

<p>It was at this time that we decided to try out a search based on &ldquo;hashtags,&rdquo; like Twitter or Tumblr. Because people could sell a variety of items on this site, we thought this would best allow them to categorize their items as they see fit. Additionally, hashtags like <code>#chem300</code> could be catch-alls for whatever you needed for a Chemistry 300 course: textbooks, clickers, lab coats, and so on.</p>

<h2>Paper Prototyping</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/paperprototype.png" alt="Photos of the UniCycle paper prototype."/></p>

<p class="caption">photos of the paper prototype</p>


<p>I took partial responsibility for the paper prototype and the ensuing paper-scrap fest. Rendering the variety of items that people could &ldquo;search for&rdquo; using our paper UI was the most challenging bit, as was searching for the right pieces to show on the display. We created little modals to mimic &ldquo;Loading results&hellip;&rdquo; which were fun to use, and we also tried to solve for cases in which our paper prototype testers might search for an item that we didn&rsquo;t anticipate.</p>

<h2>Interactive Prototype</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/unicycle_prototype.png" alt="Screenshot of UniCycle Interactive Prototype."/></p>

<p class="caption">screenshot of UniCycle's interactive prototype</p>


<p>Our final product was an interactive prototype made in Axure by all of us, using a pretty fantastic blend of Axure&rsquo;s built-in SVN versioning and Dropbox. It is currently hosted <a href="http://students.washington.edu/jhc1/hcde518/start.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>My most beloved aspects of it are those that give feedback to users' actions. For example, the main page features tickets that enumerate the number of goods reused thus far, to surface the fact that people really <em>are</em> accomplishing something great through their small actions.</p>

<p>We also have some special tweaks just for UW students. For example, if you are looking for a particular textbook, you can list it on UniCycle. If you&rsquo;re selling, you can list a book by ISBN and have the titles and authors filled in automatically. Once you list a book, you are also made aware of the number of people who might already have that book marked as &ldquo;wanted&rdquo; — which is intended to help people feel like it&rsquo;s easy to sell on UniCycle. We also surface &ldquo;duedates&rdquo; for items, valuable if a user is trying to get rid of a bed before their lease is up.</p>

<p>After having dealt with it for a majority of the quarter, I&rsquo;m not totally sold on Axure yet, and will not likely use it to personally make hi-fidelity prototypes in the future. At that point in the process, I&rsquo;d just prefer to code things up myself. Additionally, I personally love the speed and humble honesty of paper prototyping, compared to Axure&rsquo;s interactive prototypes, which to me slip somewhat into the uncanny valley.</p>

<p>That being said, I&rsquo;m sure there will come a time when Axure is uniquely valuable, and I did like having to <em>not</em> worry about vertically centering random elements in CSS. Coding UniCycle as the sole programmer in a team of four would have been extremely taxing and it&rsquo;s nice that using Axure allowed us to work on a level playing field.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>


<p>I don&rsquo;t know that I&rsquo;ll return to UniCycle given the plethora of other projects I have, but it would be great to see it go places, especially given the need for it at UW. Too much goes wasted, and I&rsquo;d love to see people get into the habit of asking their community for needed items, as well as help others when it&rsquo;s needed.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also made a <a href="/files/hcde518_portfolio_deck.pdf">portfolio deck</a> that goes over other details for this project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Invent-o-thon]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/inventathon/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T16:09:18-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/inventathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A is starting a certificate program in game design this quarter and I&rsquo;ve been helping him with his card game, Invent-o-thon.</p>

<p>The prompt being something related to <em>Victorian Combat</em>, he first went around researching what people &ldquo;first thought of when they think about the Victorian Era,&rdquo; and I was happy to hammer in the presence of Ada Lovelace, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace">The World&rsquo;s First Computer Programmer</a>. Because I&rsquo;m more interested in stories, I also talked with him about stories — in particular, making noteworthy experiences that people are excited to talk to each other about after the fact. Or, in general, creating situations in which people&rsquo;s imaginations are prompted and stretch and fill in ridiculous gaps.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/playtest1.jpg" alt="What is a faith-powered tummy mobile?"/></p>

<p class="caption">what is a faith-powered tummy mobile FIGURE IT OUT DO IT</p>


<p>A obtained a bunch of card sleeves and post-it notes for our paper prototyping. The point of the game is to create an invention over several rounds, then present it at &ldquo;showtime&rdquo; to everyone and roll dice to see if your invention explodes. Thus far, players construct machines using three decks: one deck to describe a &ldquo;power source&rdquo; (like &ldquo;electric&rdquo;), one deck to describe a &ldquo;subject&rdquo; (like &ldquo;kittens&rdquo;), and one deck to describe the actual invention (like &ldquo;generator&rdquo;).</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/playtest1_cards.JPG" alt="Playtest cards"/></p>

<p class="caption">physically impossible bathtub packer</p>


<p>We also gathered friends to do a playtest at a cafe.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/playtest2.jpg" alt="Playtest cards"/></p>

<p class="caption">kind of pathetic pleasure chamber...and others</p>


<p>One of the most valuable things learned from prototyping was which cards were compelling and funny, and which cards weren&rsquo;t — descriptive cards that seemed perfectly fine, like &ldquo;hydro-powered&rdquo; or &ldquo;solar-powered,&rdquo; were just not as fun to use as &ldquo;perfectly ordinary&rdquo; or &ldquo;rather moist&rdquo; and never quite made it to showtime. It makes sense that something like &ldquo;perfectly ordinary&rdquo; lights up more parts of your story-minded brain than &ldquo;hydro-powered,&rdquo; and overall could have more flavor. (What&rsquo;s a &ldquo;perfectly ordinary kitten-mobile&rdquo;?)</p>

<p>I sketched out some possibilities for card designs&hellip;</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/cardsketch.jpg" alt="Sketches of cards"/></p>

<p class="caption">sketches of cards</p>


<p>&hellip;and A also reined in his sister for some concept art of character roles that players could have that affected their inventions. For example, someone who was Benjamin Franklin might be able to totally swap inventions with someone else before showtime. (Oo! Sick burn!)</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/concept.jpg" alt="Concept art of Nikola Tesla"/></p>

<p class="caption">concept art of Nikola Tesla</p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elements Sketches]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/16/elements-sketches/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/16/elements-sketches</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
At Fugazo, I was hired initially to design a hidden object game. I've made a couple of posts about&nbsp;<a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/search?q=hidden+object">this type of game</a>, but never talked about mine, which was going to be a fantastical version a la <a href="http://www.boomzap.com/">Boomzap</a>'s <i>Awakening</i> series, which would hopefully shine in a market saturated with grimy amusement parks and children being stolen and dangled off cliff-ledges by evil wizards.<br /><br />The premise of the story was that a village had had its special crown stolen by a thief, who wanted it for a queen in a distant land, who in turn wanted it so she could look cool at parties. The crown was a symbol of the ancient pact the village had with the elements, and upon its disappearance havoc arose: cookfires burst, water slid away from mouths and flasks, the air blew cold, stones rolled across the feet of weary villagers, etc.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YtmP55ls_xA/UAN1Xkcy1CI/AAAAAAAABqs/WjAqz6RtxtQ/s1600/elements+map+3.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="481" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YtmP55ls_xA/UAN1Xkcy1CI/AAAAAAAABqs/WjAqz6RtxtQ/s640/elements+map+3.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a sketch of the world map;<br />the big part is the temple, the bottom-left part the village</td></tr></tbody></table><br />The elemental avatars were housed in a temple with four quarters on some massive landmass overlooking the village. Wanting to set things straight, the villagers send a girl to temple to make peace, and she ventures bravely despite the fact that avatars are known to turn annoying trespassers into statues or sparrows or whatever else pleases them. Upon arriving at the temple, the girl runs into a talking hawk, who aids her in her quest with dry banter and the occasional vague StarCraft reference. ("You need more crystals! ...to finish this mini-game")<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-c-L6g8ERer0/UAOpUQ1fCiI/AAAAAAAABsE/PW2TzcL9s_s/s1600/elements+dragon.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-c-L6g8ERer0/UAOpUQ1fCiI/AAAAAAAABsE/PW2TzcL9s_s/s640/elements+dragon.jpg" width="584" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the avatar of the fire temple, a kind of fuzzy dragoness</td></tr></tbody></table><br />In the end, it turns out that the hawk has been the thief all along; he had been turned into a hawk as punishment for getting lost and rummaging around the sacred temple. At the conclusion of the game, an epic match-three-kinda mini-game ensues in which the girl/you defeat him and win the crown back.<br /><br />I spent a lot of time playing other games for ideas on mini-games, and prototyping them out on paper, and testing them against coworkers.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-1ZQsf6z184g/UAN4jKVzGbI/AAAAAAAABrA/t4dbVRs3tpA/s1600/c1d4510e072011e1a87612313804ec91_7.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-1ZQsf6z184g/UAN4jKVzGbI/AAAAAAAABrA/t4dbVRs3tpA/s320/c1d4510e072011e1a87612313804ec91_7.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a photo of a paper prototype inspired by UW's <a href="http://games.cs.washington.edu/Refraction/refraction.html">Refraction</a></td></tr></tbody></table><br />I also spent a non-negligible amount of time outlining the various areas of the temple in a composition notebook, which I filled to the margins with cheap ballpoint ink (as it is a favorite tool of mine, beside Steadler mechanical pencils).<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6xHGGSMHnWE/UAN395Irb3I/AAAAAAAABq4/oLIc7ojXnkc/s1600/elements+earth+temple.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="408" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6xHGGSMHnWE/UAN395Irb3I/AAAAAAAABq4/oLIc7ojXnkc/s640/elements+earth+temple.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(page 1/2) a scan of my sketchbook with various areas drawn out for the "earth temple"</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-l9XshfoY4Tk/UAOq_xYyZBI/AAAAAAAABsM/CE3zetuT_Hs/s1600/elements+forest.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="415" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-l9XshfoY4Tk/UAOq_xYyZBI/AAAAAAAABsM/CE3zetuT_Hs/s640/elements+forest.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(page 2/2) a scan of my sketchbook with various areas drawn out for the "earth temple" </td></tr></tbody></table><br />I also laid out certain rooms and angles for detail and fun.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--x7SzByFqJ8/UAN50iElStI/AAAAAAAABrI/l2aJAKT3C-M/s1600/elements+fire+temple.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="185" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--x7SzByFqJ8/UAN50iElStI/AAAAAAAABrI/l2aJAKT3C-M/s320/elements+fire+temple.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">sketch of the fire temple's "tea room"</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-B4vx2Xcbrws/UAN53Woe0FI/AAAAAAAABrQ/OHHMFzZI2Mg/s1600/elements+water+throne.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="184" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-B4vx2Xcbrws/UAN53Woe0FI/AAAAAAAABrQ/OHHMFzZI2Mg/s320/elements+water+throne.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">sketch of the water temple's "throne room"</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-c5z8VivuyT0/UAN5_IwrX6I/AAAAAAAABrY/I4cvgSpziUk/s1600/elements+fire+overhead.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-c5z8VivuyT0/UAN5_IwrX6I/AAAAAAAABrY/I4cvgSpziUk/s640/elements+fire+overhead.jpg" width="434" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">sketch of the fire temple</td></tr></tbody></table><br />One unfortunate thing is that I don't have much in-game art to show. Since the art made from these sketches is "really" the work of my team's artists, I'm not comfortable sharing it. What mini-games were implemented aren't something that can be easily shared either, as are the environments and dialogue that I scripted out using our in-game scene editor...so, bummer.<br /><br />Why was the project canceled? Mainly because our small team (one designer, one programmer, and roughly four artists) couldn't compete with much larger teams working on the market. Art style is at the forefront of the hidden object genre, with many players turning away if something is too dark or too colorful, and we didn't have the power to create, polish, and re-polish within a reasonable timeframe, especially with the paint-y style that we wanted to move forward with. &nbsp;There was also greater interest with pursuing more "game-y" games, hidden objects being fairly linear.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-mPTPHA4aTQo/UAOokIYbyJI/AAAAAAAABr8/bTRj-F6cECw/s1600/elements+air+temple.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="408" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-mPTPHA4aTQo/UAOokIYbyJI/AAAAAAAABr8/bTRj-F6cECw/s640/elements+air+temple.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">sketches of the air temple, which (spoilers) was going to be on the back of a bird<br />that blue is a plastic tape-bookmarker-thing</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Perhaps some elements of...Elements...will be recycled for future projects.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[~*New, Fancy Noobling Blog*~]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2010/11/26/new-fancy-noobling-blog/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2010/11/26/new-fancy-noobling-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
My favorite thing to do is start projects, particularly those that involve huge copious amounts of writing, so it stands to reason that I've been wanting for like forever to make a blog in which I could attempt making pro conversation/discussion with myself about things that I want to learn/practice/improve upon in general.<br /><br />My project threads are as follows:<br /><ul><li><strong>Red Moleskine:</strong> For whatever form inspiration strikes in, including abruptly making some observation about the weather, drawing up a database schema for a web app (that I found out has already been done), sketching out shiba inu people, etc. etc.</li><li><strong>Spotty Daiso Notebook:</strong> For taking note of the myriad of programming/software-design related things that I have no idea about, so that I actually look them up later; also, to keep track of tasks for school research projects</li><li><strong><a href="opalitewires.blogspot.com">Opalite Wires</a>:</strong> For practicing writing something completely uncalled for every single day</li><li><strong>Normal Blog:</strong> Also for practicing writing something completely uncalled for every single day, but also for purposes of coming back months later to ooze nostalgically over whatever I wrote the previous year and see whether I'm still friends with the people that I talked about</li></ul>This makes for tons of ideas that are all over the place, and ANYWAY, the point is that, the objective of <em>this</em> blog is: to try and consolidate, into a relatively intelligible way, all the things that I do in all the other threads.<br /><br />IT WILL MAKE SENSE WHEN THERE'S MORE THINGS.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
