<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Limn | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/limn/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-10T08:28:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[#amwriting Playlist]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/02/amwriting-playlist/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/02/amwriting-playlist</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've started another story. &nbsp;I'm confident about this one. &nbsp;I didn't finish last year's <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2011/11/2011-nanowrimo-limning.html">NaNo</a>&nbsp;but I'm&nbsp;placing my palms on it, shoving and shoving until its sputum can be resurrected as a passable plot.<br /><br />Mmm.<br /><br />I've discovered (not unexpectedly) that writing on the computer is, for me, a lost cause. <br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-MyzI0jY_Bzk/TytZ60DNvkI/AAAAAAAAAos/Ch2z_vwGufc/s1600/472d84164e1a11e1a87612313804ec91_7.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-MyzI0jY_Bzk/TytZ60DNvkI/AAAAAAAAAos/Ch2z_vwGufc/s320/472d84164e1a11e1a87612313804ec91_7.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">i'm going to run out of moleskine soon</td></tr></tbody></table><br />There are too many distractions. &nbsp;I've been weaned too well to the Information Age. &nbsp;A newly-transferred Twitter packet is the sweetest nectar. &nbsp;The "(1)" notification that appears to the left of the title of my Facebook tab sends my endorphins flying (though 90% of the time it's just a request from CastleVille).<br /><br />I've also started assembling a playlist of songs Pandora has suggested to me, which I've found surprisingly stirring of the misery-hope emotions that fuel my inspiration so well. &nbsp;You can find it <a href="http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLD2A04B5DCB06A2D9">here</a>.<br /><br /><br /><br /><center><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLD2A04B5DCB06A2D9&amp;hl=en_US" width="560"></iframe></center><br /><br />Last but not least, an excerpt which I hope won't jinx my endeavors:<br /><br /><blockquote>"It will feel better once you open your eyes," Candle suggested, sounding shameful now, "sorry I can't keep it smooth," but though Win indeed felt sick, she couldn't bring herself to do it -- to open her eyes, to look down and realize that she was miles away from home.  If she fell, how long would it take for her to return?  To fall past Quartzal and Agatava and all of Tenor Anthem, the journey that had taken days in elevators, in short trains weaving on zippered tracks past caves of stationary monsters, in carriages fixed to the back of cliffdragons whose gangly shoulderblades made the entire carriage sway as they navigated aggressive granite striae.  The journey of days could be undone in hours of freefall.  Minutes, if she didn't hit anything.</blockquote></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2011 NaNoWriMo: The Limning]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/11/09/2011-nanowrimo-limning/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/11/09/2011-nanowrimo-limning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I haven't done <a href="http://www.nanowrimo.org/">NaNoWriMo</a> before because it's an event that seems to me to stress quantity over quality, and if there's something that I know I've been doing since I was in junior high, it's writing a lot.  I have hundreds of pages of 8.5pt Verdana Word Documents, for a story that I would still consider myself in the process of writing, though it's undergone pretty drastic changes since back then (most of them for the good).  My old .doc files that contain culled stuff (just in case) is longer than the actual story itself.  I mean, I started writing a <em>sequel</em> to this story before it was even finished.  (O you eighth grade self!)<br /><br />So, I don't usually feel accomplished if I reach a certain count of words.<br /><br />That being said, I don't usually feel accomplished either if I don't write anything at all, so in between work, school, and bouts of Magic I've been chipping away at my own NaNo.  I've fallen a bit behind but am certain I can catch up over Thanksgiving break.<br /><br />...but only if I can't get a copy of Skyward Sword. o___o<br /><br />The story itself is set in Anthem, the of my semi-inactive <a href="http://opalitewires.blogspot.com/">Opalite Wires</a> writing practice blog thing.<br /><br />Here are the first two paragraphs:<br /><br /><blockquote>In Quartzal, the gravity was a little lighter than usual.  This is why it was the main Lower Anthem district for the passerine, who find their flight more easily won in the skies there; a few powerful rows and you’re off, unlike in lower districts where some passerine struggle or else don’t visit at all.  A favorite tagline for passerine tourist was that in Quartzal, one’s wings often open by themselves, which indeed seems to be the case, especially in narrow restaurants where this sort of abrupt twitch can be taken very poorly.  The most popular restaurant in Quartzal served soup comprising a variety of things harvested from the explored regions of Anthem (fungus from Slatemet, cuttles from Obsidash, lightning from Tonsor) in tiny pots balanced on the backs of salamanders, who especially didn’t take kindly to abrupt movements.  Singed tongues, brows, and too much ruined furniture led the proprietors of that particular store to adopt a bound-wing policy, in which winged guests such as the passerine would be required to don a semi-attractive set of belts that had been repurposed to hold wings shut in the unfortunate but inevitable event that Quartzal’s mysterious lightness would force them open.<br /><br />It was one of the few places where rain was welcomed; for with the biannual season of downpours came a great amount of mud, which transformed choking crystalline dust into fine pearly mud that passersby were loathe to scrub from their vehicles, whether they were carriages or cycles or the long, equinal dragons that were the present fashionable mount of Quartzal’s earth-bound bipedal beings.  Rain that fell from beyond the perimeters of the district Quartzal was the only kind of liquid which would render the dirt of Quartzal in this way; water that had been stored in cisterns for the dry season would fail to bring about the same effect, as would water hauled from the lower oceans, as far below as Coralanem, where indeed someone had tried to harvest the water that loved its depth so much it would struggle against the vases of abductors with churning and hisses.  It had to be rain - rain fallen fresh and cool from the skies, water that had rested in the clouds for so long that it had forgotten everything but dozing in the breeze, sometimes calm, sometimes with fits.</blockquote></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>nadine a.</div>
<div class='content'>
Yeah!  I actually really wanted to make &quot;Her Will&quot; into a Flash platformer (http://neauro.com/content/writing/herwill/writing.pdf) but couldn&#39;t quite think of a good mechanic to build around.  You should let me know if you come up with any ideas!  I&#39;d be up for doing fun storygame stuff outside of normal work.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
Yay! :) Ever think about making one of your stories into a Flash platformer game? I&#39;d be up for a collab... :)</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
