<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Lifemisc | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/lifemisc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-25T10:01:26-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello 2013!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/01/06/hello-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/01/06/hello-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Last year was pretty great, in terms of learning more about what sort of things I'm capable of, and navigating the bewildering world of (un)employment and health insurance. In 2012, I finally started earning a salary, health insurance, and a 401k at my "dream job," and two months later was laid off —freed, so to speak, from my decade-long devotion to being a game designer. To be honest, the fact that I will never spend my life thinking <em>What if I had just pursued my dream</em> is an odd gift that I never would have expected to receive and am very thankful for.<br /><br />(Which isn't to say that I've given up on making games! Though, with all the other stuff that I want to do and learn about recently, I also can't say that I'm completely devoted to it anymore either.)<br /><br />Recently I've been trying to focus on making the most of every day, rather than thinking about how I can influence things way in the future, and for that reason I wasn't too inspired to make a particular resolution for this year. However, I would like to try and get one draft of a looong story done this year, and now that I've settled into more a more permanent residence and have gotten into the swing of full-time employment and graduate school, I think that such a goal is more within reach :)<br /><br />My other obvious goal is to have a dog, but between the aforementioned work and school I think that will end up being a resolution for a later year!<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-BroUUBWsEMQ/UOnuq0fFp-I/AAAAAAAAC_g/V25GuYgJeLM/s1600/5994955277_d230103497.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-BroUUBWsEMQ/UOnuq0fFp-I/AAAAAAAAC_g/V25GuYgJeLM/s1600/5994955277_d230103497.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">soon, my sweet</td></tr></tbody></table></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
