<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Lifemisc | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/lifemisc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-27T09:05:28-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Football: Great for the Audience]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/13/football/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-13T19:17:44-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/13/football</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past weekend I finally learned about football, something I&rsquo;ve never been terribly interested in. The most recent game I watched was Kind Of A Big Deal for the city I live in.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/sea2.jpg" alt="Rain and cars and a distant Seattle Space Needle."/></p>

<p class="caption">distant space needle.</a></p>


<p>It strikes me that football is an incredibly fun game to watch because the &ldquo;four downs&rdquo; system provides a multitude of little goals to rejoice about. Each play is rife with struggle, with a victory that can turn into loss in an instant. It reminds me of Mark Rosewater&rsquo;s description of <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/magazine/article.aspx?x=mtg/daily/mm/174">interaction and a catch-up feature</a> as things that &ldquo;every game needs.&rdquo; At each &ldquo;down,&rdquo; both teams have the potential not just to stop each other, but to improve their own standing. It&rsquo;s a powerful interval.</p>

<p>Watching the game this past weekend was the first time in my life that I really, finally <em>got</em> it. I didn&rsquo;t know there were separate offensive and defensive teams; I didn&rsquo;t know that there were people whose singular jobs were to run, or to kick, and that the had individual tutors. It&rsquo;s pretty inspiring.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/sea1.jpg" alt="Seattle Space Needle with a flag that reads '12' on top "/></p>

<p class="caption">#gohawks! and, fun fact: "the 12th man" is a copyrighted phrase. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/12th_man_(football)#Texas_A.26M_trademark_issues_and_Seattle_Seahawks_lawsuit">a phrase <em>not</em> copyrighted by us.</a></p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013 Is Off to a Busy Busy Busy Busy Start.]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/26/2013-is-off-to-busy-busy-busy-busy-start/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/26/2013-is-off-to-busy-busy-busy-busy-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've recently started using <a href="http://www.trello.com">Trello</a> to keep track of my myriad projects, and I love it because I can use it as an always-accessible repository of lists for ideas regarding games, writing, websites, homework, and so on. It's also great for keeping track of resources like free icon sets. I've also been using it to manage and focus on what things are actually currently on my plate, and making sure I don't overextend myself.<br /><br />My prime reading time has always been during my commutes, but I have been reading less because I've discovered <a href="">IA Writer</a>, a writing app which features a simple UI, a re-arranged keyboard, and integration with iCloud (which took me forever how to use; but it's way more convenient than e-mailing myself everything). I absolutely adore it and have been using it for writing practice, which has in general alleviated my plaguing anxieties about not writing enough. I tried writing on the bus with my sketchbook but the bus's movement made my scribbles illegible; typing on my iPod makes things easier, and even a little fun.<br /><br />I have also been hard at work on my part of this year's group cosplay, Black Rock Shooter. I was initially going to go for Demon Cannon User, but then a friend dropped out due to busy-ness, and now I'm rocking Strength, for which I am actually attempting to build up strength to carry around the huge cardboard hands that Andou is helping me make.<br /><br />Winter quarter is also in full swing. This quarter I'm taking my first "practical" class, usability testing, and it's funny — I always thought that I would find practical classes more immediately applicable — but instead I'm finding myself missing theory courses, where you could learn a theory and apply it <em>immediately</em>, instead of waiting to gather participants and test. I'm working with a group to improve and analyze the usability of <a href="http://www.mappingvoices.org">Mapping Voices</a>, which I was interested in for the potential application of game design — for example, how can you encourage people to take action against health inequity? How can you make people feel productive taking action?<br /><br />Though it looks like our suggestions will have to hold up against a bureaucracy and generally complicated organization, I'm looking forward to contributing to a local organization!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello 2013!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/01/06/hello-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/01/06/hello-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Last year was pretty great, in terms of learning more about what sort of things I'm capable of, and navigating the bewildering world of (un)employment and health insurance. In 2012, I finally started earning a salary, health insurance, and a 401k at my "dream job," and two months later was laid off —freed, so to speak, from my decade-long devotion to being a game designer. To be honest, the fact that I will never spend my life thinking <em>What if I had just pursued my dream</em> is an odd gift that I never would have expected to receive and am very thankful for.<br /><br />(Which isn't to say that I've given up on making games! Though, with all the other stuff that I want to do and learn about recently, I also can't say that I'm completely devoted to it anymore either.)<br /><br />Recently I've been trying to focus on making the most of every day, rather than thinking about how I can influence things way in the future, and for that reason I wasn't too inspired to make a particular resolution for this year. However, I would like to try and get one draft of a looong story done this year, and now that I've settled into more a more permanent residence and have gotten into the swing of full-time employment and graduate school, I think that such a goal is more within reach :)<br /><br />My other obvious goal is to have a dog, but between the aforementioned work and school I think that will end up being a resolution for a later year!<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-BroUUBWsEMQ/UOnuq0fFp-I/AAAAAAAAC_g/V25GuYgJeLM/s1600/5994955277_d230103497.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-BroUUBWsEMQ/UOnuq0fFp-I/AAAAAAAAC_g/V25GuYgJeLM/s1600/5994955277_d230103497.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">soon, my sweet</td></tr></tbody></table></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
