<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Wip | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/wip/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T19:51:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Reinventing Education to Be Compelling (With Bonus High School Memories!)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/03/21/on-reinventing-education-to-be/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/03/21/on-reinventing-education-to-be</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<center><!--copy and paste--><object width="446" height="326"><param name="movie" value="http://video.ted.com/assets/player/swf/EmbedPlayer.swf"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always"/><param name="wmode" value="transparent"></param><param name="bgColor" value="#ffffff"></param><param name="flashvars" value="vu=http://video.ted.com/talks/dynamic/SalmanKhan_2011-medium.flv&su=http://images.ted.com/images/ted/tedindex/embed-posters/SalmanKhan-2011.embed_thumbnail.jpg&vw=432&vh=240&ap=0&ti=1090&introDuration=15330&adDuration=4000&postAdDuration=830&adKeys=talk=salman_khan_let_s_use_video_to_reinvent_education;year=2011;theme=new_on_ted_com;theme=a_taste_of_ted2011;event=TED2011;&preAdTag=tconf.ted/embed;tile=1;sz=512x288;" /><embed src="http://video.ted.com/assets/player/swf/EmbedPlayer.swf" pluginspace="http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" wmode="transparent" bgColor="#ffffff" width="446" height="326" allowFullScreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" flashvars="vu=http://video.ted.com/talks/dynamic/SalmanKhan_2011-medium.flv&su=http://images.ted.com/images/ted/tedindex/embed-posters/SalmanKhan-2011.embed_thumbnail.jpg&vw=432&vh=240&ap=0&ti=1090&introDuration=15330&adDuration=4000&postAdDuration=830&adKeys=talk=salman_khan_let_s_use_video_to_reinvent_education;year=2011;theme=new_on_ted_com;theme=a_taste_of_ted2011;event=TED2011;"></embed></object></center><br /><br />This TED Talk was passed out to all the games grad students at UW and now that it's spring break I actually have time to look at it.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.khanacademy.org/">Khan Academy</a> is at first glance just a website that contains a lot of educational videos, so at first it seems pretty typical -- of course you can use videos to be educational -- Bill Nye, right?  And I mean, TED talks, amirite?<br /><br />But as the lecture progressed, it started talking more concerning giving feedback based on students' education and such, all very game-y things which made it more obvious why it was being circulated through that mailing list.<br /><br /><blockquote>But then I started getting letters from teachers. And the teachers would write, saying, "We use your videos to flip the classroom...what I do is I assign the lectures for homework. And what used to be homework, I now have the students doing in the classroom."<br /><br />...when those teachers are doing that, there's the obvious benefit -- the benefit that now their students can enjoy the videos in the way that my cousins did. They can pause, repeat at their own pace, at their own time. But the more interesting thing is -- and this is the unintuitive thing when you talk about technology in the classroom -- by removing the one size fits all lecture from the classroom and letting students have a self-paced lecture at home, and then when you go to the classroom, letting them do work, having the teacher walk around, having the peers actually be able to interact with each other, <strong>these teachers have used technology to humanize the classroom. They took a fundamentally dehumanizing experience -- 30 kids with their fingers on their lips, not allowed to interact with each other. A teacher, no matter how good, has to give this one size fits all lecture to 30 students -- blank faces, slightly antagonistic -- and now it's a human experience. Now they're actually interacting with each other.</strong></blockquote><br />That technology is the humanizing thing, rather than classrooms, definitely is not intuitive at all -- and when I hear something like assigning students videos for homework, the first thing I think is, <em>Are they really going to do this?</em> Are high school and younger students really going to subject themselves to mental stimulation outside of school itself?<br /><br />I guess the main belief is that people really do want to improve themselves, and will do so, given the opportunity; this is a big part of <em><a href="http://realityisbroken.org/">Reality is Broken</a></em> by Jane McGonigal, which I'm presently reading (and almost done with!).  She writes that one of the things that's essential to human happiness is "the experience, or at least the hope, of being successful.  We want to feel powerful in our own lives and show off to others what we're good at.  We want to be optimistic about our own chances for success, to aspire to something, and to feel like we're getting better over time."<br /><br />Which brings me back to my high school, which always bothered me.  We were reknowned for having tons of AP courses and turning out students that did really well in them; I took AP Computer Science A and AB there (back when AB was still offered) and our teacher told us that the girls in our class were the stark majority of all the girls that took the AP Compsci test.  By graduation, I'd taken around 12 AP courses, with grades of 3 or above in all the tests. <span class="shh">Damn you, Chemistry!  And Physics B!  Arrrghhh</span><br /><br />One thing that was unique about our school was that if you wanted to take an AP course, you could; there was no minimum GPA requirement, no test that you had to pass.  For some national government bill simulation, our class tried to pass a bill that would allow this sort of "If you want to take a harder course, do it" behavior in every high school, but it was voted down by some east coast school that said, essentially, "If you just allow anyone to take an AP course, then you will ruin the class for everyone else.  The teacher will have to cater to these dumb people, the discussions will have to be held on a lower level, we deny it."<br /><br />Which made us all really angry, I guess, and talking about it with my friends later, we pretty much agreed: If you're failing behind in class, it's not the teacher's fault, sorry bro, you've just got to keep up.<br /><br />So if you wanted to take AP Everything in our school, you could -- and I kind of imagine this as also being parallel to having that opportunity to be better, to learn more.  Our AP courses, however, had a reputation for being pretty difficult, which, though it may be true, also contributed to what I think was an unfair gap in our school.  On one side were the AP students; on the other side, your stereotypical high school students who traded drugs during lunch and graduated to work at the mall a couple miles from the school.<br /><br />This itself is an unfair description, but also what happens, not just in one high school, when education is offered and only a subset take advantage of it.  If education is all about success and being better, why do some students not pursue it, despite its realtion to basic human happiness?  What is it about our present education system that is anti-compelling?<br /><br />And we AP kids, who I speak of so highly, what did we really learn -- did we come out of high school with grades that prove usable knowledge, or are our A's just badges of facts that we've memorized and will forget the next year?<br /><br /><blockquote>In a traditional classroom, you have a couple of homework, homework, lecture, homework, lecture, and then you have a snapshot exam. And that exam, whether you get a 70 percent, an 80 percent, a 90 percent, or a 95 percent, the class moves on to the next topic. And even that 95 percent student, what was the five percent they didn't know? Maybe they didn't know what happens when you raise something to the zero power. And then you go build on that in the next concept. <strong>That's analogous to imagine learning to ride a bicycle, and maybe I give you a lecture ahead of time, and I give you that bicycle for two weeks. And then I come back after two weeks, and I say, "Well, let's see. You're having trouble taking left turns. You can't quite stop. You're an 80 percent bicyclist." So I put a big C stamp on your forehead and then I say, "Here's a unicycle."</strong><br /><br />But as ridiculous as that sounds, that's exactly what's happening in our classrooms right now. And the idea is you fast forward and good students start failing algebra all of a sudden and start failing calculus all of a sudden, despite being smart, despite having good teachers. And it's usually because they have these Swiss cheese gaps that kept building throughout their foundation. So our model is learn math the way you'd learn anything, like the way you would learn a bicycle. Stay on that bicycle. Fall off that bicycle. Do it as long as necessary until you have mastery. The traditional model, it penalizes you for experimentation and failure, but it does not expect mastery. <strong>We encourage you to experiment. We encourage you to failure. But we do expect mastery.</strong></blockquote><br />"Encouraging failure" or at least allowing it, accepting it, and using it, rather than punishing it, is also a very <em>game</em> thing.  I'm reminded of when Andreas told me a story about a teacher of his who was a little eccentric, an intelligent world traveler (or something of the sort) who abruptly settled down to become a teacher and allowed his students to take tests over and over again until they learned the material.  If you have an opportunity to do better, to <em>be</em> visibly better, I don't know who would leave it.<br /><br /><span class="shh">I mean, I guess if I had the opportunity to be visibly better at baseball or something it probably wouldn't matter to me.  But that's because I already have other things that I'd rather be improving.</span><br /><br />Something else that I really like about this anti-traditional model is the idea of <em>experimenting</em>, which I feel was really lacking in my education up until a very recent point (as in, a couple of months ago, when I realized <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2011/02/game-bonding-time.html">I could make games</a> if I wanted).  A lot of grade school is all about just learning basics -- which is good, but I wish that it wasn't in college that you started questioning <em>why</em> something happens, and start to expand on ideas, and be imaginative.<br /><br />At 11:48 of this video, there's a presentation of a "dashboard" which basically shows a detailed breakdown of how each student is doing.<br /><br /><blockquote>Green means the student's already proficient. Blue means they're working on it -- no need to worry. Red means they're stuck. And what the teacher does is literally just say, "Let me intervene on the red kids." Or even better, "Let me get one of the green kids who are already proficient in that concept to be the first line of attack and actually tutor their peer."</blockquote><br />This whole part reminds me of <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=new+york+game+school">the game school</a> in New York, which, despite being incredibly awesome and employing game techniques to improve students' will to learn, seems incredibly specific.  Though both this dashboard and the game school use visible acquisition of mastery to motivate students, I could see the dashboard being more easily used by schools like my old high school.  Something like this is not just helpful to motivate students, but to allow them to see where they need help -- no small feat, really, because I've always thought that the biggest obstacle to learning something is knowing the right question to ask.<br /><br />I wonder if any teachers actually take talks like this seriously.  Whenever I think of grade school education, it seems incredibly set in its ways.  If it changed, what would happen to all the iconic high school drama and archetypes?  YOU CAN'T HAVE A "THE SMART KID" IF EVERYONE IS SMART, OKAY.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
