<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T10:18:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Champion, Marie Lu]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/17/champion/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-17T16:06:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/17/champion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/champion.jpg" alt="Cover of Champion, which features a black and red rose"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/14290364-champion">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>June and Day have sacrificed so much for the people of the Republic—and each other—and now their country is on the brink of a new existence. June is back in the good graces of the Republic, working within the government’s elite circles as Princeps-Elect, while Day has been assigned a high-level military position. <br/><br/> 
But neither could have predicted the circumstances that will reunite them: just when a peace treaty is imminent, a plague outbreak causes panic in the Colonies, and war threatens the Republic’s border cities. This new strain of plague is deadlier than ever, and June is the only one who knows the key to her country’s defense. But saving the lives of thousands will mean asking the one she loves to give up everything. <br/><br/>
With heart-pounding action and suspense, Marie Lu’s bestselling trilogy draws to a stunning conclusion. (<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/14290364-champion">Goodreads</a>)</blockquote>


<p>(I&rsquo;ve also written about the previous books in the <em>Legend</em> trilogy, <a href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/10/06/legend-marie-lu/"><em>Legend</em></a> and <a href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/05/21/prodigy-marie-lu/"><em>Prodigy</em></a>.)</p>

<p>I finally finished Champion on the bus to work and felt all shaky and full of feels. After having been disappointed by the endings of other YA trilogies I&rsquo;ve finished recently, I was nervous about this one; and though there were some strange parts, ultimately this whole story delivered exactly what I wanted, which was: the bittersweet, bright-future fulfillment of a &ldquo;we are enemies from two different worlds&rdquo; power couple romance.</p>

<p>[ spoilers ahead ]</p>

<p>There were a few strange parts. Thomas&#8217; spoken blow-by-blow, feeling-by-feeling recollection of the night he killed Metias felt kind of awkawrd to me; and there was also more &ldquo;hand-holding&rdquo; than I would have liked. As the story goes on Day begins to lose his memory, and when trying to recollect the name of his caretaker, thinks to himself &ldquo;<em>That&rsquo;s weird</em>&rdquo;&hellip;but as readers, we <em>know</em> that it&rsquo;s strange for Day to forget the name of his long-known caretaker. That the book takes time to point it out takes away part of the fun of realizing it for ourselves.</p>

<p>The society of Antarctica, based entirely on a game-like system of points and ranking, is also thrown in as a curiosity of world-building and not examined in relation to existing structures at all. Given that the Republic of America (with its &ldquo;democratic dictatorship&rdquo; feel) and the Colonies of the America (with its &ldquo;capitalistic tyranny&rdquo; feel) are both recognized as having flaws, I thought that Antarctica might also have criticisms; but Antarctica remains unquestioned and accepted as a powerful government whose allyship is desired. There&rsquo;s nothing terribly &ldquo;wrong&rdquo; with this treatment, but I&rsquo;d really like something more — for this strange piece of world-building to fit into an overall theme, for it to contrast with what June and Day see as admirable about their own country. Maybe something like, &ldquo;Sure, in Antarctica people do good so they can get points, but where <em>we</em> live people do good just because they can and want to!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Anyway, it was an enjoyable trilogy and I&rsquo;m looking forward to more from Marie Lu in the future!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Milennium Actress (千年女優)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/13/millenium-actress/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-13T14:58:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/13/millenium-actress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/millenium.jpg" alt="Millenium Actress poster"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millennium_Actress/">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>A movie studio is being torn down. TV interviewer Genya Tachibana has tracked down its most famous star, Chiyoko Fujiwara, who has been a recluse since she left acting some 30 years ago. Tachibana delivers a key to her, and it causes her to reflect on her career; as she&#8217;s telling the story, Tachibana and Kyoji Ida, his long-suffering cameraman are drawn in. The key was given to her as a teenager by a painter and revolutionary that she helped to escape the police. She becomes an actress because it will make it possible to track him down, and she spends the next several decades acting out that search in various genres and eras. (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millennium_Actress">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>I watched <em>Millenium Actress</em> with A partly on a whim and partly because she started salivating the instant that she came across images of it online and remembered its existence. Reading about it on Wikipedia now, it looks like it&rsquo;s by Satoshi Kon, which would make it the first film of his that I&rsquo;ve seen. It&rsquo;s a beautiful film with all the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ichi-go_ichi-e">ichi go ichi e</a>&rdquo; atmospheres that I&rsquo;ve come to notice and love in Japanese stories since studying chadou one winter.</p>

<p>Why you should watch it:</p>

<ul>
<li>The animation is beautiful.</li>
<li>The story itself is crisp and well-written, super focused, with both moments that are hilarious and heart-clenchingly bittersweet.</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul>
<li>The main point of the story is that &#8220;the actress does everything in her life to reunite with the man she met once and fell in love with&#8221; — which isn&#8217;t totally new and interesting on its own.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seattle Asian American Film Festival: To Manong Carlos, One Generation's Time, and Seeking Asian Female]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/10/saaff/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T09:24:04-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/10/saaff</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the kindness of R, I was able to attend the final day of the <a href="http://seattleaaff.org/2014/">Seattle Asian-American Film Festival</a>, an event whose existence I was only barely aware of before R invited me.</p>

<p>We had tickets to see two full documentaries and one short experimental film.</p>

<h2><em>One Generation’s Time: The Legacy Of Silme Domingo &amp; Gene Viernes</em> | <em>To Manong Carlos</em></h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/onegenerationstime.jpg" alt="Photographs of Silme Domingo and Gene Viernes, two Filipino-American activists"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://seattleaaff.org/2014/shorts-programs/one-generations-time-the-legacy-of-silme-domingo-gene-viernes-to-manong-carlos/">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>One short experimental film followed by documentary feature, <em>One Generation’s Time: The Legacy of Silme Domingo & Gene Viernes</em>.</blockquote>


<p><em>One Generation&rsquo;s Time</em> is about the work that Silme Domingo and Gene Viernes did to bring equal working conditions the Filipinos employed seasonally at Alaska canneries. In the 1970s, white workers had access to better food and better living situations than Filipinos doing the same work. Furthermore, on days with less work, rather than being allowed to rest, Filipinos were instructed to move empty cans from one side of warehouses just so they were paid for &ldquo;doing something.&rdquo; Silme and Gene were both murdered for their work, and the documentary discusses the political motivations of the murders, and how the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ferdinand_Marcos">Marcos dictatorship</a> was involved. The film was directed by Shannon Gee.</p>

<p><em>To Manong Carlos</em> is a short film directed by Adrian Arilla, about his experiences as a Filipino coming to live and call America his home.</p>

<p>Why you should watch these:</p>

<ul><li><em>One Generation&#8217;s Time</em> introduces the complicated situation and political machinations of behind Silme and Gene&#8217;s work well; probably because, as Shannon Gee said in a panel afterward, she herself was entirely new to this story.</li>
<li><em>To Manong Carlos</em> is a beautiful film where Arilla&#8217;s experiences are interspersed with quotes from Carlos Bulosan&#8217;s <em>America is in the Heart</em>. Reading these quotes alongside Arilla&#8217;s modern experiences gives a special poignancy to Bulosan&#8217;s &#8220;old&#8221; writings, which are still incredibly relevant today. In a media atmosphere where the stories of Filipinos are either rarely told or outright suffocated, it&#8217;s moving to remember that we <em>do</em> have stories, that we have a history. We don&#8217;t drift to America as &#8220;minority&#8221; individuals separate and small, but that we follow and build on the work and words that have come before us.</li>
</ul>




<h2><em>Seeking Asian Female</em></h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/seeking_asian_female.jpg" alt="Poster for Seeking Asian Female, depicting a white man and a Chinese woman in wedding attire, and the director of the documentary, a Chinese woman."/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.mrqe.com/movie_reviews/seeking-asian-female-m100102931">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote><em>seeking asian female</em> is an eccentric modern love story about Steven and Sandy—an aging white man with “yellow fever” who is obsessed with marrying any Asian woman, and the young Chinese bride he finds online. Debbie, a Chinese American filmmaker, documents and narrates with skepticism and humor, from the early stages of Steven’s search, through the moment Sandy steps foot in America for the first time, to a year into their precarious union. Global migration, Sino-American relations and the perennial battle of the sexes, weigh in on the fate of their marriage in this intensely captivating personal documentary. (<a href="http://www.seekingasianfemale.com/the-film/">Seeking Asian Female</a>)</blockquote>


<p>I&rsquo;ve been dying to see <em>Seeking Asian Female</em> since coming across <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3kbGrQe17cU">the trailer</a> a year or two ago. Watching it at the Seattle Asian-American Film Festival was particularly gratifying, as the entire theater was groaning and laughing every time a white person swooned about the &ldquo;servant girl&rdquo;-ishness and &ldquo;green papaya fragrance&rdquo; of the Asian women they saw (and smelled?) in their minds.</p>

<p>Why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>It&#8217;s as hilarious as it is cringe-worthy. You cringe and laugh as you cringe.</li>
<li>The story is well told.</li>
<li>The director does a great job telling the story of Sandy, the &#8220;Asian Female&#8221; of this film, and also examines the ethics of herself being in the middle of this relationship.</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;m happy that something like the Seattle Asian-American Film Festival exists, and hope it continues next year. Watching both movies, I was reminded of N&rsquo;s quote at our last AB meeting: &ldquo;If we don&rsquo;t tell our stories, our stories tell us.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recently Consumed Delicious Anime and Manga]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/04/yay-anime/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-04T14:07:09-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/04/yay-anime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been getting <em>really</em> into anime and manga again, which happens occasionally. The last time this happened was with <a href="http://blog.neauro.com/2012-11-14-sword-art-online-so-pretty">Sword Art Online</a>, an anime I loved until the second season, which led the story down into an incestuous love triangle and a hideous, totally unncessary sexual assault scene.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s an overview of some anime/manga I&rsquo;ve found recently.</p>

<h2>Anime: Kuragehime / 海月姫 / Princess Jellyfish</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/animango/kuragehime_anime.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://sleepisfortheweak.org/reviews/micros/princessjellyfish">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>Amamizukan is an apartment complex where no boys are allowed. Tsukimi, a girl who adores jellyfish, lives there happily with her friends who all have nerdy obsessions of their own. Their peaceful lives gradually start to change when a beautiful woman helps Tsukimi out of a pinch. She stays overnight at the apartments—but it turns out &#8220;she&#8221; is really a &#8220;he&#8221;. (<a href="http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/anime.php?id=11282">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Complete. Genre: Jousei/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>H has been heavily encouraging me to watch this series for years and I finally set aside time for it after finding it on Netflix!</p>

<p>Reasons why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>It&#8217;s legitimately hilarious. Even A, who generally despises anime, enjoyed it. <em>This is really saying something.</em></li>
<li>There are varied female characters! With varied appearances and varied interests!</li>
<li>Kuranosuke&#8217;s crossdressing/femme presentation isn&#8217;t used by the main cast as something to belittle him.</li>
<li>Surprisingly, it&#8217;s the only story I&#8217;ve ever consumed where I didn&#8217;t really mind the love triangle and felt like I was rooting for both sides of it.</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul> <li>The ending is pretty sudden.</li>
</ul>




<h2>Manga: Kuragehime / 海月姫 / Princess Jellyfish, HIGASHIMURA Akiko</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/animango/kuragehime_manga.jpg" alt="Picture from Kuragehime manga"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.mangareader.net/kuragehime">via</a>)</p>




<blockquote>Kuragehime follows Tsukimi Kurashita, an 18-year-old who moved from Kagoshima to Tokyo to become an illustrator. Tsukimi is a jellyfish otaku who comes to live in a shared bath and toilet, women-only apartment, Amamizukan. Other tenants include fujoshi, NEETs and others who consider fashion their natural enemy, calling themselves &#8220;Amars&#8221;. One day, Tsukimi meets a fashionable and beautiful girl, Kuranosuke Koibuchi, who saves a jellyfish that is about to die at a pet shop. She later discovers that Kuranosuke is merely cross-dressing in order to evade inheritance of his father&#8217;s occupation as a politician. (<a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=38146">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Ongoing. Genre: Jousei/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>Being dissatisfied with the anime&rsquo;s ending, I chased up the manga.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should read it:</p>

<ul><li>Though the rendering of events isn&#8217;t as funny as in the anime, it&#8217;s still pretty cute.</li>
<li>(spoilers) <span class="spoiler">The manga doesn&#8217;t make it look as if Shuu is falling in love with the woman sexually blackmailing him, which is good.</span></li>
<li>The author also has short manga detailing events in her own life, and they&#8217;re *such funny wow*.</li>
</ul>




<h2>Manga: Dengeki Daisy / 電撃デイジー, MOTOMI Kyousuke</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/animango/dengeki_daisy.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://dengekidaisy.wikia.com/wiki/List_of_Chapters">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>After orphan Teru Kurebayashi loses her beloved older brother, she finds solace in the messages she exchanges with Daisy, an enigmatic figure who can only be reached through the cell phone her brother left her. Meanwhile, Teru meets and forms a strange friendship with mysterious Tasuku Kurosaki, her school&#8217;s janitor. For some reason, Kurosaki always seems to be around whenever Teru needs help which leads Teru to wonder: Could Daisy be a lot closer than she thinks?</br></br>

As the mystery of Daisy unfolds, Teru also discovers that there may have been a lot more to the life and death of her brother than she ever dreamed&#8230;and that the man she thought was her friend just might have all the answers.(<a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=13582">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Ongoing. Genre: Shoujo/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>This was recommended to me by Tumblr friends.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should read it:</p>

<ul><li>It&#8217;s <em>so cute wow</em>. If you need a heavy dose of thick, syrupy shoujo, this is it. <em>This is it.</em></li>
<li>Teru The Protagonist is an awesome female lead, and though there are some &#8220;damsel&#8221; moments, she mostly has impressive/fun moments where she saves herself and the entire day just when the author leads you to expect the opposite. (Wow such subversive!)</li>
<li>Teru also has friendships with other girls, both of whom she confides in and supports throughout the series.</li>
<li>There&#8217;s a girl who could totally be slut-shamed, <em>and she isn&#8217;t</em>.</li>
<li>This series is the first I&#8217;ve seen to depict a relationship growing significantly through communicating with each other digitally, which is pretty tight.</li>
<li>The main male lead is a HACKER! :&#8217;D</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li>It&#8217;s really cheesy. <em>Really cheesy</em>. When you&#8217;re not getting cavities, you&#8217;re drowning in cheese. Though really, depending on your mood, this is kind of a plus.</li></ul>




<h2>Manga: Kamisama Hajimemashia | 神様はじめました / Kamisama Kiss, SUZUKI Julietta</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/animango/kh_manga.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.zerochan.net/1311703">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote> Momozono Nanami’s dad, a man with a penchant for gambling, disappeared after accumulating a huge amount of debt. Thus, she was chased out of her house by the debt collectors. When she met a timid guy being chased by a dog, he told her that he’d give her his house. She believed his persuasive talk, but when she went to his house… it turned out to be a shrine. Moreover, a guy with fox ears appeared, which made Nanami even more confused. What will become of homeless and confused Nanami? (<a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=24388">via</a>) </blockquote>


<p>Status: Ongoing. Genre: Shoujo/Supernatural/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve actually been reading this for a while, but it&rsquo;s worth another shout-out because I&rsquo;ve been re-reading it and it&rsquo;s one of my favorite series to date, right up there with <em>Full Metal Panic!</em>.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should read it:</p>

<ul><li>The supernatural premise is fun, and the majority of the characters have a lot of charm. (The only one I can&#8217;t totally get behind is Mizuki, mostly because he seems the most unnecessary to the plot.)</li>
<li>Nanami The Protagonist gets stuff done! Woo!</li>
<li>Tomoe is a well-developed male lead. He has bangs, a dark past, animal ears, cooking skills — everything you could ever possibly desire on this imperfect earth.</li>
<li>I really love Suzuki-sensei&#8217;s unconventional-looking art style.</li>
<li>*Time paradox!*</li></ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li>Recent chapters (specifically, 92 and 107) have had some uncomfortable dubcon scenes. Ultimately Suzuki-sensei has handled these scenes in an <em>alright</em> way&#8230;but I wish she&#8217;d have her characters call out and condemn the problematic aspects head-on.</li>
<li>The story recently has also been slowing down and felt uncomfortably off-pace, though I&#8217;m not giving up on it just yet.</li></ul>




<h2>Anime: Kamisama Hajimemashita / 神様はじめました / Kamisama Kiss</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/animango/kh_anime.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://mysticalcrimsonsky.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/kamisama-hajimemashita-new-image-revealednew-movie-for-2013/">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>After her father having run away due to gambling debts, and being evicted from her apartment, Nanami meets Mikage, a strange man who is afraid of dogs. Nanami &#8220;saves&#8221; Mikage from a dog and tells him her story. He gives Nanami his house as a thank you for saving him. Nanami accepts the offer, due to having nowhere else to go. Mikage draws her up a map showing her where to go. Upon arriving, she finds that it is a rundown shrine. Nanami is then almost killed by Tomoe, who was expecting Mikage to finally return after his 20 year absence. She is then greeted by both Onikiri and Kotetsu, as the new land god of the shrine. Unable to accept Nanami as the new land god, Tomoe mocks her then leaves the shrine, which, without Tomoe&#8217;s power transforms back into a run-down state. Not wanting to rob Tomoe of his home and realizing that her powers as a god are too weak anyway Nanami leaves, but eventually is brought back by Tomoe after she seals a contract with him, making him her familiar. (<a href="http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/anime.php?id=14441">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>
Status: Complete. Genre: Shoujo/Supernatural/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>Nanami&#8217;s voice actress is perfectly casted. <em>Perfectly.</em></li>
<li>If you enjoyed the manga, you&#8217;d probably also enjoy seeing some of the scenes animated?</li></ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li>Nanami has less agency in the anime, and I don&#8217;t Recent chapters (specifically, 92 and 107) have had some uncomfortable dubcon scenes. Ultimately Suzuki-sensei has handled these scenes in an <em>alright</em> way&#8230;but I wish she&#8217;d have her characters call out and condemn the problematic aspects head-on.</li>
<li>The story recently has also been slowing down and felt uncomfortably off-pace, though I&#8217;m not giving up on it just yet.</li></ul>




<h2>Anime: Free! Iwatobi Swim Club</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/animango/free.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/anime-news/2013/09/25-1/second-season-of-free-anime-teased">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>Four boys named Haruka, Makoto, Nagisa and Rin all participated in a swimming tournament shortly before graduating elementary school and later parted ways. Years later, they reunite when Rin challenges Haruka to a race and wins. Not wanting to be defeated so easily, Haruka gathers Makoto and Nagisa and a new recruit named Rei to form the Iwatobi High School Swimming Club. (<a href="http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/anime.php?id=15291">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Complete. Genre: Comedy/Sports&hellip;?</p>

<p>How could I not watch this? After all, it&rsquo;s <a href="http://knowyourmeme.com/memes/events/swimming-anime"><em>the series that Tumblr made</em></a>.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>The animation is pretty. I even read on Tumblr that the actual swimming movements were pretty accurate. <em>Neat</em>.</li></ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li>The story is just alright.</li>
<li>Queer-baiting (used extensively here) is boring.</li></ul>




<h2>Anime: Kyoukai no Kanata / 境界の彼方 / Beyond the Boundary</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/animango/knk.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.zerochan.net/1570806">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>Akihito Kanbara is a high school sophomore in the literature club who believes himself to be a &#8220;Meganest&#8221;, and although he appears to be human, he is actually half Yōmu, which makes him invulnerable to wounds, due to the fact that he can heal so quickly, and also immortal. One day, Akihito meets freshman Mirai Kuriyama when it appears as if she is about to attempt suicide by jumping off of the school rooftop. Mirai is isolated because of her ability to manipulate blood, which is considered heresy even among other members of the underworld, so she is shunned. Soon after Akihito saves Mirai, disturbing events begin to arise. (<a href="http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/anime.php?id=15546">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Complete. Genre: Action/Romance/Comedy/Fantasy.</p>

<p>I was lured into watching this anime because of the gorgeous animation and my instant affinity for the main character, who has red glasses not totally unlike my own. Also, &ldquo;meganest&rdquo; in the description above stands for the fact that Akihito is really into women who wear glasses.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>Like <em>Free!</em>, also by Kyoto Animation, the animation (especially with the fight scenes) is gorgeous.</li>
<li>If, like me, you are a sucker for the forbidden romance between a &#8220;demon-type person&#8221; and &#8220;demon-slayer-type person&#8221; — well, here it is.</li>
<li>I love the ending song, which is Stereo Dive Foundation&#8217;s <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NaHx6oENn9s">Daisy</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li><a href="http://seventhstyle.com/2013/08/10/kyoukai-no-kanata-goes-moeblob-in-anime-pv/">The moeblob is strong with this one.</a></li>
<li>The ending was rushed and I&#8230;still don&#8217;t really get what happened.</li>
<li>The two main male characters are overly obsesssed with their fetishes. It&#8217;s annoying at least and disturbing at worst, especially since the girl characters they&#8217;re focusing their fetishes on are clearly uncomfortable.</li>
<li>To be honest, this series as a whole fell flat for me, but the eyecandy was quite filling.</li></ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developing for Opera Mini]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/21/opera-mini/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-21T10:38:15-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/21/opera-mini</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It came to my attention recently that not only are the majority of the users for one of my projects using Opera Mini, but that Opera Mini has a Very Special way of dealing with Javascript.</p>

<p>From <a href="http://dev.opera.com/articles/view/opera-mini-web-content-authoring-guidelines/#javascript">their authoring guidelines</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
while Mini supports JavaScript just as well as Opera Desktop, interactivity is somewhat more limited. When the user clicks a link or a button, then the Mini client sends that information back to the server, where the server performs the associated action (such as loading a new page, executing some JavaScript, etc.).
<br/><br/>
For authors, the upshot of all this is that once a page has been rendered by the server, it won&#8217;t change until the user does something on that and there is no way for scripts to run in the background. The user must do something to make Mini talk to the server in order for JavaScript to be unpaused. As a result, you cannot expect things like JavaScript animations or timed Ajax updates to work in the background as they would on a desktop browser.
<br/><br/>
JavaScript running on the Mini server will only run for a couple of seconds before pausing, for resource constraint reasons. This applies to JavaScript run due to an event firing e.g. onload, as well as code run because of a user action.</blockquote>


<p>I&rsquo;m still working on getting it properly working, which seems impossible given the bulk of Javascript used in this case and its heavy reliance on Ajax.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Praise of #vscocam]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/16/vsco/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-16T09:16:32-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/16/vsco</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After about seven years with the same litle phone, I finally decided to upgrade. If I&rsquo;m being honest, I did it because the iPhone 5S/5C camera seemed like such an improvement over the previous, and I really wanted to have access to a camera usable in ordinary situations. (My old Motorola was also starting to have problems — bad audio, bad button sensitivity.)</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/vsco0.jpg" alt="My old phone."/></p>

<p class="caption">goodbye dear friend</p>


<p>The pictures that my phone takes are great — better than the pictures my old work iPod had, and definitely better than no pictures taken at all. But, what makes my silly phone photos really fun and gorgeous is the <a href="http://vsco.co/vscocam">VSCO Cam app</a>.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/vsco1.jpg" alt="the foggy ferry dock on thanksgiving"/></p>

<p class="caption">the foggy ferry dock on thanksgiving</p>


<p>You can take pictures from the app or import them, and then control expore, temperature, white balance, saturation&hellip;I have to admit, though, that it took me forever to realize that bottom bar that showed all these editing options is actually something you can scroll from left to right.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/vscobar.png" alt="a photo of a girl"/></p>

<p class="caption">these colors were seriously bland and boring before i edited it.<br/>and,there&#8217;s that bar. it doesn&#8217;t look scrollable at all.</p>


<p>There are also a variety of filters which, to me, are way more subtle and attractive than Instagram&rsquo;s filters. I admit that I use the F2 filter way more than the others.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/vsco2.jpg" alt="foggy seattle"/></p>

<p class="caption">foggy cityline</p>


<p>Feel free to check out <a href="http://instagram.com/neauro">my Instagram</a> for more photos.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/vsco3.jpg" alt="the cranes at seattle pier"/></p>

<p class="caption">the dinosaur-like cranes at the pier</p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Website: Fong Baatz Portfolio]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/15/fongbaatz/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-15T10:32:12-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/15/fongbaatz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/fongbaatz.png" alt="Screenshot of Fong Baatz portfolio"/></p>

<p class="caption">screenshot of <A href="http://fongbaatz.com">fong baatz portfolio</a></p>


<p>For some weeks now I&rsquo;ve been working on the portfolio site of a local artist (who is also A&rsquo;s mother). It&rsquo;s been fun. The website can be accessed <a href="http://fongbaatz.com">here</a>. Parts of the process are documented on <a href="http://neauro.tumblr.com/tagged/fongportfolio">my Tumblr</a>.</p>

<p>This weekend she and other artists are having an open house at Magnuson Building 30, which was repurposed by the city of Seattle for their work. The open house is on January 19th, from 2:00 to 5:00 pm. Check it out!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books: His Fair Assassin, Robin LaFevers]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/15/his-fair-series/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-15T09:57:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/15/his-fair-series</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/dark_triumph_cover.jpg" alt="Cover of Dark Triumph"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9943270-dark-triumph">via</a>)</p>




<blockquote>Seventeen-year-old Ismae escapes from the brutality of an arranged marriage into the sanctuary of the convent of St. Mortain, where the sisters still serve the gods of old. Here she learns that the god of Death Himself has blessed her with dangerous gifts—and a violent destiny. If she chooses to stay at the convent, she will be trained as an assassin and serve as a handmaiden to Death. To claim her new life, she must destroy the lives of others.
<br/><br/>

Ismae’s most important assignment takes her straight into the high court of Brittany—where she finds herself woefully under prepared—not only for the deadly games of intrigue and treason, but for the impossible choices she must make. For how can she deliver Death’s vengeance upon a target who, against her will, has stolen her heart?
<Br/><br/>

— Grave Mercy</blockquote>




<blockquote>
When Sybella arrived at the doorstep of St Mortain half mad with grief and despair the convent were only too happy to offer her refuge - but at a price. The sisters of this convent serve Death, and with Sybella naturally skilled in both the arts of death and seduction, she could become one of their most dangerous weapons.
<br/><br/>
But her assassin&#8217;s skills are little comfort when the convent returns her to the life that nearly drove her mad. Her father&#8217;s rage and brutality are terrifying, and her brother&#8217;s love is equally monstrous. But when Sybella discovers an unexpected ally she discovers that a daughter of Death may find something other than vengeance to live for&#8230;
<Br/><br/> 
— Dark Triumph</blockquote>


<p>A coworker lent me <em>Grave Mercy</em> and <em>Dark Triumph</em>, the books currently released in the <em>His Fair Assassin</em> trilogy, and I devoured them both in less than a week. They were delicious.</p>

<p>The books are set in Brittany, at a time when it is fighting for its independence against the French. There&rsquo;s a lot of political intrigue, and, as Goodreads is fond of saying, &ldquo;magical assassin nuns,&rdquo; who are the main characters of the books. Overall, they&rsquo;re fun characters to read about, poisons and daggers and conflicts and struggles all. They navigate politics, relationships, and their own identities and duties.</p>

<p>(TW) As a warning, these books contain a lot of sexual assault, especially the second book, whose protagonist, Sybella, is a survivor. Whereas sexual assault in stories is something I often eyeroll at due to its prevalent use as a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=toa_vH6xGqs">grimdark fridging mechanism</a>, the use of sexual assault in <em>His Fair Assassin</em> wasn&rsquo;t trivialized, dramaticized, or used to further the motivations of another character. Sexual assault is a horrible act, and when victim-blaming occurs it is struck down as wrong. Both books explore women making choices about their sexuality, with consenting, supportive partners.</p>

<p>(It seems weird to even write the above paragraph. Like, shouldn&rsquo;t this just be <em>the way it is</em>? It seems strange to praise a book so highly for meeting what should be common guidlines for decency. Anyway. <em>His Fair Assassin</em> nails it.)</p>

<p>Something that I felt these books were lacking were that they took for granted my knowledge of European history. For example, why is Brittany rebelling against France? I wonder if Brittany&rsquo;s rebellion is just something that Everyone is aware of already; even so, it would have been nice to have in-book examples of why a French takeover would be so bad. It would&rsquo;ve also been nice to see more reasons why everyone was so willing to devote their lives to a twelve-year-old duchess. That everyone was unerringly adoring of her and willing to die for her sake was strange to me, and descriptions of her being &ldquo;wiser than her years&rdquo; didn&rsquo;t quite stand up on its own as a reason to rally behind her, especially when the world is so patriarchal.</p>

<p>This series was one of the rare cases where I loved the second book more than the first. The protagonist of the third book, Annith, has been introduced thus far as a predictably innocent character, but I&rsquo;m looking forward to where LaFevers will take her.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kickstarter and Completion]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/15/kickstarter/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-15T09:03:10-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/15/kickstarter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/kickstarter1.png" alt="A screenshot of my Kickstarter profile"/></p>

<p class="caption">a screenshot of <A href="http://www.kickstarter.com/profile/endian">my kickstarter profile</a></p>


<p>After reading of a case in which <A href="http://rosalarian.tumblr.com/post/66303922266/alexds1-alexheberling-encik-farhan-is-a">a Kickstarter backer scammed dozens of artists</a>, one phrase stuck out to me. The phrase isn&rsquo;t in that link, and unfortunately, I can&rsquo;t find it in any others, but it goes something like: <em>[The scammer] doesn&rsquo;t give them any money, and gets to have all these projects shown on his profile</em>.</p>

<p>It made me realize Kickstarter&rsquo;s profiles worth looking at as a thing that people can actually be proud of. That appeal to a persons&rsquo;s sense of progress, and the desire to gather things. The little pie chat, especially, could be an example of <a href="http://www.psychologyofgames.com/2010/11/endowed-progress-effect-and-game-quests/">endowed progress</a>. Even if there&rsquo;s nothing necessarily telling you, &ldquo;Go fill in your pie chart!&rdquo; the fact that it&rsquo;s <em>there</em>, and it&rsquo;s <em>incomplete</em>&hellip;</p>

<p>Well, I feel compelled to fill it up. But I&rsquo;m also the type of person that restarted my Metroid Prime save file when I realized I missed scanning the first boss.</p>

<p>Kickstarter also offers some encouragement when you click the empty slice of your pie chart.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/kickstarter2.png" alt="A screenshot of my Kickstarter profile, after clicking on the 'design' slice"/></p>

<p class="caption">&#8220;Let&#8217;s change that!&#8221;</a></p>


<p>It&rsquo;s pretty cute that the slices are all (presumably) different colors, and I&rsquo;m really tempted to fill them in with $1 pledges to relevant projects. I wonder how Kickstarter encourages users to back more projects if they have filled in all their slices?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Football: Great for the Audience]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/13/football/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-13T19:17:44-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/13/football</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past weekend I finally learned about football, something I&rsquo;ve never been terribly interested in. The most recent game I watched was Kind Of A Big Deal for the city I live in.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/sea2.jpg" alt="Rain and cars and a distant Seattle Space Needle."/></p>

<p class="caption">distant space needle.</a></p>


<p>It strikes me that football is an incredibly fun game to watch because the &ldquo;four downs&rdquo; system provides a multitude of little goals to rejoice about. Each play is rife with struggle, with a victory that can turn into loss in an instant. It reminds me of Mark Rosewater&rsquo;s description of <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/magazine/article.aspx?x=mtg/daily/mm/174">interaction and a catch-up feature</a> as things that &ldquo;every game needs.&rdquo; At each &ldquo;down,&rdquo; both teams have the potential not just to stop each other, but to improve their own standing. It&rsquo;s a powerful interval.</p>

<p>Watching the game this past weekend was the first time in my life that I really, finally <em>got</em> it. I didn&rsquo;t know there were separate offensive and defensive teams; I didn&rsquo;t know that there were people whose singular jobs were to run, or to kick, and that the had individual tutors. It&rsquo;s pretty inspiring.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/sea1.jpg" alt="Seattle Space Needle with a flag that reads '12' on top "/></p>

<p class="caption">#gohawks! and, fun fact: &#8220;the 12th man&#8221; is a copyrighted phrase. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/12th_man_(football)#Texas_A.26M_trademark_issues_and_Seattle_Seahawks_lawsuit">a phrase <em>not</em> copyrighted by us.</a></p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design: UniCycle]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/unicycle/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-09T15:22:52-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/unicycle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For HCDE 518 the theme of our projects was &ldquo;UX for Good.&rdquo; I teamed up with three others (Joshua Coppola, Irene Huberman, and Matt Yukubousky) who were interested in solving climate change, and after admitting that &ldquo;solving climate change&rdquo; was going to be out of scope for the quarter, we searched for ways that we could encourage people to make better environmental choices.</p>

<p>One problem in encouraging environmentally friendly choices is that the immediate results of such choices are often negative. Good environmental decisions don&rsquo;t pay off for the actual environment immediately, and often your only tangible &ldquo;reward&rdquo; is the fact that you&rsquo;ve spent more time or money being good, as in the case of going to farmer&rsquo;s markets to buy organic or local produce. (Though for some I know the payoff of farmer&rsquo;s markets is better-tasting food, and forming relationships with the community, etc.)</p>

<p>We were all interested in designing <em>something</em> for our nearby community, and at some point someone finally brought up the concept of &ldquo;freecycling,&rdquo; which is the term for a community that gives and gets items from each other for free. (In this sense, it&rsquo;s really more like &ldquo;free-reusing&rdquo; than &ldquo;free-recycling.&rdquo;) We realized that such a system is perfect for implementation in a college campus, where living situations are temporary and fluid, requiring people to predictably give and get furniture like beds and couches when the academic year turns. Additionally, undergraduates in particular, lacking free-flowing cash, have a need of used items like textbooks and whatever other paraphernalia required of them in classes, like clickers. Groups in Seattle exist already for freecycling, such as <a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/freecycleseattle/info">Seattle Freecycle</a>, but none geared specifically for students who might need to quickly get rid of a bed before move-out, or require a specific edition of a book for a class.</p>

<p>Realizations in hand, we established our design question: <strong>How can we use technology to encourage reuse of goods within the University of Washington community?</strong></p>

<p>And after Bruce Perry came up with the perfect name for our project — <em>UniCycle</em> — we were all in.</p>

<h2>Surveys</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/unicycle/surveys.png" alt="Screenshot of some survey responses."/></p>

<p class="caption">screenshot of some survey responses</p>


<p>We developed a (somewhat long-ass) survey to kick off our user research, and distributed it across our social networks, the UW group we found at Reddit, and a Facebook group devoted to &ldquo;UW Textbook Exchange.&rdquo; The feedback we received overall to the idea of &ldquo;a site where people can easily exchange textbooks&rdquo; was very positive:</p>

<blockquote>“This idea is great and I hope it takes form soon! It eliminates the middle man like buffalo exchange that rips off the sellers and charges more for certain items to buyers to make profit.&#8221; - /u/huskygurll</blockquote>


<p>On the bright side, we learned that there are some clear pain points when students try to get rid of their stuff. Though many students desire to sell their textbooks and furniture, many do not because they don&rsquo;t want to go through the hassle of setting up prices, haggling, meeting up with people. In the case of female students, there was also the extra overhead of making sure they were safe when interacting with strangers.</p>

<p>Though we initially wanted to create a site that was devoted to <em>just</em> students giving each other things for free, students&#8217; reported consciousness of money made this unfeasible. Survey participants reported occasinally that, if they could not get enough money for Item X, they&rsquo;d rather keep it. With this in mind, we decided to design a hub for students to not just give each other things for free, but also sell or barter them away. &ldquo;Free items&rdquo; could continue to be our main headliner, however, something to draw people in the same way that Priceline draws customers with their &ldquo;name your own price&rdquo; system.</p>

<h2>Design Mapping</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/unicycle/designmapping.png" alt="Team UniCycle design mapping, and a close-up photo of the design mapping."/></p>

<p class="caption">design mapping</p>


<p>One design technique that was new to be this quarter was <strong>design mapping</strong>, which involves thinking through a user flow and taking note of everything that comes up using sticky notes. Green notes can stand for goals, pink notes for concerns, yellow for extra considerations, blue for possible new features — and so on. One thing I love about design mapping is that you are able to keep track of everything. When talking about how to support Yosh&rsquo;s desire to buy an old couch online, we don&rsquo;t need to silence the person that starts talking about bed bugs, and chastise them for going off-topic — we just add it to the map, and continue forward.</p>

<p>Design mapping helped us get a grip on the kinds of behaviors that we wanted to support with UniCycle: buy a used item, put a used item up for sale, contact a seller, and so on.</p>

<h2>Sketches</h2>


<p>We did a ton of sketches. Just, tons of them.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/unicycle/sketches2.png" alt="Sketching UniCycle UI on a whiteboard."/></p>

<p class="caption">here are just a few of them</p>


<p>I have to admit that it was hard to come up with so many ideas individually and then have to figure out how to actually move forward. It took us most of the afternoon, a huge whiteboard, and a lot of back-and-forth to decide on the almost-final interface that we wanted to go with, Once we did decide, it was tough to decide who was going to have the responsibility of moving forward with creating a paper prototype, or creating a digital prototype with something like Axure, which some of us wanted experience using.</p>

<p>It was at this time that we decided to try out a search based on &ldquo;hashtags,&rdquo; like Twitter or Tumblr. Because people could sell a variety of items on this site, we thought this would best allow them to categorize their items as they see fit. Additionally, hashtags like <code>#chem300</code> could be catch-alls for whatever you needed for a Chemistry 300 course: textbooks, clickers, lab coats, and so on.</p>

<h2>Paper Prototyping</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/unicycle/paperprototype.png" alt="Photos of the UniCycle paper prototype."/></p>

<p class="caption">photos of the paper prototype</p>


<p>I took partial responsibility for the paper prototype and the ensuing paper-scrap fest. Rendering the variety of items that people could &ldquo;search for&rdquo; using our paper UI was the most challenging bit, as was searching for the right pieces to show on the display. We created little modals to mimic &ldquo;Loading results&hellip;&rdquo; which were fun to use, and we also tried to solve for cases in which our paper prototype testers might search for an item that we didn&rsquo;t anticipate.</p>

<h2>Interactive Prototype</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/unicycle/unicycle_prototype.png" alt="Screenshot of UniCycle Interactive Prototype."/></p>

<p class="caption">screenshot of UniCycle&#8217;s interactive prototype</p>


<p>Our final product was an interactive prototype made in Axure by all of us, using a pretty fantastic blend of Axure&rsquo;s built-in SVN versioning and Dropbox. It is currently hosted <a href="http://students.washington.edu/jhc1/hcde518/start.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>My most beloved aspects of it are those that give feedback to users&#8217; actions. For example, the main page features tickets that enumerate the number of goods reused thus far, to surface the fact that people really <em>are</em> accomplishing something great through their small actions.</p>

<p>We also have some special tweaks just for UW students. For example, if you are looking for a particular textbook, you can list it on UniCycle. If you&rsquo;re selling, you can list a book by ISBN and have the titles and authors filled in automatically. Once you list a book, you are also made aware of the number of people who might already have that book marked as &ldquo;wanted&rdquo; — which is intended to help people feel like it&rsquo;s easy to sell on UniCycle. We also surface &ldquo;duedates&rdquo; for items, valuable if a user is trying to get rid of a bed before their lease is up.</p>

<p>After having dealt with it for a majority of the quarter, I&rsquo;m not totally sold on Axure yet, and will not likely use it to personally make hi-fidelity prototypes in the future. At that point in the process, I&rsquo;d just prefer to code things up myself. Additionally, I personally love the speed and humble honesty of paper prototyping, compared to Axure&rsquo;s interactive prototypes, which to me slip somewhat into the uncanny valley.</p>

<p>That being said, I&rsquo;m sure there will come a time when Axure is uniquely valuable, and I did like having to <em>not</em> worry about vertically centering random elements in CSS. Coding UniCycle as the sole programmer in a team of four would have been extremely taxing and it&rsquo;s nice that using Axure allowed us to work on a level playing field.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>


<p>I don&rsquo;t know that I&rsquo;ll return to UniCycle given the plethora of other projects I have, but it would be great to see it go places, especially given the need for it at UW. Too much goes wasted, and I&rsquo;d love to see people get into the habit of asking their community for needed items, as well as help others when it&rsquo;s needed.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also made a <a href="http://blog.neauro.com/files/hcde518_portfolio_deck.pdf">portfolio deck</a> that goes over other details for this project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Story: Monsterfolk]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/monsterfolk/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-09T14:32:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/monsterfolk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The most recent issue of AU is out at Bulldog News!</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/monsterfolk1.JPG" alt="AU Issue X at Bulldog News"/></p>

<p class="caption">Such AU Issue X!</p>


<p>This time the theme was <em>Monster</em> and for this story I have to admit that I was heavily inspired by <em>Howl&rsquo;s Moving Castle</em> and <em>Shadow of the Colossus</em>. <a href="https://twitter.com/couch_crusader">Chris</a> helped me come up with a name for my main character, though I hope that name isn&rsquo;t <em>too</em> obvious.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still working on a place to host my writing online. For now, if you&rsquo;re in Seattle, you can pick up a copy at Bulldog News!</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/monsterfolk2.JPG" alt="Monsterfolk at Bulldog News"/></p>

<p class="caption"><em>Monsterfolk</em>, complete with some sketches I did, which the editors asked to add!</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Story: Chronectomy]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/au13-submissions/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-09T13:06:27-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/au13-submissions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/chronectomy1.JPG" alt="AU Issue VIII at Bulldog News"/></p>

<p class="caption">AU Issue VIII at Bulldog News</p>


<p>I&rsquo;m into my last couple months as a UW student, and these are my last couple months to submit to <a href="http://strayingfromreality.wordpress.com/">AU</a>, UW&rsquo;s speculative fiction journal. Since the <a href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012-12-30-short-story-golemists-work.html">last time I&rsquo;ve written about it</a> I&rsquo;ve had two more acceptances! The story that I&rsquo;ll talk about in this post is <em>Chronectomy</em>, written for the Winter 2012, Issue VIII prompt: <em>chronos</em>, or time.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/chronectomy2.JPG" alt="Chronectomy!"/></p>

<p class="caption">Chronectomy! I LOVE what the editors did with the &#8220;O&#8217;s.&#8221;</p>


<p>I came up with an idea almost immediately and wrote furiously for a couple hours before realizing I was writing entirely the wrong story, and redid the entire thing. I&rsquo;m still working on a place to host my short stories online, but at least for now you can read <em>Chronectomy</em> on <a href="http://neauro.com">my portfolio</a>.</p>

<p>[ spoilers follow ]</p>

<p>I was really happy with the way I described the chronectomy clinic in this draft, but there were a couple problems overall that made me realize I had to totally redo it:</p>

<ul>
  <li>I intended this draft&#8217;s appeal to be that the audience has no idea what&#8217;s going on, but I realized that I wanted to write something a little deeper. In this draft, once you realize that the clinic is about removing memories, there&#8217;s not much else to get out of it.</li>
  <li>The protagonist of this draft, Alice, doesn&#8217;t have a very clear motive. Again, I was relying on there to be some kind of &#8220;Oohh, why is she here?&#8221; feeling to pull the audience through, but I wasn&#8217;t confident that all this exposition and description would be fun to read on its own, when you don&#8217;t even know why the character is there.</li>
  <li>At the end, I wanted to pull a sort of &#8220;Whoa! Bet you didn&#8217;t see that coming!&#8221; moment, where the clinician suddenly steals the protagonist&#8217;s memories for himself — but I realized that by the time you reach the end, you don&#8217;t know enough about him at all to care that he stole her memories, nor do you know why he did so. You also never know the protagonist well enough to care that her memories were stolen, since she&#8217;s shrouded in mystery for the draft&#8217;s majority.</li>
  <li>Since the original prompt was related to &#8220;time,&#8221; my initial intention was to explore what people would do with time — selling it, donating it, using it to heal their mental trauma, and so on. When the clinician starts reciting all these uses to the protagonist, I realized that those things were all way more interesting than what was happening right then in the story, and that furthermore, all these uses were just being talked about, and not actually experienced.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, I realized the better perspective to use for this story was not Alice but the clinician, and why he would steal someone else&rsquo;s memory in the first place.</p>

<p>Draft below the cut.</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr/>


<p>The clinic was a low building perched on a strip, cornered between a sit-down pho place and a hole-in-the-wall that dispensed frozen yogurt from ancient, sticky machines. It was delicious, in part because of the sheer novelty of getting yogurt from a machine you expected would only cough out rust and coppery water. And it was cheap — a dollar six for a cup that sat easily in your palm, and only fifty cents more for a tablespoon of chopped pineapple and chocolate chips.</p>

<p>Her lips pursed and she felt tears well in her eyes. It made the building, already blurry with heat, even more hazy and dream-like. There were protestors lined up on the curb outside the clinic and she marched across the parking lot clutching the bulky duffel bag like a shield. As she approached, one of the protestors stabbed his spork into a soft boulder of yogurt freckled with rainbow sprinkles, and lifted one of the signs that was leaning on the clinic wall.</p>

<p>&ldquo;All of life is a gift,&rdquo; he managed loudly, and as yogurt spilled on his shirt the rest of the group cackled. A girl hit him playfully on the shoulder. It seemed the appointment was during the high school shift.</p>

<p>She tried not to look at them, but couldn&rsquo;t help glancing down as she stepped over their polished legs. One girl cried, &ldquo;Just be strong! Don&rsquo;t throw yourself away!&rdquo; And one boy called, &ldquo;Come on, we&rsquo;ll buy you a yogurt if you cancel,&rdquo; and the girls again squealed with feigned indignation between yogurt-dripping laughs.</p>

<p>She swallowed and reached for the door. There was a sticker on it, a logo of beige hands holding two sides of an hourglass and pouring the grains from one side into the other. Her sweating palms slid on the searing metal of the door handle and she winced. The laughter rang in her ears. One of the boys had a familiar laugh, bright, the too-loud kind that was swollen with all the air in his lungs and was let out in booms that encompassed everyone an drew them in. Her heart clenched. And she yanked the door as hard as she could.</p>

<p>The door rattled fiercely and did not open. Her perspiring hand slipped off the handle and she nearly fell back.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You have to push,&rdquo; the boy told her, and pronounced each with so slowly that she had pushed the door and moved inside before he finished the sentence.</p>

<p>It was air-conditioned inside, and the cool air soothed her flushed cheeks. After the outside, which had been blurry with heat, the details of the inside of the clinic seemed unreasonably sharp. There was no chrome in sight, no blustering or chirping machines, no bubbling beakers. The walls were off-white and decorated with fake paintings of pastel flowers straining as if to escape their plastic frames. The furniture was like stuff she might have seen in a normal doctor&rsquo;s office, plastic cushions that were easy to clean and squeaked a little when she set her bag down.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good morning! I can help you here,&rdquo; said the person at the counter, a man her age who had just walked in and was tugging a white doctor&rsquo;s coat sleeve hastily over a tattoo on his forearm. She approached cautiously, eyes cast on the little bit of ink she could see beyond the cuff.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Film,&rdquo; he explained with a smile, and tugged the sleeve up to show her, a tattoo&rsquo;d sleeve of cinema tape encircling a tab arm. &ldquo;They like that I keep it under wraps.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She made her mouth into a smile for him. He had had a tattoo too — also a sleeve, though the opposite arm. He had gotten it on a trip he had taken by himself to Hawand it symbolized &ldquo;freedom.&rdquo; (Now she wondered, Freedom from what? And, He probably was lying about going alone, wasn&rsquo;t he?)</p>

<p>She managed to uncoil her knotting throat and said, &ldquo;Thanks for taking me on such short notice. I saw the clinic isn&rsquo;t usually open at this time.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He smiled at her. &ldquo;No problem. It does keep the protestors off our back to accept patients at strange times. Those kids they post out there don&rsquo;t really care one way or another.&rdquo; He gestured at a door in the lounge. &ldquo;You wanna come back?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Shouldn&rsquo;t I fill out some paperwork or something?&rdquo;</p>

<p>He cocked his head. &ldquo;Do you want to?&rdquo;</p>

<p>And have a trail that connected her with a chronectomy, something that future employers would find and wonder and not give her the benefit of a doubt about?</p>

<p>&ldquo;Not really,&rdquo; she admitted.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Then, no paperwork. I will need payment up front though. In case you forget later.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Um,&rdquo; she murmured, &ldquo;I heard that I could get any fees waived if I&hellip;donated&hellip;?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;In that case,&rdquo; he said, &ldquo;all you need to fill out is this waiver.&rdquo; He slid a pink slip toward her and she plucked a pen from a little hourglass container where it had been stabbed upright into sand-colored lentils. She read it briefly and checked the appropriate boxes.</p>

<p>I agree to donate. I understand my donation waives all fees.</p>

<p>I understand I will not be able to review the [something something — a Latin word]. I agree they will be the sole property of Chosen Life, to dispose of at will.</p>

<p>There was a signature area at the bottom. She hadn’t been asked for ID. She considered and then wrote Alice on the line. Who cared?</p>

<p>She marked the right boxes and slid the paper back. He looked at it briefly and then filed it away.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Then,&rdquo; he said, gesturing to a door connecting the lounge and the back of the clinic, &ldquo;follow me.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She hesitated. Wariness bloomed in her. It was strange that the clinic was empty; it was strange that the only person here was a man, and a pretty young one at that, maybe nothing more than an intern. But she had trusted her gut before and it had let her down, further than she had ever known she could go. She walked through the door.</p>

<p>The clinician was waiting for her on the other side. He led we through a small hallway. &ldquo;What was your name, again?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Alice,&rdquo; she decided.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, Alice,&rdquo; he said, opening a door for her, &ldquo;you can call me Liu. I&rsquo;m not a doctor — not yet — but I am a certified chronectomist. Please have a seat. We can have you out of here in fifteen minutes, max.&rdquo;</p>

<p>So Liu was some kind of neotech grad student. Just like&hellip;</p>

<p>Stop. Don&rsquo;t even start. She forced herself to take a breath, which juddered in her throat. She expected one of the long tables with adjustable height and a paper on it, but the room had a divan like her psychiatrist. She hesitated when she saw it and Liu laughed.</p>

<p>&ldquo;None of that feely-weepy stuff here. Just make yourself comfortable while I set up.&rdquo; He glanced up at the clock in the room and then began to rummage around the drawers, fumbling with white plastic instruments sealed in bags.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Can I ask a couple questions?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Sure! Fire away. And hold out your right arm.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She pulled back her sleeve and he velcroed a strap over her arm that squeezed it uncomfortably.</p>

<p>She swallowed. &ldquo;Is it true that I&rsquo;ll age a little bit? Physically?&rdquo;</p>

<p>He smiled, as if to say, It&rsquo;s okay, I get this question all the time. &ldquo;No, you won&rsquo;t. The procedure is called a chronectomy, but what&rsquo;s really extracted are memories — the footprints of time on your brain. If anything, technically, you’ll be getting a little younger. Hmm, looks like your blood pressure’s just a tad low.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah. Is that okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s fine.&rdquo; He turned and reached for one of the instruments that was unearthed. Curious, she strained to see. There were two rings. &ldquo;Now, hold out your middle fingers. Politely, of course.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She did.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Is it possible that I might lose other memories I don&rsquo;t want to?&rdquo; she asked.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Nope, and you’ll see why in a bit.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What happens to them? After they&rsquo;re&hellip;after I donate them? I know I won’t have a say in them anymore, but&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It’s fine, I can answer that. A couple things can happen to them.&rdquo; He had a little vial and waggled it around as he spoke. &ldquo;Usually it gets sold. Depending on the content, you can help other people with it — sometimes the government will buy it for war veterans — ’time heals all wounds,’ you know. Psychologists and the like can use it for research. And — this is not Chosen Life, understand, but in the black markets — sometimes people come and they’ll sell their memories of studying for a test to richer students. There are growing markets over in Asia where people are selling hours of studying for a pretty prime price. It’s fascinating.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Spoken like a true grad student.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Of course, it all depends on the memory. Are you ready to get started?&rdquo;</p>

<p>She swallowed. &ldquo;Yes.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Liu nodded. He rolled a tray beside her and, after unpackaging it, handed it to her. It was a simple mask, like a.surgeon’s mask, but made of soft cotton. He put one on as we&rsquo;ll, but it was impermeable pale green plastic and rubber.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Put this on.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She did. The mask&rsquo;s rubber band was too tight and quickly tangled in her hair. Liu tugged it a couple times and when he was certain it was secure around her mouth and nose he rapped the vial one last time against his palm and then opened it carefully. There was a dropper protruding from the inside of the lid and he filled it up with clear liquid, and pinched it onto her cotton mask.</p>

<p>It soaked into the cotton. She jumped. It had a strong smell that she wasn’t expecting. It smelled like — like —</p>

<p>&ldquo;Take a deep breath,&rdquo; he told her. She had stopped breathing in panic. She took a deep breath and the smell took form. It was like drinking cold water on a hot day but instead of trickling down ice cold between her ribs it trickled upward, a fuzzy warmth that permeated against the roof of her mouth, the veins behind her eyeballs, the place in her brain that ached every morning she woke up and realized she was without him. She trembled and her eyes began to water. She felt separated from her limbs,and for that reason fumbled when Liu started to shove something into her hands. Her fingers fumbled around the strange object. It took her a while to realize it was a pen.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Write as you answer,&rdquo; Liu said. His voice was a whisper, but it reverberated throughout her body. &ldquo;What does it smell like?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Like his jacket,&rdquo; she said, through a haze. Her voice was loud. She heard her teeth clicking as she spoke, as if she were underwater. Her hand scribbled. &ldquo;Like his cologne. Like our pillows in the morning.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Invent-o-thon]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/inventathon/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T16:09:18-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/inventathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A is starting a certificate program in game design this quarter and I&rsquo;ve been helping him with his card game, Invent-o-thon.</p>

<p>The prompt being something related to <em>Victorian Combat</em>, he first went around researching what people &ldquo;first thought of when they think about the Victorian Era,&rdquo; and I was happy to hammer in the presence of Ada Lovelace, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace">The World&rsquo;s First Computer Programmer</a>. Because I&rsquo;m more interested in stories, I also talked with him about stories — in particular, making noteworthy experiences that people are excited to talk to each other about after the fact. Or, in general, creating situations in which people&rsquo;s imaginations are prompted and stretch and fill in ridiculous gaps.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/inventothon/playtest1.jpg" alt="What is a faith-powered tummy mobile?"/></p>

<p class="caption">what is a faith-powered tummy mobile FIGURE IT OUT DO IT</p>


<p>A obtained a bunch of card sleeves and post-it notes for our paper prototyping. The point of the game is to create an invention over several rounds, then present it at &ldquo;showtime&rdquo; to everyone and roll dice to see if your invention explodes. Thus far, players construct machines using three decks: one deck to describe a &ldquo;power source&rdquo; (like &ldquo;electric&rdquo;), one deck to describe a &ldquo;subject&rdquo; (like &ldquo;kittens&rdquo;), and one deck to describe the actual invention (like &ldquo;generator&rdquo;).</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/inventothon/playtest1_cards.JPG" alt="Playtest cards"/></p>

<p class="caption">physically impossible bathtub packer</p>


<p>We also gathered friends to do a playtest at a cafe.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/inventothon/playtest2.jpg" alt="Playtest cards"/></p>

<p class="caption">kind of pathetic pleasure chamber&#8230;and others</p>


<p>One of the most valuable things learned from prototyping was which cards were compelling and funny, and which cards weren&rsquo;t — descriptive cards that seemed perfectly fine, like &ldquo;hydro-powered&rdquo; or &ldquo;solar-powered,&rdquo; were just not as fun to use as &ldquo;perfectly ordinary&rdquo; or &ldquo;rather moist&rdquo; and never quite made it to showtime. It makes sense that something like &ldquo;perfectly ordinary&rdquo; lights up more parts of your story-minded brain than &ldquo;hydro-powered,&rdquo; and overall could have more flavor. (What&rsquo;s a &ldquo;perfectly ordinary kitten-mobile&rdquo;?)</p>

<p>I sketched out some possibilities for card designs&hellip;</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/inventothon/cardsketch.jpg" alt="Sketches of cards"/></p>

<p class="caption">sketches of cards</p>


<p>&hellip;and A also reined in his sister for some concept art of character roles that players could have that affected their inventions. For example, someone who was Benjamin Franklin might be able to totally swap inventions with someone else before showtime. (Oo! Sick burn!)</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/inventothon/concept.jpg" alt="Concept art of Nikola Tesla"/></p>

<p class="caption">concept art of Nikola Tesla</p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts Re: Thomas Was Alone]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/thomas-was-alone/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T09:52:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/thomas-was-alone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/twa.png" alt="Screenshot of Thomas Was Alone"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<a href="http://www.mobygames.com/game/windows/thomas-was-alone/screenshots/gameShotId,566500/">via</a>)</p>


<p><em>Thomas Was Alone</em> was super cute, if more ambiguous than I personally like. I liked the personality given to all the different shapes, though their common heroism and conceit got a little old as the game went on, which was why Laura&rsquo;s cynicism made her my favorite (though I felt compelled inexlicably to keep calling her &ldquo;Ruth&rdquo;). I loved that the levels were tilted, the play of light, the strange colors. (Though I wonder if any colorblind users had a hard time playing?)</p>

<p>One thing I think the game could have been improved was the game&rsquo;s sense of progression; though numbers ticked up each level, after a while they became meaningless, and now that the game is finished I&rsquo;m not totally sure what I would use them for. The introduction of each of the colored shapes, Thomas&rsquo;s &ldquo;death,&rdquo; and the era of the gray shapes seemed to be the largest movements in the story, and though each was accompanied with a fun snippet of &ldquo;The AIs are gaining sentience!&rdquo; flavor I didn&rsquo;t really have a sense that things were reaching their end until the end came suddenly to meet me. Some levels seemed like little &ldquo;drabbles&rdquo; and experiments, which I completed without much more effort than would take for me to click a cow in Farmville, and it would have been cool to see something else related to AIs breaking their previous ways of being. Breaking through the borders of levels — intentionally disobeying orders — something to add to the flavor text.</p>

<p>I played <em>Thomas Was Alone</em> on a projector and if you have the opportunity to do so yourself I recommend it. All those rectangles are like way better when they&rsquo;re as big as your face.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running IE7, IE8, and IE9 on a Mac, Using VirtualBox]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/virtualbox/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T09:07:20-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/virtualbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been putting off getting a virtual machine running on the Mac computer I use for work, mostly because I wanted to forget the existence of &lt;IE9 browsers entirely. Unfortunately, the visual bugs accumulating across my projects were starting to get a little ridiculous.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/proleft.png" alt="Screenshot of IE8 errors"/></p>

<p class="caption">omg why</p>


<p>After some hours of searching and fiddling, I discovered my favorite solution for running IE on a Mac. It goes like this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Download the relevant/recent version of Oracle&#8217;s <a href="http://www.virtualbox.org">VirtualBox</a>.</li>
<li>Use the Terminal and and run <code>curl -s https://raw.github.com/xdissent/ievms/master/ievms.sh | env IEVMS_VERSIONS="8 9" bash</code> to download 2 virtual machines; one that can run IE8, and one that can run IE9.</li>
</ol>


<p>That&rsquo;s it! Once that&rsquo;s finished, you can open VirtualBox and you&rsquo;ll see your boxes all ready to go.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/virtualbox.png" alt="Screenshot of IE8 in VirtualBox"/></p>

<p class="caption">only IE8 is pictured above</p>


<p>Thanks to <a href="http://osxdaily.com/2011/09/04/internet-explorer-for-mac-ie7-ie8-ie-9-free/">OSXDaily</a> for the post that led me to finding <a href="https://github.com/xdissent">xdissent</a>&rsquo;s awesome installations.</p>

<p>Other notes:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>border-radius</code>, <code>rem</code>, and <code>opacity</code> are some of the many words not recognized by IE8.</li>
<li>PressF12 to open up IE8&#8217;s Developer Tools.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Tumblr: Delightful UX]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/07/delightful-ux/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-07T14:39:07-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/07/delightful-ux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/delightful-ux.png" alt="Screenshot of delightful-ux.tumblr.com"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com">via</a>)</p>


<p>For whatever reason, <a href="http://tumblr.com">Tumblr</a> is becoming my social media site of choice, probably because its humor appeals to me so much. I also love that it supports people easily creating blogs that cater to specific topics &mdash; like <a href="http://medievalpoc.tumblr.com/">people of color in medieval art</a>, or <a href="http://moviecode.tumblr.com/">source code in TV and films</a>, or <a href="http://tabcloseddidntread.com/">intrusive pop-ups</a>.</p>

<p>Anyway, I&rsquo;ve made my own tumblr for gathering examples of <a href="http//delightful-ux.tumblr.com">delightful user experience</a>, which is my main interest when it comes to the wide world of human-centered design. Even though I love it, I&rsquo;m still muddy on what comprises a delightful user experience, and thus far have tossed in examples of <a href="http://adobe.breach.il.ly/#/about">useful websites with friendly wording</a>, as well as <a href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com/post/71660750263/hells-pizza-coffin-box-new-zealand-based-hell">pizza box designs with unnecessary but awesome utility</A>, and <a href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com/post/71681828062/australian-sharks-send-tweets-to-warn-swimmers">sharks with Twitter accounts</a>.</p>

<p>For now, when deciding whether to add an example, I ask myself, &ldquo;Could this Thing accomplish what it currently accomplishes, but in a more boring way?&rdquo; Or, &ldquo;Does this Thing solve for an action that is not-that-fun to do?&rdquo; And if the answer to either is &ldquo;yes!&rdquo; — lo, thusly do I deem it delightful.</p>

<p>I understand that second question might still catch Things that are not entirely playful — but I&rsquo;m not going to stress out about differentiating between design that&rsquo;s good and design that fulfills some nebulously defined good feel.</p>

<p>If you have encountered a good feel recently yourself, feel free to <a href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com/submit">submit</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts Re: Phoenix Wright: Dual Destinies]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/23/phoenix-wright/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-23T11:03:14-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/23/phoenix-wright</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/aceattorney5.png" alt="Apollo Justice, Phoenix Wright, and Athena Cykes from Phoenix Wright: Dual Destinies"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.joystiq.com/2013/10/24/phoenix-wright-dual-destinies-review-f8ea4d29/">via</a>)</p>


<p>After NaNoWriMo finished, my pastime of choice during my commute became playing through <em>Phoenix Wright: Dual Destinies</em>.</p>

<p>[ spoilers ahead ]</p>

<p>Athena was a cool protagonist, though scenes where she was relegated to &ldquo;cyncial dude&rsquo;s naive, enthusiastic female sidekick&rdquo; were yawny. (Come on! Maya and Trucy are already these characters, we don&rsquo;t need more of them.) Ultimately it&rsquo;s nice to see that Athena has her own reasons for entering the attourneyforce, and though they were man-centered they were also totally platonic, which was nice. Athena&rsquo;s devoting to &ldquo;saving&rdquo; Blackquill also mirrored her desire to save her best friend, Juniper Woods, which meant her dramatic, heroic tendencies at least were in character.</p>

<p>Mostly I was happy to see old characters again, even Apollo Justice, who I disliked before but liked in <em>Dual Destinies</em>, probably because he was now a familiar face, haha. What I wanted most out of this game was to see Maya again, but I guess a note from her will do in lieu of <em>nothing</em>.</p>

<p>I also liked <em>Dual Destinies</em>&lsquo; execution of &ldquo;telling the end at the beginning.&rdquo; One of my favorite parts was realizing that Apollo had had an eyepatch over his eye even <em>before the courtroom explosion</em> — it was a fun/cute manipulation of the audience&rsquo;s assumptions that that particular bandage was just part of his injuries.</p>

<p>Good examples of &ldquo;the end at the beginning&rdquo; does <em>not</em>, however, include all the times that the game felt obliged to either tell you who the antagonist was, or make it clearly obvious, and PWDD&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://www.awkwardzombie.com/index.php?page=0&comic=123013">serious case of the hand-holdies</a>&rdquo; led to me to really only loving the game&rsquo;s final case, and feeling shruggy about the others. It would have been nice if each case had contributed more to each character&rsquo;s development as well; &ldquo;Ninetails Vale&rdquo; in particular didn&rsquo;t feel tied to anything in the larger story, and as a standalone wasn&rsquo;t terribly interesting to me either.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netflix: Such Killer Whales]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/20/on-netflix-killer-whales/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-20T06:55:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/20/on-netflix-killer-whales</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/blackfish-poster.jpg" alt="Blackfish poster"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.magpictures.com/blackfish/">via</a>)</p>


<p>Documentaries are my whitenoise of choice. Due to studying, I&rsquo;ve been listening to a lot more of them on Netflix.</p>

<p>More recently, I&rsquo;ve two documentaries about orcas: <em>Killer Whales</em> by the Discovery Channel, about the behavior of killer whales in the wild; and <em>Blackfish</em>, about orcas held in captivity. They&rsquo;re both pretty incredible; I&rsquo;m shocked at how much footage there is of killer whales doing things, whether it&rsquo;s hunting poisonous sting rays in New Zealand or yanking human beings into pools by their ankles.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s pretty hilarious to watch the footage of killer whales hunting seals in the first documentary, with a voiceover of a man marveling at their intelligence; and to watch this footage again in the second, where the background noise is preserved, and a woman is panicking, &ldquo;Oh no! Oh no! <em>On noooo</em>!&rdquo;</p>

<p><em>Blackfish</em> also connected nicely with the last essay in <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Best-American-Science-Nature-Writing/dp/0547350635">The Best American Science and Nature Writing (2011)</a>, though the writer states there that one of the orca trainers was pulled by her hair into the water, whereas trainers in the <em>Blackfish</em> movie argue that this is a lie, another way to &ldquo;blame the victim&rdquo; of the orca attack, rather than the orca itself and the poor treatment that drove it to &ldquo;psychopathy.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frozen]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/18/frozen/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-18T09:24:39-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/18/frozen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/frozen-poster.jpg" alt="Frozen poster"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.comingsoon.net/news/movienews.php?id=109012">via</a>)</p>


<p>A and I went to see <em>Frozen</em>, a movie I had very little interest in seeing until I realized Idina Menzel was voicing a main character. There&rsquo;s been a lot said already for the lack of diversity amongst the characters (regarding both <a href="">race</a>, as well as <a href="http://sapphicdalliances.tumblr.com/post/68881922280">the representation of women</a>) and my disappointment about these issues in <em>Frozen</em> has exhausted me utterly. I don&rsquo;t want to talk about it. Instead, I want to note aspects of the overall story that A and I discussed after the movie.</p>

<p>[ spoilers ahead ]</p>

<h2><em>Frozen</em> is about Elsa and Anna</h2>

<p>This is great. From the trailers, there was almost no indication that the story&rsquo;s main conflict involved the relationship between two women. Anna struggles somewhat with the men in the story, and though she desires &ldquo;true love&rdquo; at its beginning, lovers never usurp her existing relationship with her sister. At the end, Anna even plays the main role in saving both Elsa and herself, through the power of ~<em>True Love</em>~! Hurray!</p>

<h2>But what does <em>Frozen</em> do with &ldquo;True Love&rdquo;?</h2>

<p>&ldquo;True Love&rdquo; seems to be Frozen&rsquo;s main theme. Elsa&rsquo;s version of True Love is &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t harm those who you love,&rdquo; and requires her to isolate herself as a precaution to harming her sister; the fact that doing so makes both her and Anna unhappy are not as important as Anna&rsquo;s safety. At the end of the movie, Elsa realizes (somewhat abruptly) that her version of True Love is flawed, presumably because it&rsquo;s more about fearing herself, rather than loving someone else. (…right? This actually happened so suddenly that I&rsquo;m just going to believe that this is the case.)</p>

<p>In contrast, Anna&rsquo;s version of true love — which could be described as &ldquo;Always believe in someone that you love&rdquo; — has absolutely no fear involved. Despite everyone&rsquo;s warnings and panic, Anna continues to believe the best of Elsa, even when Elsa actually <em>does</em> harm her.</p>

<p>I like how Elsa and Anna&rsquo;s interpretations of love clash in this movie, but one thing I don&rsquo;t like is that, though Elsa&rsquo;s view of love evolves by the end of the movie, Anna&rsquo;s view remains static. From the beginning Anna is the same &ldquo;open to loving people!&rdquo; character that she&rsquo;s shown to be from the beginning, despite events that show people can harm her: Elsa ostracizes her, Love Interest #1 (Hans) betrays her. That these events don&rsquo;t change her outlook on life feels like a waste; rather than actively choosing to love people, for Anna it&rsquo;s just a given, and this takes away from her complexity and agency as a character.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s worse is that the events of the movie are put into motion by Elsa&rsquo;s fear that she might kill Anna, and by the end of the movie, it&rsquo;s revealed that there was no way that Elsa could have ever killed Anna at all. The entire time, Anna had a magical understanding of &ldquo;True Love&rdquo; that could have <em>always</em> saved her from Elsa&rsquo;s power, which makes the entire plot somewhat of a non-issue.</p>

<h2>And what did the other characters do?</h2>

<p>Given that the movie&rsquo;s main conflict is Elsa and Anna&rsquo;s relationship, and true love, the other major characters — Kristoff, Olaf, and Hans — all felt thrown in. I would have loved to see them all focused to serve the &ldquo;true love&rdquo; theme by addressing love in different ways. Treated differently, Kristoff could have been a great catalyst for Anna&rsquo;s development of her version of love. I&rsquo;m inagining him, a character distrusting of other humans, teaching her about the horrible things humans do; she fights it (&ldquo;No way, humans are inherently Lawful Good!&rdquo;); Kristoff then points out that her sister is laying waste to their kingdom and also has been pretty mean in general to people; Anna cracks a bit; and then, right on cue, Anna is betrayed again by Hans.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/anna.jpg" alt="Frozen poster"/></p>

<p class="caption">omg will she now become totally jaded? or will she still choose looove? (<A href="http://turntherightcorner.com/2013/09/27/movie-trailer-for-disneys-frozen/disneys-frozen-2013-screenshot-princess-anna/">via</a>)</p>


<p>Kristoff&rsquo;s dislike of humans is played up without explanation of how it came to be, as if he had simply dropped out of the sky as a perfectly-formed gruff male love interest. I would have loved to see more time spent on him and his relationship with Sven and the snow trolls, rather than other seemingly extraneous details of his character. For example, why is it important that Kristoff is an ice merchant, and what was the point of the opening scene that is dedicated to showing his childlike failure at selling ice? You learn later that Kristoff was adopted by the trolls, and distrusts other humans; so if Kristoff was actually homeless at the beginning of the movie, why did he have a sled and ice-harvesting tools at his disposal? (Or was he not homeless? Are we just supposed to be okay with his abduction?) My headcanon involves Kristoff having saved Sven from the cruelties of humans in his life — meeting the trolls — realizing that they&rsquo;re way better.</p>

<p>Olaf was a character I grimaced at in the movie trailers and ended up being pleasantly entertained by.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/olaf.gif" alt="Frozen poster"/></p>

<p class="caption">oh youu (<A href="http://worldbuiltfor2.tumblr.com/post/69015715475/when-someone-emotionally-hurts-you-but-you-have-to">via</a>)</p>


<p>Even though his main purpose is comedic entertainment, it would have been nice to see more about what he means to Anna and Elsa&rsquo;s relationship. He&rsquo;s their precious childhood snowman, and is really the only indication Anna has that Elsa still treasures her after years of being isolated.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="http://blog.neauro.com/images/olaf.jpg" alt="Frozen poster"/></p>

<p class="caption">love again, anna! do iiit! (<A href="http://www.rotoscopers.com/2013/09/27/ten-things-we-loved-about-the-new-frozen-trailer/">via</a>)</p>


<p>As for the last major-ish character, Hans: I wasn&rsquo;t too interested in him, and wish that all the time devoted to him was given to the other characters instead. Hans is too flat, an antagonist that comes out of nowhere, affects no one uniquely, and isn&rsquo;t redeemed. Anna could have been betrayed by any other person; Kristoff could have found any other, more character-specific reason to back off from being with Anna.</p>

<h2>In conclusion</h2>

<p>I had a lot of fun watching <em>Frozen</em>, particularly with the ~<em>twist</em>~ of Anna saving herself. And her kiss at the end with Kristoff was such consensual wow! Also, the particle effects were great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
