<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Bad Ux | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/bad-ux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T19:51:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two Wishes for Orca Card]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/30/two-wishes-for-orca-card/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/30/two-wishes-for-orca-card</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8bC74HOcr-8/UCLmDvd3phI/AAAAAAAAB9Q/U-4kald-qnA/s1600/3465566019_86060511e0.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8bC74HOcr-8/UCLmDvd3phI/AAAAAAAAB9Q/U-4kald-qnA/s320/3465566019_86060511e0.jpg" width="240" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">photo by JeanineAnderson (<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/jeanineanderson/3465566019/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><br /><a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2011/11/i-seriously-notice-this-all-time-which.html">I've written before about the Orca Card</a>, which is essentially Seattle's digital purse for public transportation: buses, ferries, our single light-rail system. Now that it's summer and I've come to rely more on my Orca Card instead of my beloved (yet inactive) student bus pass, a couple things become apparent:<br /><br /><ol><li><b>I really wish I knew when my transfers ended. </b>I don't even remember how long transfers are supposed to last. Two hours? Three? When you pay in cash, the bus driver hands you a little piece of paper which can be used as fare for your next bus ride, as long as you're fairly within time limits. With Orca, your transfer is invisible, and strict -- are you leaving the bus two minutes after your fare is up, because of traffic or because the bus itself is late? Too bad, you're paying the fare again. (This also gets frustrating when you board a bus that's "Pay as you leave" -- because even if you got on the bus within the time limit, what if you disembark too late?)</li><li><b>I really wish I knew how much money I had on my card as soon as I looked at it. </b>In my mind I imagine a little E-ink box that would happily display your available funds, in a futuristic, perfect society. To be fair, the card reader does tell you what your card's remaining balance is once you swipe, but I find myself squinting at the small, gray-on-gray display every time I pass by. And, it would also be nice if this card reader could tell you things like, "Hey, your transfer will be up at 4:15pm!"</li></ol><div><br /></div><div>Not knowing when your transfers end can also be problematic for low-income users; as a professor in the HCDE department at UW <a href="http://bethkolko.wordpress.com/2011/04/16/how-technology-encodes-values/">points out</a>&nbsp;from a student dissertation, "Basically, you board the bus and swipe your card. If you’re inside the allotted transit time, nothing is deducted from your card. If not, the full fare comes off your card. And for some people, that might have been their way to work tomorrow. And that’s it for their cash this week."</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Ux] BookScan Station]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/11/ux-bookscan-station/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/11/ux-bookscan-station</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">If you are going to impose a size limit on the scans that people want to e-mail to themselves...</div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vcX6B8FB-M0/T_29Kt4Z3RI/AAAAAAAABp0/HFhUfiMxgM8/s1600/emailsize.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vcX6B8FB-M0/T_29Kt4Z3RI/AAAAAAAABp0/HFhUfiMxgM8/s320/emailsize.jpg" width="311" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">"Email maximum size is 50MB."</td></tr></tbody></table><br />...then there should be a way to know how many bytes you've already used up with your present scans.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8PlAPoiu1PU/T_29K-gjrtI/AAAAAAAABp8/--wlvqq0Xkc/s1600/emailsize2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8PlAPoiu1PU/T_29K-gjrtI/AAAAAAAABp8/--wlvqq0Xkc/s320/emailsize2.jpg" width="311" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">essential information, where you at?</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><div>Especially if the only warning you get when you go over is when you are just about to e-mail something. At this point, the only option left for users is to go back and delete scans that they've already done, which means they'll need to be scanned again.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Seriously Notice This All the Time, Which Probably Means It Could Be Made Better]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/11/15/i-seriously-notice-this-all-time-which/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/11/15/i-seriously-notice-this-all-time-which</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Bus drivers in Seattle will sometimes talk to passengers as they enter the bus.  As passengers step up, the drivers will put their hands over the little fare box to obstruct it, and repeat, loudly, "Pay as you leave.  <em>Pay as you leave.  PAY AS YOU LEAVE.</em>"<br /><br />Alas!  It's too late.  The person was talking on their cellphone and already swiped their Orca card on the Orca card reader.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8bC74HOcr-8/UCLmDvd3phI/AAAAAAAAB9Q/U-4kald-qnA/s1600/3465566019_86060511e0.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8bC74HOcr-8/UCLmDvd3phI/AAAAAAAAB9Q/U-4kald-qnA/s320/3465566019_86060511e0.jpg" width="240" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">photo by JeanineAnderson (<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/jeanineanderson/3465566019/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />After doing this, the bus driver will usually just sigh.<br /><br />Orca is (essentially) just a fancy debit card for public transportation in some counties around southern Puget Sound.  To use, you fill it up with money and then press it against the Orca card reader, which is located further away than the bus driver can reach to block it from hasty passengers responding to habit and the design of the bus entranceway.  Swiping your Orca card incorrectly may result in some weird things happening with your fare (things possibly related to how your transfers are monitored), and though I don't know the exact repercussions of paying when you enter the bus instead of when you exit, it is kind of sad to see bus drivers being frustrated with this, especially since I learned in an Informatics class last year that bus drivers have some pretty serious rules governing their work.<br /><br />Also especially since I feel like there are a couple ways you could mitigate this frustration:<br /><ul><li><strong>Move the Orca card reader closer to the bus driver.</strong>  Then the bus driver could reach over and cover the card reader much in the same way I see them covering the fare box.  I think this could be the least expensive solution.</li><li><strong>If someone tries to pay when they are not supposed to, the Orca reader shouldn't charge them.</strong>  There are already <a href="http://www.onebusaway.org/">technologies</a> in use that make use of what I assume is a capability to know where a bus is at a certain time, which could be used to know when people should be charged, and for what rate.  (Presently drivers fiddle with the Orca card readers to make sure that people get charged properly, which seems like it may be an unnecessary task.) People try to pay for the bus all the time in the Ride Free area and it doesn't matter how many nice, green "Ride Free" signs there are, they just don't read -- so just account for it.  Extra advantage: bus driver thinks less about fares in general, and more about just driving.  (Disadvantage: This doesn't account for cash fares.  Also, how are you really supposed to know when people are entering or exiting, to figure out whether they should be charged?<ul><li>Use cameras to measure differences in position to determine a passenger's direction?</li><li>Count the number of times a door opens and closes?</li><li>Or, since you don't really need to touch Orca cards directly to the Orca card reader and James keeps talking about how easy it is to sniff data from Orca cards, maybe the transaction should just happen as people are standing on the bus, so they don't pause to pay with an Orca at all.  Thus you could have something like: a) Charge everyone as they get on the bus, b) If a person leaves the bus in a Ride Free area, put the money back on the card, c) Else, if the person leaves the bus after leaving the Ride Free Area, just leave the charge on the card.)</li></ul></li></ul><br />Granted, these are all probably past the power of our struggling transportation system (though I admit I only describe as struggling due to <a href="http://seattlebikeblog.com/2011/11/09/seattles-prop-1-soundly-defeated/">Prop. 1</a> failing recently and grumbling anecdotes on Facebook about the inefficiency of buses).</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
