<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Travel | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-27T09:05:28-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SpeediShuttle Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/03/speedishuttle-update/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/03/speedishuttle-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
When Andou and I <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/07/a-guide-to-some-touristy-things-of-oahu.html">visited Hawaii last month</a>, we had arranged for SpeediShuttle to pick us up on the 7th of July. We waited until about an hour before our flight before we quit calling their unresponsive hotline for reasons why they hadn't shown up yet, and called a taxi instead.<br /><br />Well, last weekend we finally heard back from them -- more than seven weeks after we arranged from them to pick us up. It turns out that someone had taken in our information and mis-typed it, somehow taking our request for a July 7th pick-up and noting it as&nbsp;<i>Pick these people up on August 30th.</i><br /><i><br /></i>Though it was a stressful situation at the time, to be honest, after seven weeks it's hard to grasp at even a semblance of bitterness. Mistakes happen. Even so, the SpeediShuttle people we spoke to were very kind and offered us a refund, which was great! :) That at least pays for (most of) the taxi fare, haha.<br /><br />To be honest, the thing I'm most curious about now is how the mistake was made. No matter how I look at the keypad, it seems far-fetched to mis-type <i>8/30</i>&nbsp;instead of <i>7/7</i>...was the person who made the appointment maybe using an HTML-style form with drop-downs...even on drop-downs, "30" is pretty far from "7"...I mean, if someone's just inputting data into a computer, then maybe you could just have users fill in the data themselves, right? Rather than calling a human being to input pickup data for them, and then have no confirmation that the input data was correct?<br /><br />Furthermore, the fact that someone may miss their flight out when their system fails is a pretty serious consequence, one that may warrant at least one person manning their hotline at all times. Or if the hotline could at least take messages when no one's there?<br /><br />Shrug.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Guide to Some Touristy Things of O'ahu]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/27/a-guide-to-some-touristy-things-of-oahu/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/27/a-guide-to-some-touristy-things-of-oahu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I spent the week of the Fourth of July visiting Hawai'i for the first time. We went to the third-largest island, O'ahu, a.k.a "The Gathering Place," which is the island which has Hawai'i's capital, Honolulu. Our driver from the airport described&nbsp;Honolulu&nbsp;("place of shelter") as being named for the fact that the surrounding mountains shield it from bad weather.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-AYSJHDHXVR8/UBGx4mqJN9I/AAAAAAAAByk/Rgur-z3m9Qk/s1600/Oahu_(1).jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-AYSJHDHXVR8/UBGx4mqJN9I/AAAAAAAAByk/Rgur-z3m9Qk/s1600/Oahu_(1).jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">o'ahu (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oahu">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><a href="http://www.speedishuttle.com/pickup">SpeediShuttle</a>, which has a partnership with the airport, did a great job of taking us to the Seaside Hotel with a minimum of stress despite parades clotting up downtown Honolulu. We ended up paying around $50 for a round-trip, with the promise that we could call their 24-hour hotline at any time and get picked up and taken back to the airport when we needed to catch our departing flight. I wouldn't recommend paying in advance for the returning trip to the airport, because no one came to our 5am pickup or picked up the phone, and an hour and a half before our departure time we resorted to taking a cab back to HNL, which cost an extra $40. :( <b>Edit</b>: <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/09/speedishuttle-update.html">A SpeediShuttle update</a>.<br /><br />We stayed at the Seaside Hotel, which is one of the more modest places in Waikiki, but still well within reach of buslines and tourist fervor. Some online reviews indicated that it used to be "private" and reserved for airline employees. You can rent beach towels for the day, swim on a small rooftop pool, and lie on the bed wondering in vain why Discovery Channel broadcasts so many "[Storage/Property/X] Wars" shows nowadays. There was free Wi-Fi but we were never able to really connect to it successfully, and relied on the lobby computers for bus schedules instead. (To be honest, it was nice to be on a forced Internet break.)<br /><br />Something that our SpeediShuttle driver recommended we check out was a magazine called <i>101 Things to Do: Oahu, </i>which turned out to be a pretty good guide-slash-advertising booklet. This and other magazines can be picked up for free on most street corners, and contain coupons!<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-pCDMlZcsGHM/UBGy9wyDYUI/AAAAAAAABys/JP1iu7KtW_s/s1600/mag_oahu.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-pCDMlZcsGHM/UBGy9wyDYUI/AAAAAAAABys/JP1iu7KtW_s/s1600/mag_oahu.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">101 Things to Do: Oahu (<a href="http://www.101thingstodo.com/oahu/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><b>Monday</b><br />The first thing we did was go to Hanauma ("ha-now-ma") Bay&nbsp;Nature Preserve, which is essentially a really gorgeous bay historically used by Hawaiian royalty as their private fishing grounds.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nLxdMRmD1Go/UBK3NeXNEKI/AAAAAAAAB1Q/B5OjmJaBfCA/s1600/hanauma.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="194" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nLxdMRmD1Go/UBK3NeXNEKI/AAAAAAAAB1Q/B5OjmJaBfCA/s640/hanauma.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">iphone photos stitched together with <a href="http://hugin.sourceforge.net/">hugin</a></td></tr></tbody></table><br />Admission fee is $7.50. The coolest thing to do here is snorkel; the water is warm and colorful fish dart around pecking at the rocks. (Apparently turtles, sharks, and jellyfish sometimes drift through as well; and we definitely saw at least one pufferfish that had us flailing back to the shore in noob-like panic, haha.) You can rent snorkeling sets (goggles, snorkel breather thing, enormous awkward fins) for $15, or $18 if you want prescription goggles (which were worth it).<br /><br />Other wildlife to be spotted include Indian Mongooses, one of which I spotted sneaking around beach towels placed too close by shady foliage. Mongooses are invasive, and were <a href="http://www.instanthawaii.com/cgi-bin/hawaii?Animals.mongoose">introduced in the 1700s</a> to the islands to deal with rats eating up the sugarcane. (In the end, diurnal mongooses ended up snacking not on noctural rats, but on the eggs of endemic bird species. Whoops.)<br /><br />Hanauma is open all days except its Tuesday sabbath, and is accessible via the 22, which takes 40 minutes to an hour to get there from Waikiki. Because of the crowds, it's best to get there early and leave early, since afternoon buses come every half-hour and sometimes can't pick everyone up. (The 22 fills up with visitors from the Sea Life Park before accepting people from Hanauma.)<br /><br />The restaurants we visited that day were <a href="http://www.luluswaikiki.com/">Lulu</a>'s for breakfast, and Marukame Udon for lunch. Lulu's had great loco moco and macadamia coconut waffles (though the latter were quite syrup-drenched and sweet). Marukame ended up being our favorite restaurant the whole trip: the udon is freshly-made, cheap (at about $6 a bowl in <i>Waikiki, </i>where prices are tourist-high), and delicious. The tempura isn't bad either. :9<br /><br />The best times to go to Marukame are around 3 to 4; after that, it's dinner rush.<br /><br />Another place we visited throughout our trip was Tropical Dream Ice Cream, a hole-in-the-wall ice cream place right next to the Seaside Hotel. It served delicious ice cream with local ingredients, including but not limited to: mango, pineapple coconut sorbet, macadamia nut...<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mUPlgihczuQ/UBG77mScgjI/AAAAAAAABzg/YXF5ojUSGdU/s1600/DSC_0387.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="212" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-mUPlgihczuQ/UBG77mScgjI/AAAAAAAABzg/YXF5ojUSGdU/s320/DSC_0387.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">macadamia nut tastes great with john steinbeck</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><br /><b>Tuesday</b><br />We spent this day walking through downtown Honolulu to try loco moco at L&amp;L's, which is kind of like a Hawaiian McDonalds, except all the food comes on white styrofoam trays. (It was pretty good, though almost overly-filling. Then again, maybe we hadn't recovered from Marukame the previous day.)<br /><br />The main goal for the day was to visit the <a href="http://www1.honolulu.gov/parks/hbg/fbg.htm">Foster Botanical Garden</a>, one of the many botanical gardens on O'ahu. The guides at front said it would take about an hour to get through. We went a little fast, but still enjoyed the enormous "exceptional" trees, which included this absolutely enormous palm tree:<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ihpeylCI02o/UBG83kyBa6I/AAAAAAAABzo/ezRnj-zgRCo/s1600/DSC_0188.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ihpeylCI02o/UBG83kyBa6I/AAAAAAAABzo/ezRnj-zgRCo/s400/DSC_0188.jpg" width="265" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">you are so big!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Another cool tree is thorny, percussive&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Couroupita_guianensis">cannonball tree</a>&nbsp;(not pictured), and the striped rainbow eucalyptus (below).<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-LE6alCTs7_Q/UBG9tlOJcfI/AAAAAAAABzw/X9glRa9-t0Y/s1600/DSC_0231.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-LE6alCTs7_Q/UBG9tlOJcfI/AAAAAAAABzw/X9glRa9-t0Y/s400/DSC_0231.jpg" width="265" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">you are so colorful!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />We also visited the Waikiki Aquarium, which is fairly small but worth a visit if neon-colored fish are your thing. (The giftshop at Hanauma also offers a coupon for $1 off adult admission to the Waikiki Aquarium.) The most impressive part to me was the "enormous giant huge fish exhibit," in which various person-sized fish like the giant trevally circle around.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-aW1_5wo7c0I/UBG-eFgoBoI/AAAAAAAABz4/W4CKX6y4lb8/s1600/DSC_0290.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="424" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-aW1_5wo7c0I/UBG-eFgoBoI/AAAAAAAABz4/W4CKX6y4lb8/s640/DSC_0290.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">you are so, so big</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rZvwdi2nSBI/UBG-tQ7dt9I/AAAAAAAAB0A/3ezRp5M1c8E/s1600/DSC_0246.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="424" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rZvwdi2nSBI/UBG-tQ7dt9I/AAAAAAAAB0A/3ezRp5M1c8E/s640/DSC_0246.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">cue the children screaming "NEMOO"</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I think we also tried hiking up to Makapu'u on this day. It's reachable by taking the 22 or 23 to Sea Life Park and walking back and up along the highway. The trail is simple -- just an upward curve -- and at the top is a lookout point with a small lighthouse.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-VEB4LIe41Lg/UBK6Ah4VbJI/AAAAAAAAB1g/-U3M_YO2_h8/s1600/IMG_0058.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-VEB4LIe41Lg/UBK6Ah4VbJI/AAAAAAAAB1g/-U3M_YO2_h8/s320/IMG_0058.jpg" width="239" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the breeze was so strong and nice</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I liked the view back down almost better.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-N4QmospHtA8/UBK6JlJwFJI/AAAAAAAAB1o/EMa10Z6VgxY/s1600/IMG_0062.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="298" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-N4QmospHtA8/UBK6JlJwFJI/AAAAAAAAB1o/EMa10Z6VgxY/s400/IMG_0062.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">i can't remember the name of this mountain, though. diamondhead?</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><br /><b>Wednesday</b><br />On Wednesday we headed out super early to visit Eggs n Things, a restaurant in Waikiki where we had seen a pretty sizable line of people waiting at around 7am. Luckily, time zones made it easy for us to wake up and head out in time to avoid a 20+ minute wait, and the food (loco moco, and banana/macadamia nut french toast) turned out to be just as delicious as hoped. Eggs n Things also has their own triplet of syrups, flavored guava, pineapple, and coconut. They were so delicious I bought the coconut one to take home, only realizing later and with sorrow that one ingredient is <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/05/things-i-learned-from-extra-virginity.html">partially hydrogenated oil</a>.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-zwlxi_8jR5Y/UBK4Whmy1kI/AAAAAAAAB1Y/WcCeoqfRr-E/s1600/eggsnthings.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="213" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-zwlxi_8jR5Y/UBK4Whmy1kI/AAAAAAAAB1Y/WcCeoqfRr-E/s320/eggsnthings.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">loco moco &amp; fancy french toast at eggs n things</td></tr></tbody></table><br />It was the first Wednesday of the month, so we were intending to visit the <a href="http://honolulumuseum.org/">Honolulu Museum of Art</a>&nbsp;on their free day, but because it was also a holiday (July 4th), the museum was closed. We headed up to the <a href="http://www.bishopmuseum.org/">Bishop Museum</a> instead, which was great and had a variety of Hawaii-specific exhibits.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-11WaQ3u2RzA/UBK7EAn6k8I/AAAAAAAAB1w/6maYYjCEQxk/s1600/IMG_0064.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="239" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-11WaQ3u2RzA/UBK7EAn6k8I/AAAAAAAAB1w/6maYYjCEQxk/s320/IMG_0064.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">bishop museum courtyard</td></tr></tbody></table><br />A science building describes Hawaii's biological diversity and formation with wax volcano simulations, and other buildings contain many cultural and historical artifacts from the Asian immigrants who worked on the sugarcane plantations. We were also able to catch a show in the observatory that showed us where and how to spot Mercury and Venus in the night sky.<br /><br /><br /><b>Thursday</b><br />Thursday was our dedicated "North Shore" day. We caught early buses to Waimea Valley Adventure Park. It took two hours to get there, but the drive was quite scenic.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XwtNTeR3EZ0/UBHCZMLq1JI/AAAAAAAAB0k/9W3uds8VbCM/s1600/DSC_0328.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="424" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-XwtNTeR3EZ0/UBHCZMLq1JI/AAAAAAAAB0k/9W3uds8VbCM/s640/DSC_0328.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a beach near/in waimea valley</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Waimea stands for "red water," and I think refers to how the dirt is reddish with oxidation? (Citation needed.) Waimea Valley Adventure Park itself is a huge botanical garden which leads up to a freshwater waterfall where visitors can swim if rainfall hasn't made the area mudslide-hazardous.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Onw1lKavCIk/UBHDBT_1nAI/AAAAAAAAB0s/LQli7K3Ckg0/s1600/DSC_0352.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="424" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Onw1lKavCIk/UBHDBT_1nAI/AAAAAAAAB0s/LQli7K3Ckg0/s640/DSC_0352.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">waimea falls</td></tr></tbody></table><br />The falls are cold and 30 feet deep in areas, and floats are provided for people who aren't strong swimmers.<br /><br /><br /><b>Friday</b><br />Our last day in Hawaii was spent visiting Kailua. Kailua has the whitest, finest sand on O'ahu, but is also littered with little pinecones and needles. The day we went, strong wind turned the sand on the shore into fine little bullets, though underneath the waves it was velvet-soft. You can kayak here to a nearby rocky-looking island, but seeing as I can't get 20 feet from the shore without fearing I'll be swept into the Pacific Ocean, I was content watching people flail their oars around against the waves.<br /><br />Restaurant recommendation: Boots n Kimos, cash-only, which has very yummy pancakes drenched in macadamia nut cream.<br /><br /><br /><b>In Conclusion</b><br />O'ahu! It was great.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lavender Festival & Hurricane Ridge]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/26/lavender-festival-hurricane-ridge/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/07/26/lavender-festival-hurricane-ridge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Dyg-143_ADg/UBGIDKoN_0I/AAAAAAAABw8/i6UfFfiJkbI/s1600/DSC_0409s.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="424" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Dyg-143_ADg/UBGIDKoN_0I/AAAAAAAABw8/i6UfFfiJkbI/s640/DSC_0409s.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">purple haze farms</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">Last weekend I visited the <a href="http://www.lavenderfestival.com/">Sequim Lavender Festival</a>. Fun fact: Sequim is the only city in Western Washington that has an irrigation system. (At least, that's what the volunteer on our bus to Purple Haze Farms said. Even if it's not quite the <i>only</i>&nbsp;irrigation system presently, I guess the idea is that Sequim doesn't get as much water as surrounding areas.)</div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UCivtCbPjsE/UBGID9r-DFI/AAAAAAAABxE/NDxekZ0luQY/s1600/DSC_0414s.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="265" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UCivtCbPjsE/UBGID9r-DFI/AAAAAAAABxE/NDxekZ0luQY/s400/DSC_0414s.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">chicken statue and lavender</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">The Lavender Festival is fun and fragrant. You can tour farms and a broad and variety-filled street fair. The population of European-descended Americans is such that a lot of stuff plays on fairy myths (bottles of "fairy dust," beaded "fairy bells," hose-and-wire "fairy wings"), which I rarely see at other street fairs I attend in Seattle.&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lavender">Fun fact</a>: lavender is part of the mint family, has antiseptic and anti-inflammatory properties, and the price of a pound of it in Roman times was equivalent the price of fifty haircuts.</div><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">When I approached this next plant at Purple Haze, someone declared, "Teazle has been around since the time of the woolly mammoth!"&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dipsacus">Wikipedia</a>&nbsp;doesn't back this up, but does describe teazle as invasive in the United States and partially&nbsp;carnivorous.</div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nX85wss1rQw/UBGIB7Fug_I/AAAAAAAABw0/Baxxml7Q1M8/s1600/DSC_0400s.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="424" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-nX85wss1rQw/UBGIB7Fug_I/AAAAAAAABw0/Baxxml7Q1M8/s640/DSC_0400s.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">teazle/teasel/teazel, aka dipsacus</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">My proudest purchase was half a dozen sedums/phocuses/succulents/stonecrops/hens-n-chicks of various colors, whose specific species I can't recall or discover. (Maybe one's a&nbsp;<a href="http://www.sedumphotos.net/v/sedum-a/Sedum+album+rhodopaeum.jpg.html">Sedum album rhodopaeum</a>?) Fun fact: plants like this must remain outdoors, because their <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoma">stoma</a>, which is used in photosynthesis and respiration, use a drop in temperature as a signal to open up. So, sedums in an indoor environment with relatively stable temperature suffocate.)</div><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-L4fMrvyYzdM/UBGIEe_lKtI/AAAAAAAABxM/Op-YKXLclq0/s1600/DSC_0484s.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="265" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-L4fMrvyYzdM/UBGIEe_lKtI/AAAAAAAABxM/Op-YKXLclq0/s400/DSC_0484s.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">i can breathe!</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">My collection of relatively hard-to-kill plants (started with a pair of air plants I got at another street fair) is growing! (Haha?)</div><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-0EXBkb00L3U/UBGIF20LdmI/AAAAAAAABxU/3fgNWbAQgpQ/s1600/DSC_0485s.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="265" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-0EXBkb00L3U/UBGIF20LdmI/AAAAAAAABxU/3fgNWbAQgpQ/s400/DSC_0485s.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><br />Afterward we visited Hurricane Ridge. It costs $15 for a car to enter, but you have in-and-out privileges for about a week and can ascend some 5000 feet up and over the clouds.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Nh4BcvWDsDo/UBGR7Fn7rUI/AAAAAAAABx4/QotqpiOqiMc/s1600/DSC_0472s.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="424" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Nh4BcvWDsDo/UBGR7Fn7rUI/AAAAAAAABx4/QotqpiOqiMc/s640/DSC_0472s.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">whoa!</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br /></div><div>Fun fact: Hurricane Ridge is named for its "intense gales and winds," though all we had when we visited was sunshine and slight elevation sickness.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiny Tower & Randomly Generated Diversity]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/03/30/tiny-tower-randomly-generated-diversity/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/03/30/tiny-tower-randomly-generated-diversity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
After failing some months ago to see what was so special about it, I gave Tiny Tower another try and began to see what was so entertaining about it. &nbsp;I like that "leveling up" and the sense of progression is done via the number of floors you have in your tower, as well as the number of people that have been placed into their "dream jobs." &nbsp;Violet Perkins, for example, dresses like a pseudo-Viking and dreams of working in a bowling alley.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-SrEKOH14hkA/T2y5VwAx9VI/AAAAAAAAAsw/hKWjBneu0VM/s640/blogger-image--1909783493.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><img border="0" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-SrEKOH14hkA/T2y5VwAx9VI/AAAAAAAAAsw/hKWjBneu0VM/s640/blogger-image--1909783493.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">don't worry, violet! i got your back!</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><br />The thing I like the most about Tiny Tower are these randomly generated people -- specifically, their randomly generated complexions and genders and dreams. &nbsp;It's all random, but I can think of no other game with this variety of brown people, much less brown people with this variety of aspirations.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-UMs847sO_ks/T2y5VBFeasI/AAAAAAAAAsg/YuFGk1oinuU/s640/blogger-image--1045616008.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-UMs847sO_ks/T2y5VBFeasI/AAAAAAAAAsg/YuFGk1oinuU/s640/blogger-image--1045616008.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">he dreams of browsing forums<br />while sugar-coating deep-fried dough</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">Amanda Garrett is non-white, non-male (potentially?), and wants to work in a <i>Laboratory. &nbsp;</i>And she wears a hat!</div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i><br /></i></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-F9IdxDeFPFk/T2y5Wdt3qEI/AAAAAAAAAs4/j_t6-0G8C2g/s640/blogger-image-1593978126.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-F9IdxDeFPFk/T2y5Wdt3qEI/AAAAAAAAAs4/j_t6-0G8C2g/s640/blogger-image-1593978126.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">GOSH YOU ARE SO AWESOME</td></tr></tbody></table><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;">Yeah, yeah -- these little lives are admittedly shallow. &nbsp;Amanda Garrett is just one combination of random numbers. &nbsp;But, a character like Amanda Garrett appears rarely if ever in a video game. &nbsp;And if she was, it would be pretty likely that her pixeled body would probably be contorted to fit the <a href="http://www.your-critic.com/2011/06/gamers-gaze-part-1.html">gamer gaze</a>.</div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;">Lee Colman is another favorite bitizen of mine. &nbsp;I have imagined him into a friendly, loud-voiced, outgoing dude with a hat he never removes, with an inexplicable gift for blending fruit into flavors that soothe the body and mind. &nbsp;He halves and skins pineapples barehanded and closes up by faithfully polishing the blades of his processors, each a chef-caliber shuriken.</div><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-6XeCQLDHJWo/T2y5Vl6DzgI/AAAAAAAAAso/pNvXqMUcp34/s640/blogger-image-1585481038.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-6XeCQLDHJWo/T2y5Vl6DzgI/AAAAAAAAAso/pNvXqMUcp34/s640/blogger-image-1585481038.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">good ol' lee colman</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">Now if only I didn't feel so much like a druggie whenever I check my tower and make sure everything's stocked.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Off the Leash]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/03/21/off-leash/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/03/21/off-leash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
is the cutest dog-based tilt runner game that I've ever played, despite being a game in which it is difficult to play and get a screenshot which captures the excitement of running full tilt (ohoho) with a growing pack of thickly-lined canines. I only wish that there was a shiba inu, but then, I always wish this for everything, even things that don't necessarily include dogs in the first place.<br /><br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Mixvu6hl3zE/T2ovQKb4dkI/AAAAAAAAAr8/-lPWr3xePpg/s640/blogger-image-1447569057.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Mixvu6hl3zE/T2ovQKb4dkI/AAAAAAAAAr8/-lPWr3xePpg/s640/blogger-image-1447569057.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of "off the leash"</td></tr></tbody></table><br />It's free to play, with purchaseable items being more (non-shiba) dogs, power-ups, and even a permanent "2x coin bonus" thing for 99 cents. &nbsp;At some point I unlocked "Tiki Surf Hut Bonus Thing Level" and searched around for it in vain, only to realize that its appearance would be a semi-random in-game&nbsp;occurrence, not something that I could summon at will from the main menu. &nbsp;Was this an example of "verbal, unexpected, informational feedback" that is so beloved of games that hold high the ideal of <a href="http://chrishecker.com/Achievements_Considered_Harmful%3F">instrinsic motivation</a>? &nbsp;Or maybe just UI that wasn't clear enough in informing me that it would reward me with such a bonus level after collecting X amount of steaks and Y number of dalmations during play? &nbsp;The world may never know.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-O6CiUATBERg/T2y5EYdhSiI/AAAAAAAAAsY/EdzBFRxnA_A/s1600/blogger-image-1979466662.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-O6CiUATBERg/T2y5EYdhSiI/AAAAAAAAAsY/EdzBFRxnA_A/s320/blogger-image-1979466662.jpg" width="213" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the crash of 38 dogs</td></tr></tbody></table></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
