<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ui/ux | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/ui-slash-ux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T21:23:27-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Tumblr: Delightful UX]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/07/delightful-ux/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-07T14:39:07-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/07/delightful-ux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/delightful-ux.png" alt="Screenshot of delightful-ux.tumblr.com"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com">via</a>)</p>


<p>For whatever reason, <a href="http://tumblr.com">Tumblr</a> is becoming my social media site of choice, probably because its humor appeals to me so much. I also love that it supports people easily creating blogs that cater to specific topics &mdash; like <a href="http://medievalpoc.tumblr.com/">people of color in medieval art</a>, or <a href="http://moviecode.tumblr.com/">source code in TV and films</a>, or <a href="http://tabcloseddidntread.com/">intrusive pop-ups</a>.</p>

<p>Anyway, I&rsquo;ve made my own tumblr for gathering examples of <a href="http//delightful-ux.tumblr.com">delightful user experience</a>, which is my main interest when it comes to the wide world of human-centered design. Even though I love it, I&rsquo;m still muddy on what comprises a delightful user experience, and thus far have tossed in examples of <a href="http://adobe.breach.il.ly/#/about">useful websites with friendly wording</a>, as well as <a href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com/post/71660750263/hells-pizza-coffin-box-new-zealand-based-hell">pizza box designs with unnecessary but awesome utility</A>, and <a href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com/post/71681828062/australian-sharks-send-tweets-to-warn-swimmers">sharks with Twitter accounts</a>.</p>

<p>For now, when deciding whether to add an example, I ask myself, &ldquo;Could this Thing accomplish what it currently accomplishes, but in a more boring way?&rdquo; Or, &ldquo;Does this Thing solve for an action that is not-that-fun to do?&rdquo; And if the answer to either is &ldquo;yes!&rdquo; — lo, thusly do I deem it delightful.</p>

<p>I understand that second question might still catch Things that are not entirely playful — but I&rsquo;m not going to stress out about differentiating between design that&rsquo;s good and design that fulfills some nebulously defined good feel.</p>

<p>If you have encountered a good feel recently yourself, feel free to <a href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com/submit">submit</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cultural Differences Across Pokemon X & Y Websites]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s1600/pokemonxy.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s640/pokemonxy.jpg" width="510" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshots of the websites for Pokemon X &amp; Y<br />Japan (above), Netherlands (bottom)</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1">A couple weeks ago we analyzed the marketing sites for Pokemon X and Y across different countries. It turns out that all sites for Pokemon X and Y are the same — except for the one in Japan, which is shown at the top of the screenshot above.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">The differences between the Japanese site and the rest-of-the-world sites include:</div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><h4>Feature Descriptions</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain more information about the game, for example, direct links to features like the Pokemon Global Link; on the Japanese site, these are internal.</div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Hype</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites feature a large image carousel on their homepage, which shows other features of the game, all shown to excite:&nbsp;<i>Discover the Might of Mega-Evolved Pokemon! A New World of Amazing Pokemon!</i></div><div><i><br /></i></div><div>In contrast, the front page of the Japanese site merely says:&nbsp;<i>Pokemon, heading to a brand new dimension</i>! (Referring, I think, to the 3D?)</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Obvious Marketing</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain immediate links to buy the game, as well as the 3DS; the Japanese site does not. (According to Julius, the 2DS isn't even available in Japan, perhaps because "Everyone there already has a 3DS!")</div></div><div><h4><br /></h4><h4>JavaScript</h4><div>The Japanese site has very little Javascript, and each page looks to be straight HTML. Additionally, text is often baked straight into the images, rather than being left as straight text, which is often the case in websites due to accessibility issues. (Text on images cannot be easily parsed by screenreaders. Some users also prefer to render text on websites to be more readable, for example, through the excellent&nbsp;<a href="http://www.beelinereader.com/">BeeLine</a>&nbsp;app.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Description vs. Instruction</h4><div>The Japanese site is more descriptive of the story and characters of the game; the non-Japanese site is more instructive of how to play the Pokemon game.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div class="p1">We chalked up the majority of the differences the fact that Pokemon is more popular in Japan; Japanese game-players may not need to be particularly taught about Pokemon, or persuaded to buy it. But, this exercise makes me more interested in other facets of Japanese web design. Why is there so much baked-in text, why aren't there fancy hover menu states, why is the design so flat compared to the chrome and bevels of the non-Japanese sites? Is web accessibility less important in the Japanese corner of the internet, or is it handled in a way that's different in the US?</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">One final note: out class lecture that week was done by Kate Edwards, current Executive Director of IGDA, who shared some cool stories regarding the "culturization" problems she's encountered when helping to ship games across international borders. Something she noted was that, in the Netherlands, "adult" games don't need to be localized into Dutch because the adults there prefer to play the games in English. So, the fact that the Pokemon X and Y site text is all written in Dutch…</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><br /><div class="p1">…well…you can totally still enjoy the world of Kalos as a grown-up grad student with a full-time job. Just saying!</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delicious Bookmarklet UI]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/25/delicious-bookmarklet-ui/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/25/delicious-bookmarklet-ui</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="p1"><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-w1-3NA9zSXA/UkMSEAhleKI/AAAAAAAAELo/VeKHZG8pTwU/s1600/Screen+Shot+2013-09-25+at+Wed%252C+Sep25%252C+2013.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="430" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-w1-3NA9zSXA/UkMSEAhleKI/AAAAAAAAELo/VeKHZG8pTwU/s640/Screen+Shot+2013-09-25+at+Wed%252C+Sep25%252C+2013.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of bookmarklet "save" view</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I received <a href="http://www.delicious.com/">Delicious</a>' bookmarklet layout change today and it's a lot prettier — I wish I could compare it to the previous one — but for whatever reason I couldn't immediately tell where to input my tags. The light lines, the title <i>beneath </i>the input — it's weird — it's like the hospital or government forms that I always take two of whenever I need to fill one out, because I always put my address and phone number in the wrong box.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">This is the sort of impediment you feel only at first glance, maybe. I hitched for a couple minutes but now I get it. However, with the previous bookmarklet, I liked that "tags" was a huge box, and I could click anywhere within it to start input. Now I have to click either the invisible input box, or the light "tags" title. (Though I notice now that when you hover over tags, it does darken the input line somewhat.)<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-PY693rjnR4A/UkMR-Zp9rcI/AAAAAAAAELg/O7obxicF4GI/s1600/Screen+Shot+2013-09-25+at+Wed%252C+Sep25%252C+2013+1.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="566" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-PY693rjnR4A/UkMR-Zp9rcI/AAAAAAAAELg/O7obxicF4GI/s640/Screen+Shot+2013-09-25+at+Wed%252C+Sep25%252C+2013+1.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of bookmarklet "home" view</td></tr></tbody></table></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Another improvement to the bookmarklet: before, after saving a link to Delicious, the pop-up turned completely white and there was no indication that your link was saved successfully. This time, you see a small version of your Delicious homepage, with your newly-saved link at the top. This still doesn't give you feedback if you open the bookmarklet on an already-saved page and alter tags or comments, however.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">In other news, this review on <i><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/news/200648/Opinion_The_tragedy_of_Grand_Theft_Auto_V.php">Grand Theft Auto 5</a> </i>by Leigh Alexander is great.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lift App]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/26/lift-app/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/26/lift-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I tried using <a href="http://lift.do/">Lift</a> for a while. Having read <a href="http://zenhabits.net/sticky/">ZenHabit</a>'s encouragement that the way to start a habit is by just <em>starting</em>, even if it's a little bit at a time, I thought Lift would be a good (and pretty) way to keep myself accountable. I rearranged my iPod home screen, putting it on my front page's top row. I dutifully added three habits that I wanted to keep track of: getting exercise, writing, and more writing.<br /><br />Two things broke Lift for me.<br /><br /><strong>First — You can't go back to previous days to mark what habits you did, but didn't mark that day.</strong> Or maybe you can, and I just couldn't figure out how? In any case, I have an iPod — I'm not connected to the internet through it every day — and stressing myself out by making sure I log into Lift at least once a day is something I'm not willing or happy to burden my completionist personality with.<br /><br /><strong>Second — ultimately, Lift isn't meaningful enough to me.</strong> Though I'm working on getting both exercise and writing time, actually doing those things is the feel-good reward, and Lift doesn't add to these feelings in any interesting way. Even with Tiny Tower, logging in once a day to mindlessly tap things gives you, eventually, an impressive tower. All Lift could do for me was represent my taps as a series of colored bars and occasionally send some canned inspirational e-mails.<br /><br />On a side note, it is fun to read Lift's blog and see data compiled about people's <a href="http://blog.lift.do/post/40128965086/infographic-your-goals-in-2013">2013 goals</a>, or other ways that people are using <a href="http://blog.lift.do/post/42988396863/lift-tip-rewards-for-good-habits">extrinsic awards</a> to keep themselves sticking to habits that I think are easy to justify yourself out of, such as not staying late at work.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>nadine a.</div>
<div class='content'>
Yeah! It does make me wonder about the life cycle of this sort of app though. It seems to make itself obsolete by the success of its users (assuming success is defined by gaining intrinsic happiness). Then again, I suppose you could say that about a lot of things (like dating sites :P).</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
If you&#39;ve gotten started and now actually doing your habits is your reward, then I&#39;d say you probably don&#39;t need Lift at this point anyway. :)</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pinterest Thoughts]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/14/pinterest-thoughts/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/14/pinterest-thoughts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-nXd9sMOxHqU/UFJQ7rduSvI/AAAAAAAACgc/O4B38ms78ss/s1600/pinterest.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="354" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-nXd9sMOxHqU/UFJQ7rduSvI/AAAAAAAACgc/O4B38ms78ss/s640/pinterest.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of my pinterest page</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><br />At some point I thought Pinterest was The Greatest Thing, but&nbsp;then a week or two passed and I found it pretty forgettable. Compared to Tumblr, it's something that fell short of my "<a href="http://www.nirandfar.com/2012/09/habit-zone.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+NirAndFar+%28Nir+and+Far+Blog%29">habit zone</a>," maybe because I felt less of a community there, or because the cascading photos serve so much better the action of basking in the beauty of something for three seconds before moving onto the next Amazing Thing That I Want to Try (like <i><a href="http://www.17apart.com/2012/02/how-to-grow-green-onions-indefinitely.html">growing green onions indefinitely</a>, WHOA</i>. Though, apparently the onions only last about 3 or 4 more chops, and get pretty bland). Compare to Tumblr, where the single-column feed of media encourages you to stay, and to read, and to discuss, at least a <i>little</i>&nbsp;longer.<br /><br />Something that Pinterest has about Tumblr is the sense of organization -- my storage of links on Tumblr just gets larger and longer and harder to parse, especially with the overhead of adding tags (which may not match tags I already made, and which I might not have added at all, out of laziness). In contrast, organization in the form of boards is Pinterest's foundation, and it also very easily keeps tracks of images and their source links for you. It's also easy to skim even huge piles for what you want, or easy to just skim them with a smug sense of satisfaction at your gathered knowledge.<br /><br />Pinterest! The best way to visually organize cross-platform bookmarks in a way that makes you feel as productive as if you had actually been doing all the DIY things you're marking to do Later.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
