<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movie | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/movie/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T20:13:04-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Objectified]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/08/13/objectified/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/08/13/objectified</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HuIpXnHY_WM/UCKwdrpQ_QI/AAAAAAAAB8I/eG_d116_Jnk/s1600/objectified-poster-large.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HuIpXnHY_WM/UCKwdrpQ_QI/AAAAAAAAB8I/eG_d116_Jnk/s320/objectified-poster-large.jpg" width="216" /></a></div><br /><blockquote><i>Objectified is a feature-length documentary film examining the role of everyday non-living objects, and the people who design them, in our daily lives. The film is directed by Gary Hustwit. Objectified premiered at the South By Southwest Festival on March 14, 2009. </i><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Objectified" via="via" wikipedia="wikipedia">(via Wikipeda)</a></blockquote><br /><i>Objectified </i>has been languishing on my Netflix Instant Queue for the good part of a year or so. I finally watched it, and was glad! The film brings together a variety of designers from Across the World, who all talk about what they personally feel is Good Design. It's refreshing to watch designers talk so passionately about chairs and personal marks on the world and shaving away at the superfluous "fat" of a toothbrush design until they eliminate the concept of a toothbrush from oral health completely. It's amusing to see one designer swear that he's always "lived in the future," while another reaches into the past for <a href="http://davebmiller.wordpress.com/2010/06/10/spelunking-the-cell-phone/">a modern cellphone design inspired by childhood memories of peeling potatoes</a>.<br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><br />In the end, I was relieved when the movie moved from "NEW THINGS! Aren't they cool? <i>Buy all these new cool things!</i>" to "Do we <i>really</i>&nbsp;need new cool things? I mean, just <i>look</i>&nbsp;at all the things that we already have."<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-20cHlJOlVXQ/UCKyaABIJSI/AAAAAAAAB8Y/f2sKV-TU3qE/s1600/2184_4.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="358" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-20cHlJOlVXQ/UCKyaABIJSI/AAAAAAAAB8Y/f2sKV-TU3qE/s640/2184_4.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">just...look at them (<a href="http://www.blu-ray.com/movies/Objectified-Blu-ray/6861/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />The film points out the great problem of sustainability in product design, how it's not just about recycling/upcycling but how sustainability must guide design from before the beginning to beyond the end. <i>Why</i>&nbsp;are you designing this thing? What will it add to the world that doesn't already exist? And what will happen to the thing, when someone designs a new thing five seconds later?</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watched Brave the Other Day,]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/07/11/watched-brave-other-day/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/07/11/watched-brave-other-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
and was a little disappointed by it. (spoilers ahead)<br /><div><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-nDvl14uO4FA/T-fRrFCHmsI/AAAAAAAABNs/R09YmE54Mig/s1600/295px-Brave-Apple-Poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-nDvl14uO4FA/T-fRrFCHmsI/AAAAAAAABNs/R09YmE54Mig/s320/295px-Brave-Apple-Poster.jpg" width="216" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the art was gorgeous, though (<a href="http://pixar.wikia.com/Brave">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />The movie on the whole is beautiful, but the characters and story felt shallow and unfocused. Soon after the start of the movie, Merida describes her family and lifestyle, from the fact that her mother is controlling to the existence of her three younger brothers -- a huge contrast from introductory sequences a la WALL-E and Up, where you are given the chance to watch characters interact, learn what they do and what they love without anyone explaining it to you like a textbook.<br /><br />Throughout the movie there were little actions that I wish had had more background or more follow-through, more <i>meaning</i>&nbsp;in general.<br /><br />For example, when her mother gave her that necklace -- how important was it? Wouldn't it have felt so much more <i>painful</i> to watch Merida give that necklace away to the witch if you had known <i>anything</i><span style="background-color: white;">&nbsp;about it? If it was something her mother had inherited, something that stood for all the tradition and love that her mother was trying to give to her, which Merida then selfishly threw away?</span><br /><br /><span style="background-color: white;">And, why is it so important for Merida to be introduced as an amazing archer -- what purpose did her archery ever serve to the story? There's the competition scene, but her shooting in that case didn't make any difference to the fact she was still going to be married off. For the rest of the movie, whenever she shoots an arrow (like at that Big Evil Magic Bear) it </span><i style="background-color: white;">doesn't do anything</i><span style="background-color: white;">. Contrast to Katniss in The Hunger Games, whose proficient archery is used at all times to express her character: it's used in her illicit yet altruistic hunting activity, it's what she uses to defy the Capitol during her evaluation, it's what she uses to explode her enemies' supplies before she's ready to actually kill them, and it's what she uses when she does kill her first human being. In fact, at the end of Brave you saw Merida showing off more of her sword skills when she prevents her father from attacking her mother. So, why stress her archery?</span><br /><br />The movie also worked off some assumptions of marriage that I wish had been explained. Like -- why is Merida so <i>immediately</i>&nbsp;opposed to marriage? Why does marriage even need to happen in this story, other than the fact that it's "The Tradition"? At some point Merida's mother starts lecturing off this story about how Tradition is Important, but it still doesn't have any&nbsp;tie-in to why Merida has to be married, or why this is such an oppressive thing. I mean, her mother is doing okay, right? &nbsp;Her mother is shown to wield an incredible amount of respect among all the other men in the movie, walking among their brawls without a scratch, pacifying them with ear pinches.<br /><br />And the way this "I don't want to be married!" conflict ended made me cringe. Essentially, Merida confronts the other clan leaders and their sons and, with the blessing of her (pantomiming, bear-shaped) mother, declares "It's time for us to break away from tradition!"<br /><br />And the men go, "Hmm, okay!"<br /><br />It was just so....<i>aww, man</i>. Because, a<span style="background-color: white;">ssuming marriage is an institution of oppression towards women (which it's treated as during this movie), it's dissolved </span><i style="background-color: white;">way</i><span style="background-color: white;">&nbsp;too easily -- essentially by women (Merida, and her mother) deciding for themselves that they no longer want to be held beneath it.&nbsp;It reeks of the idea that people choose whether or not to be a victim -- as if this whole time, Merida and her mother had just been "oppressing themselves." Brave is a fictional children's movie, but the idea that "People can just get whatever they want if they just ask for it" is one that's very well-believed, and in the end I would have preferred to see Merida really <i>fight</i>&nbsp;to "change her fate," as the move's tagline stated, instead of "discover that the true power to succeed was within her all along," which is blatantly American Dream-y.</span><br /><br />Really <i>fight</i>&nbsp;someone else other than her mother, I mean, who was I guess is the only person in this movie&nbsp;not progressive enough to be okay with Merida not marrying.<br /><br /><span style="background-color: white;">Even if you don't want to think about it from a social justice-y standpoint, it's still mind-boggling why the problem Merida had in this movie was marriage. Merida's mother wanted marriage for the purposes of "keeping peace" between the clans; but the clan-leaders and their sons clearly didn't want marriage badly enough to argue when Merida proposed an alternative.</span><br /><br /><span style="background-color: white;">The last thing I want to mention: what was up with that magical warrior bear? I guess it was chasing Merida at the very beginning of the movie, and at the end, surrounded by people, was only interested in mauling <i>her? &nbsp;</i>&nbsp;The way that he dissolved into blue at the end seemed to imply that he had some relation to the will-o-the-wisps, but I don't get how Merida was important to him at all.</span><br /><br />That all being said, I guess I'm still looking forward to Pixar's <a href="http://www.themarysue.com/pixar-day-of-the-dead-movie/">next movie</a>.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cool Things I've Learned Watching the Blue Planet]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/09/05/cool-things-ive-learned-watching-blue/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/09/05/cool-things-ive-learned-watching-blue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Nowadays I get easily frustrated by movies.  The last straw was <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Picture_Perfect_(1997_film)">Picture Perfect</a>.  The main character, a woman, decides to focus on her career instead of on men, and succeeds in her work so drastically that her male boss is threatened by her, and passes her over for a promotion until she proves her "stability" to him be being in a relationship.<br /><br />Cool.  Thanks, romance movies.<br /><br />In any case, nowdays it's easier to stomach documentaries, particularly nature-related ones like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Blue_Planet">The Blue Planet</a>.  Which is amazing!  I can't even imagine how they could have gotten some of this footage.<br /><br />The following are things that blew my mind the most.<br /><br /><br /><h3>There is life on earth that does not depend on the sun.</h3><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9Mt-1cxO72w/TmURm86YtoI/AAAAAAAAAbQ/pNVUZ_bmbr8/s1600/deepseavolcano.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="488" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9Mt-1cxO72w/TmURm86YtoI/AAAAAAAAAbQ/pNVUZ_bmbr8/s640/deepseavolcano.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a colony beyond sunlight</td></tr></tbody></table><br />White crabs, fish, 2-meter long <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pompeii_worm">Pompei worms</a>, and hundreds of other species live near underwater volcanic vents, completely independent from the sun.  Their survival instead depends on bacteria that can derive sulfides from the vent, and are to these creatures what plants are to us.  Volcanic vents like these are also often only active for a couple decades or so.<br /><br /><br /><h3>Shearwater birds can dive down to a depth of several meters.</h3><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uEs0yq0SkPM/TmUPzv9nenI/AAAAAAAAAbA/Khxv6vVLvJc/s1600/dolphinsandbirds.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="478" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uEs0yq0SkPM/TmUPzv9nenI/AAAAAAAAAbA/Khxv6vVLvJc/s640/dolphinsandbirds.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">dolphins and shearwaters underwater</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I mean, puffins can dive as well but I guess I was just shocked to see birds and dolphins swimming and eating <em>together</em>.  In this part of the documentary, a school of mackerel were cornered from above by the shearwaters and from below by the dolphins, and then later were set upon by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yellowfin_tuna">yellowfin tuna</a> (i.e. albacore).<br /><br /><br /><h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firefly_squid">Firefly squid</a> have photophores not only on their tentacles, but over their entire body.</h3><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-F37c8zxsaOQ/TmUQ9RmhHQI/AAAAAAAAAbI/G4DNX-JI23k/s1600/fireflysquid.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="488" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-F37c8zxsaOQ/TmUQ9RmhHQI/AAAAAAAAAbI/G4DNX-JI23k/s640/fireflysquid.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">pretty!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />This was in the episode titled "The Deep" which in general was full of beautiful luminescent stuff, including <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_vM1KhgloUA">Sea Gooseberries</a>, which I saw for the first time at the Monterey Bay Aquarium.<br /><br /><br /><h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capelin">Capelin</a> fish lay their eggs on beaches.</h3><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xc2iwaQqZtU/TmUTyjIiANI/AAAAAAAAAbY/kZ3Fgwns7eU/s1600/fishfish.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="482" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xc2iwaQqZtU/TmUTyjIiANI/AAAAAAAAAbY/kZ3Fgwns7eU/s640/fishfish.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">omg so many of them</td></tr></tbody></table><br />At the end of June/early July, capelin beach themselves to lay and fertilize their eggs.  This is possibly because the eggs are safer from predation here than in the open water.  Eggs laid here may also develop faster.<br /><br /><br /><h3>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marine_Iguana">marine iguana</a> is the only lizard that can swim, and feeds on seaweed and algae.</h3><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VDCxpPe0NGU/TmUUVHIdvmI/AAAAAAAAAbg/904B0nrAqbU/s1600/iguana.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="482" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VDCxpPe0NGU/TmUUVHIdvmI/AAAAAAAAAbg/904B0nrAqbU/s640/iguana.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">ye. &nbsp;eat that algae</td></tr></tbody></table><br />In order to eat, it dashes down to rocks between strong breaker waves and eats the seaweed before dashing back up to safety again.  Or else it swims, though the documentary stated that only males can swim?  Weird.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
