<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movie Recs | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/movie-recs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-27T09:05:28-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Milennium Actress (千年女優)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/13/millenium-actress/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-13T14:58:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/13/millenium-actress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/millenium.jpg" alt="Millenium Actress poster"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millennium_Actress/">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>A movie studio is being torn down. TV interviewer Genya Tachibana has tracked down its most famous star, Chiyoko Fujiwara, who has been a recluse since she left acting some 30 years ago. Tachibana delivers a key to her, and it causes her to reflect on her career; as she's telling the story, Tachibana and Kyoji Ida, his long-suffering cameraman are drawn in. The key was given to her as a teenager by a painter and revolutionary that she helped to escape the police. She becomes an actress because it will make it possible to track him down, and she spends the next several decades acting out that search in various genres and eras. (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millennium_Actress">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>I watched <em>Millenium Actress</em> with A partly on a whim and partly because she started salivating the instant that she came across images of it online and remembered its existence. Reading about it on Wikipedia now, it looks like it&rsquo;s by Satoshi Kon, which would make it the first film of his that I&rsquo;ve seen. It&rsquo;s a beautiful film with all the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ichi-go_ichi-e">ichi go ichi e</a>&rdquo; atmospheres that I&rsquo;ve come to notice and love in Japanese stories since studying chadou one winter.</p>

<p>Why you should watch it:</p>

<ul>
<li>The animation is beautiful.</li>
<li>The story itself is crisp and well-written, super focused, with both moments that are hilarious and heart-clenchingly bittersweet.</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul>
<li>The main point of the story is that "the actress does everything in her life to reunite with the man she met once and fell in love with" — which isn't totally new and interesting on its own.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seattle Asian American Film Festival: To Manong Carlos, One Generation's Time, and Seeking Asian Female]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/10/saaff/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T09:24:04-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/10/saaff</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the kindness of R, I was able to attend the final day of the <a href="http://seattleaaff.org/2014/">Seattle Asian-American Film Festival</a>, an event whose existence I was only barely aware of before R invited me.</p>

<p>We had tickets to see two full documentaries and one short experimental film.</p>

<h2><em>One Generation’s Time: The Legacy Of Silme Domingo &amp; Gene Viernes</em> | <em>To Manong Carlos</em></h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/onegenerationstime.jpg" alt="Photographs of Silme Domingo and Gene Viernes, two Filipino-American activists"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://seattleaaff.org/2014/shorts-programs/one-generations-time-the-legacy-of-silme-domingo-gene-viernes-to-manong-carlos/">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>One short experimental film followed by documentary feature, <em>One Generation’s Time: The Legacy of Silme Domingo & Gene Viernes</em>.</blockquote>


<p><em>One Generation&rsquo;s Time</em> is about the work that Silme Domingo and Gene Viernes did to bring equal working conditions the Filipinos employed seasonally at Alaska canneries. In the 1970s, white workers had access to better food and better living situations than Filipinos doing the same work. Furthermore, on days with less work, rather than being allowed to rest, Filipinos were instructed to move empty cans from one side of warehouses just so they were paid for &ldquo;doing something.&rdquo; Silme and Gene were both murdered for their work, and the documentary discusses the political motivations of the murders, and how the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ferdinand_Marcos">Marcos dictatorship</a> was involved. The film was directed by Shannon Gee.</p>

<p><em>To Manong Carlos</em> is a short film directed by Adrian Arilla, about his experiences as a Filipino coming to live and call America his home.</p>

<p>Why you should watch these:</p>

<ul><li><em>One Generation's Time</em> introduces the complicated situation and political machinations of behind Silme and Gene's work well; probably because, as Shannon Gee said in a panel afterward, she herself was entirely new to this story.</li>
<li><em>To Manong Carlos</em> is a beautiful film where Arilla's experiences are interspersed with quotes from Carlos Bulosan's <em>America is in the Heart</em>. Reading these quotes alongside Arilla's modern experiences gives a special poignancy to Bulosan's "old" writings, which are still incredibly relevant today. In a media atmosphere where the stories of Filipinos are either rarely told or outright suffocated, it's moving to remember that we <em>do</em> have stories, that we have a history. We don't drift to America as "minority" individuals separate and small, but that we follow and build on the work and words that have come before us.</li>
</ul>




<h2><em>Seeking Asian Female</em></h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/seeking_asian_female.jpg" alt="Poster for Seeking Asian Female, depicting a white man and a Chinese woman in wedding attire, and the director of the documentary, a Chinese woman."/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.mrqe.com/movie_reviews/seeking-asian-female-m100102931">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote><em>seeking asian female</em> is an eccentric modern love story about Steven and Sandy—an aging white man with “yellow fever” who is obsessed with marrying any Asian woman, and the young Chinese bride he finds online. Debbie, a Chinese American filmmaker, documents and narrates with skepticism and humor, from the early stages of Steven’s search, through the moment Sandy steps foot in America for the first time, to a year into their precarious union. Global migration, Sino-American relations and the perennial battle of the sexes, weigh in on the fate of their marriage in this intensely captivating personal documentary. (<a href="http://www.seekingasianfemale.com/the-film/">Seeking Asian Female</a>)</blockquote>


<p>I&rsquo;ve been dying to see <em>Seeking Asian Female</em> since coming across <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3kbGrQe17cU">the trailer</a> a year or two ago. Watching it at the Seattle Asian-American Film Festival was particularly gratifying, as the entire theater was groaning and laughing every time a white person swooned about the &ldquo;servant girl&rdquo;-ishness and &ldquo;green papaya fragrance&rdquo; of the Asian women they saw (and smelled?) in their minds.</p>

<p>Why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>It's as hilarious as it is cringe-worthy. You cringe and laugh as you cringe.</li>
<li>The story is well told.</li>
<li>The director does a great job telling the story of Sandy, the "Asian Female" of this film, and also examines the ethics of herself being in the middle of this relationship.</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;m happy that something like the Seattle Asian-American Film Festival exists, and hope it continues next year. Watching both movies, I was reminded of N&rsquo;s quote at our last AB meeting: &ldquo;If we don&rsquo;t tell our stories, our stories tell us.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upstream Color]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/16/upstream-color/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/16/upstream-color</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-RI85LsClieI/UjesMLwjybI/AAAAAAAAECM/mTlTcUEZGQY/s1600/Upstream_Color_poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-RI85LsClieI/UjesMLwjybI/AAAAAAAAECM/mTlTcUEZGQY/s1600/Upstream_Color_poster.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Upstream_Color">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote>A man and woman are drawn together, entangled in the life cycle of an ageless organism. Identity becomes an illusion as they struggle to assemble the loose fragments of wrecked lives. (<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2084989/">via</a>)</blockquote><div class="p2">[spoilers]<br /><br /></div><div class="p1">A and I watched <i>Upstream Color </i>this weekend, per the recommendations of various friends and coworkers. As someone on Reddit stated, one great thing about it is that the director does not underestimate the intelligence of his audience. As a viewer, I felt as if I was running to keep up —pausing at one scene with just enough time to grasp at understanding — before rushing on to the next — the next — the next.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">A and I noted some scenes with awe at the "show, don't tell" attention to detail. For example, at some point, the female protagonist says to her love interest, "Let's buy a car," and the next scene shows them driving an old vehicle with the price still painted on the windshield. I found the first "hyponosis" scene awesome for its strangeness, and yet so disturbing that I couldn't bear to watch parts of the protagonist's violation.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">I loved that the medium so closely reflects the characters' mental state; the choppiness of the timeline mirrors the difficulty that I imagine they must have had trying to reconstruct their lives after having been so compromised. The story also explores some facets (symptoms?) of the hypnotic state that I enjoyed; for example, once the main characters start telling stories to each other, they begin accepting them as their own, and begin arguing about whose memories actually belong to whom.</div><br /><div class="p1"><i>Upstream Color </i>is great in its focus; it address the exploitation of hypnosis, and the repercussions of it on a human's brain. (Will the victims ever be okay again? What does "okay" even look like anymore?) <i>Upstream Color </i>requires an intellectual athleticism that leaves you a little sore by the end, in a way that's not unpleasant.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wolf Children Ame and Yuki]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolf_Children">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br /></div>(spoilers)<br /><br />I watched <em>Wolf Children: Ame and Yuki</em> the other day and was taken aback at how I pretty much had tears flowing continuously down my face, starting from the dam scene until the end of the movie . (What is it like to love someone and then see their body thrown into the back of a garbage truck? <em>Oh God</em>)<br /><br />It’s a story that I would be surprised to find in the US, because despite the fact that the title alludes to the wolf-shapeshifting children, the story is just as much about their mother, Hana, and her struggles to raise the children, aided only by her dead partner’s dwindling savings. She learns about natural birth to avoid going to hospitals; she fights off health inspectors; at some point her daughter accidentally ingests detergent and there’s an amusing scene of her rushing off into the night and then glancing desperately back and forth between a children’s hospital and a pet clinic.<br /><br />Though Hana misses her partner, at no point does she ever really find a replacement for him, or need another man at all. Even when she moves into the countryside, she receives assistance from the entire community there (though there is vaguely tsundere old man involved). Though her partner was a wolfman and is the reason why her children are also partially wolves, he just isn’t a part of the equation after he leaves. It sounds simple, but it’s such a relief that there are stories out there about women persevering, doing their own thing against all odds, and ultimately finding a place where they (and their children) can just be themselves.<br /><br />It’s also just a relief to see a woman who isn’t vilified for being a single mother, who isn’t ultimately viewed as lesser and unwhole for her lack of a man, who loses him and continues to move on with her life. Despite what much media would have you believe, without men, women keep existing and struggling towards their own goals.<br /><br />It's true that Hana’s motivations center almost entirely on the health of her children, which on its own isn’t terribly stereotype-breaking, but I appreciated how Hana didn’t lose her personality to become a faceless machine of a mother figure, a character wholly defined by her offspring’s emotions. Her bright attitude could have been unbelievable, but was acceptable to me because it is something established as a defining trait: "Even at my father’s funeral I laughed." And even so, it doesn’t mean she’s perfect: she often admits her ignorance (and remedies it thoroughly researching all her problems), she cries, she bandages her fingers, she panics, and rubs her back when it aches. You also get a glimpse of Hana's life as it was before motherhood, and a little "after," once her children have embarked <br /><br />And now that all of that is said — though <em>Wolf Children</em> impressed me with its focus on Hana as a single mother, after talking about this movie with Heather, I learned that the "virtuous mother" is actually a trope not uncommon in Eastern narratives. I haven't noticed it much, but will definitely be keeping an eye on it from now on.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rise of the Guardians: Wow, That Was Legit]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/12/30/rise-of-guardians-wow-that-was-legit/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/12/30/rise-of-guardians-wow-that-was-legit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-k4Q8cJLnfbs/UOAAmZRWtzI/AAAAAAAAC84/CnhV2QzqQnE/s1600/Rise_of_the_Guardians_poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-k4Q8cJLnfbs/UOAAmZRWtzI/AAAAAAAAC84/CnhV2QzqQnE/s320/Rise_of_the_Guardians_poster.jpg" width="205" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rise_of_the_Guardians">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />After a lot of hemming and hawing because of the fact that it scored "only" <a href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/rise_of_the_guardians_2012/">74% on Rotten Tomatoes</a>, I decided to drag Andou along to see it in theaters because I figured the animation was worth seeing at least once on a huge screen.<br /><br /><i>I really liked it, </i>much more than <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/11/wreck-it-ralph-pretty-cool-and-shiny.html">Wreck-It Ralph</a>, the other visually ebullient film that I can't help comparing it to.<br /><i><br /></i> <br /><h3>Things I Really Liked About RotG (with spoilers for both it and <i>Wreck-It Ralph</i> below):</h3><br /><ul><li><b>Jack's problem is clearly defined</b>:&nbsp;<i>I don't know why I'm here, and I want to be seen</i>. By the end of the film, Jack's character also undergoes a transformation to solve his problem:&nbsp;<i>My purpose is to share my love of "fun" with children, and now they believe in me. </i>In contrast, Ralph's "transformation" seemed weak and frustrating to me personally; at the beginning he is a character who longs for recognition and acceptance, and at the end becomes happy because he gets...recognition and acceptance. It's just a little boring. It's like a story about someone who says, "You know what I would like? $5." And then that someone meets a princess who gives him $5. The end!</li><li><b>The other primary characters interacted with Jack in ways that helped him with his transformation.</b>&nbsp;Santa teaches Jack the idea of a "center," or something that Jack is <i>all about,</i>&nbsp;which Jack realizes he doesn't know. Tooth teaches Jack that he was someone before he was Jack Frost, and later is an example of how the Guardians have become misaligned with their previous love of caring for children. Bunny is a sort of litmus test for Jack's familiarity with the Guardians, and the Sandman's death was what triggered Jack's supercoldblizzard power (or whatever). The antagonist, Pitch, was also a foil for Jack, representing the "bad side" of wanting to be seen and recognized so badly that you would want children to fear you. In contrast, the interactions between Ralph and characters like Felix and <strike>Jane Lynch</strike> Sergeant Tamora were pretty shallow, and after the Hero's Duty part of the movie, whenever you saw Tamora it was really just for romantic comedy fluff that had nothing to do with the movie's title character.</li><li><b>The Tooth Fairy had her own not-man-related things going on, </b>including but not limited to control of whatever the fairy army is called and a love of gummy, bloody teeth that was amusingly ridiculous. Compare to the Sergeant, whose motivation is hate for the bug-things because they killed her husband (in her fake memories). It's true that Tooth was fangirly about Jack's teeth and all of her fairy minions were swooning over Jack's hoarfrost bangs but I'll take what I can get.</li><li><b>No romance! </b>(Beyond that too-long hug at the end between Tooth and Jack?)&nbsp;Just, thank you for not stuffing that into the movie, especially since it was already bursting its seams with all the fast-paced kingdom-touring and gold particle effects. (On a related note, #rainbowsnowcone and #frostbite seem to be what the shippers are calling Frost/Tooth.)</li></ul><br />There were a couple plot holes in the movie that bothered me somewhat (Why did they only need to round up teeth for one night to save Tooth? After everyone fell asleep in Jamie's room, why were they suddenly in the sleigh, still-sleeping, later?) but I have been reading <i>Wired for Story</i>&nbsp;by Lisa Cron recently, and one of its tenets is that good stories are not about what just events that happen, but about the changes that happen in their characters. I'm not ready to forgive all plot holes for this reason, but it does give me a new lens into what details are the most important in story. In the case of these two movies, Jack's change from the invisible, meaningless delinquent into someone that uses his fun for good is what made him so much more compelling to me, and enjoyable to watch as well.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
