<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Anime Recs | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/anime-recs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-21T17:51:21-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Milennium Actress (千年女優)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/13/millenium-actress/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-13T14:58:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/13/millenium-actress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/millenium.jpg" alt="Millenium Actress poster"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millennium_Actress/">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>A movie studio is being torn down. TV interviewer Genya Tachibana has tracked down its most famous star, Chiyoko Fujiwara, who has been a recluse since she left acting some 30 years ago. Tachibana delivers a key to her, and it causes her to reflect on her career; as she's telling the story, Tachibana and Kyoji Ida, his long-suffering cameraman are drawn in. The key was given to her as a teenager by a painter and revolutionary that she helped to escape the police. She becomes an actress because it will make it possible to track him down, and she spends the next several decades acting out that search in various genres and eras. (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millennium_Actress">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>I watched <em>Millenium Actress</em> with A partly on a whim and partly because she started salivating the instant that she came across images of it online and remembered its existence. Reading about it on Wikipedia now, it looks like it&rsquo;s by Satoshi Kon, which would make it the first film of his that I&rsquo;ve seen. It&rsquo;s a beautiful film with all the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ichi-go_ichi-e">ichi go ichi e</a>&rdquo; atmospheres that I&rsquo;ve come to notice and love in Japanese stories since studying chadou one winter.</p>

<p>Why you should watch it:</p>

<ul>
<li>The animation is beautiful.</li>
<li>The story itself is crisp and well-written, super focused, with both moments that are hilarious and heart-clenchingly bittersweet.</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul>
<li>The main point of the story is that "the actress does everything in her life to reunite with the man she met once and fell in love with" — which isn't totally new and interesting on its own.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
