<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Board Games | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/board-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T09:11:38-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Played Small World and the Flavor Was Bittersweet]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/23/smallworld/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-23T09:37:48-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/23/smallworld</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/smallworld1.jpg" alt="Picture of Smallworld board, with 'Dragon Master Elves' at the front"/></p>

<p class="caption">dragon master elves?!</p>


<p>Last Friday we hit up a small pub table and inconspicuously played J&rsquo;s copy of Small World, <a href="http://www.daysofwonder.com/smallworld/en/">&ldquo;the fun, zany, light-hearted civilization board game!&rdquo;</a></p>

<blockquote>Designed by Philippe Keyaerts as a fantasy follow-up to his award-winning Vinci™, Small World is inhabited by a zany cast of characters such as dwarves, wizards, amazons, giants, orcs and even humans; who use their troops to occupy territory and conquer adjacent lands in order to push the other races off the face of the earth. (<a href="http://www.daysofwonder.com/smallworld/en/">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>This game has some disturbing colonialization themes aside; there are even pre-existing people in some territorites that you must conquer to inhabit that territory. Even so, I enjoyed this game so much that I eyed it hungrily at Card Kingdom after our party dispersed. The delicious flavor! The cool (albeit almost entirely white) characters! I love that the game naturally becomes different each time as you mix &ldquo;race powers&rdquo; and &ldquo;special powers;&rdquo; I love that the flavor of the game itself, its pictures and words, are delicious and meaningful and fly off the cardboard and became us — as in the terrifying era of K&rsquo;s Pillaging Skeletons, uprooting their femurs from mountain and farmland and laying waste across nests of Flying Trolls and Berserk Humans, resting for only a moment before rising again in greater number. <em>What</em>.</p>

<p>One weak part of the game, however, are the victory points. They are called gold; if you have the most of them at the end of the game, You Win. Flavor-wise, I don&rsquo;t feel like they entirely fit — when, during all this conquest, does gold arbitrary rise from the depths? — and there&rsquo;s also not much that you can do with them, other than occasionally exchange them to get the race you want. During the &ldquo;conquest&rdquo; phase, they are useless. What if instead you could use them to do something like increase your number of troops, and gamble to try and get more land? What if you needed to pay coins in order to roll for reinforcement, an action that is otherwise totally free and something you usually want to do? It seems like a missed opportunity for <a href="http://evolutionlive.blogspot.com/2010/03/flydrill-and-logistical-gameplay.html">logistical gameplay</a>, and allowing players the pleasure of &ldquo;not simply doing something, but doing it well — optimizing it to perfection.&rdquo;</p>

<p>A also noted that, though he felt he had made the right &ldquo;decisions,&rdquo; he still placed last in our group of four, and didn&rsquo;t grasp how he could have played the game better. He didn&rsquo;t feel that he had &ldquo;gained experience&rdquo; and learned how to play the game any better. Though I can&rsquo;t find it now, it reminds me of what I have read once regarding <a href="http://spryfox.com/our-games/tripletown/">Triple Town</a>, and how it seems to be a simple game until you make a mistake — <em>and then you get it</em>, you get what the game is about, you feel excited to give it another go.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/smallworld2.jpg" alt="Picture of Smallworld board, with a ton of stuff on it"/></p>

<p class="caption">smallworld board, getting all exciting as stuff accumulates</p>


<p>I hope to try out the expansions sometime, though the use of &ldquo;gypsy&rdquo; as a race in one of them is disconcerting, and reminds me of how uncomfortable the overall theme is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkham Horror]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/14/arkham-horror/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/14/arkham-horror</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Last Saturday I played Arkham Horror for the first time.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cjGeAWMrb4k/TxJ9LLf6SoI/AAAAAAAAAms/Mc31jp8yRtU/s1600/5512bbd839a111e1abb01231381b65e3_7.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cjGeAWMrb4k/TxJ9LLf6SoI/AAAAAAAAAms/Mc31jp8yRtU/s320/5512bbd839a111e1abb01231381b65e3_7.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="font-size: 13px;">i HAD to be the author</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I've heard that it's a good game so it won't be new to say that I enjoyed it. &nbsp;I don't usually play board games, though when I think back on my elementary school days I remember that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;ved=0CDcQFjAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2FSorry!_(game)&amp;ei=y30ST9KDJ6TfiALS59zADQ&amp;usg=AFQjCNEA1221dP1EPMUJc6DFyN_TNh2Z5g&amp;sig2=81dpv9-O-QF5NsBTfHcYPQ">Sorry!</a> and <a href="http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;ved=0CDIQFjAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2FMouse_Trap_(board_game)&amp;ei=s30ST8r4E-OjiQKjzoG7DQ&amp;usg=AFQjCNEagI_wcwiYKxMAIwenxQXTQy6W1A&amp;sig2=avE2_oH1q64NvDhdx6f9yg">Mouse Trap</a>&nbsp;and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uno_(card_game)">Uno</a> (which kinda counts, right?) took up the majority of my free time in Latchkey during the pre-Gameboy era. &nbsp;The most surprising thing about board games now, I have to say, is that the pieces are made of such sturdy material -- layers of cardboard with this very pleasant hard matte/muslin texture. &nbsp;Then again, maybe it's because this is a Grown Up's game.<br /><br />Things I liked about Arkham Horror:<br /><br /><ul><li>Flavor! &nbsp;The names of places, what you could do in those places, the characters and their abilities, the subtle things written on the cards which explained just enough to chill your mind without sounding cheesy. &nbsp;<i>You suddenly realize the purpose of the sharp instrument. &nbsp;Shuddering, you place it back. &nbsp;Lose one Sanity Point and gain one Clue Token.</i></li><li>Cooperation -- time has weakened my tolerance for competitive board games. &nbsp;Now I just love working together to achieve common goals.</li><li>Being able to change your character's stats every upkeep -- because it's nice to not be totally locked into a build.</li><li>The possibility of (fun) epic failure -- something that I think is way easier to accomplish in video games than in a board game. &nbsp;In video games, things can explode with flash and fluff when you miscalculate; in Arkham Horror, you've got the Ancient Ones and your imagination. &nbsp;And the fact that whatever Ancient One that awoke is now screwing everybody over immensely with negative buffs and Endless enemies.</li></ul><div><br /></div><div>In general, the game had just the right amount of complexity -- enough to keep you on your toes, not so much that you were glancing at the rulebook every time you wanted to do something (though we did reach for the rulebook a non-negligible number of times). &nbsp;</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
