<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Board Games | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/board-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T19:51:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkham Horror]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/14/arkham-horror/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/14/arkham-horror</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Last Saturday I played Arkham Horror for the first time.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cjGeAWMrb4k/TxJ9LLf6SoI/AAAAAAAAAms/Mc31jp8yRtU/s1600/5512bbd839a111e1abb01231381b65e3_7.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cjGeAWMrb4k/TxJ9LLf6SoI/AAAAAAAAAms/Mc31jp8yRtU/s320/5512bbd839a111e1abb01231381b65e3_7.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="font-size: 13px;">i HAD to be the author</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I've heard that it's a good game so it won't be new to say that I enjoyed it. &nbsp;I don't usually play board games, though when I think back on my elementary school days I remember that <a href="http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;ved=0CDcQFjAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2FSorry!_(game)&amp;ei=y30ST9KDJ6TfiALS59zADQ&amp;usg=AFQjCNEA1221dP1EPMUJc6DFyN_TNh2Z5g&amp;sig2=81dpv9-O-QF5NsBTfHcYPQ">Sorry!</a> and <a href="http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;ved=0CDIQFjAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fen.wikipedia.org%2Fwiki%2FMouse_Trap_(board_game)&amp;ei=s30ST8r4E-OjiQKjzoG7DQ&amp;usg=AFQjCNEagI_wcwiYKxMAIwenxQXTQy6W1A&amp;sig2=avE2_oH1q64NvDhdx6f9yg">Mouse Trap</a>&nbsp;and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uno_(card_game)">Uno</a> (which kinda counts, right?) took up the majority of my free time in Latchkey during the pre-Gameboy era. &nbsp;The most surprising thing about board games now, I have to say, is that the pieces are made of such sturdy material -- layers of cardboard with this very pleasant hard matte/muslin texture. &nbsp;Then again, maybe it's because this is a Grown Up's game.<br /><br />Things I liked about Arkham Horror:<br /><br /><ul><li>Flavor! &nbsp;The names of places, what you could do in those places, the characters and their abilities, the subtle things written on the cards which explained just enough to chill your mind without sounding cheesy. &nbsp;<i>You suddenly realize the purpose of the sharp instrument. &nbsp;Shuddering, you place it back. &nbsp;Lose one Sanity Point and gain one Clue Token.</i></li><li>Cooperation -- time has weakened my tolerance for competitive board games. &nbsp;Now I just love working together to achieve common goals.</li><li>Being able to change your character's stats every upkeep -- because it's nice to not be totally locked into a build.</li><li>The possibility of (fun) epic failure -- something that I think is way easier to accomplish in video games than in a board game. &nbsp;In video games, things can explode with flash and fluff when you miscalculate; in Arkham Horror, you've got the Ancient Ones and your imagination. &nbsp;And the fact that whatever Ancient One that awoke is now screwing everybody over immensely with negative buffs and Endless enemies.</li></ul><div><br /></div><div>In general, the game had just the right amount of complexity -- enough to keep you on your toes, not so much that you were glancing at the rulebook every time you wanted to do something (though we did reach for the rulebook a non-negligible number of times). &nbsp;</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
