<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Anime | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/anime/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-25T10:01:26-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Milennium Actress (千年女優)]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/13/millenium-actress/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-13T14:58:55-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/13/millenium-actress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/millenium.jpg" alt="Millenium Actress poster"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millennium_Actress/">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>A movie studio is being torn down. TV interviewer Genya Tachibana has tracked down its most famous star, Chiyoko Fujiwara, who has been a recluse since she left acting some 30 years ago. Tachibana delivers a key to her, and it causes her to reflect on her career; as she's telling the story, Tachibana and Kyoji Ida, his long-suffering cameraman are drawn in. The key was given to her as a teenager by a painter and revolutionary that she helped to escape the police. She becomes an actress because it will make it possible to track him down, and she spends the next several decades acting out that search in various genres and eras. (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millennium_Actress">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>I watched <em>Millenium Actress</em> with A partly on a whim and partly because she started salivating the instant that she came across images of it online and remembered its existence. Reading about it on Wikipedia now, it looks like it&rsquo;s by Satoshi Kon, which would make it the first film of his that I&rsquo;ve seen. It&rsquo;s a beautiful film with all the &ldquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ichi-go_ichi-e">ichi go ichi e</a>&rdquo; atmospheres that I&rsquo;ve come to notice and love in Japanese stories since studying chadou one winter.</p>

<p>Why you should watch it:</p>

<ul>
<li>The animation is beautiful.</li>
<li>The story itself is crisp and well-written, super focused, with both moments that are hilarious and heart-clenchingly bittersweet.</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul>
<li>The main point of the story is that "the actress does everything in her life to reunite with the man she met once and fell in love with" — which isn't totally new and interesting on its own.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wolf Children Ame and Yuki]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolf_Children">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br /></div>(spoilers)<br /><br />I watched <em>Wolf Children: Ame and Yuki</em> the other day and was taken aback at how I pretty much had tears flowing continuously down my face, starting from the dam scene until the end of the movie . (What is it like to love someone and then see their body thrown into the back of a garbage truck? <em>Oh God</em>)<br /><br />It’s a story that I would be surprised to find in the US, because despite the fact that the title alludes to the wolf-shapeshifting children, the story is just as much about their mother, Hana, and her struggles to raise the children, aided only by her dead partner’s dwindling savings. She learns about natural birth to avoid going to hospitals; she fights off health inspectors; at some point her daughter accidentally ingests detergent and there’s an amusing scene of her rushing off into the night and then glancing desperately back and forth between a children’s hospital and a pet clinic.<br /><br />Though Hana misses her partner, at no point does she ever really find a replacement for him, or need another man at all. Even when she moves into the countryside, she receives assistance from the entire community there (though there is vaguely tsundere old man involved). Though her partner was a wolfman and is the reason why her children are also partially wolves, he just isn’t a part of the equation after he leaves. It sounds simple, but it’s such a relief that there are stories out there about women persevering, doing their own thing against all odds, and ultimately finding a place where they (and their children) can just be themselves.<br /><br />It’s also just a relief to see a woman who isn’t vilified for being a single mother, who isn’t ultimately viewed as lesser and unwhole for her lack of a man, who loses him and continues to move on with her life. Despite what much media would have you believe, without men, women keep existing and struggling towards their own goals.<br /><br />It's true that Hana’s motivations center almost entirely on the health of her children, which on its own isn’t terribly stereotype-breaking, but I appreciated how Hana didn’t lose her personality to become a faceless machine of a mother figure, a character wholly defined by her offspring’s emotions. Her bright attitude could have been unbelievable, but was acceptable to me because it is something established as a defining trait: "Even at my father’s funeral I laughed." And even so, it doesn’t mean she’s perfect: she often admits her ignorance (and remedies it thoroughly researching all her problems), she cries, she bandages her fingers, she panics, and rubs her back when it aches. You also get a glimpse of Hana's life as it was before motherhood, and a little "after," once her children have embarked <br /><br />And now that all of that is said — though <em>Wolf Children</em> impressed me with its focus on Hana as a single mother, after talking about this movie with Heather, I learned that the "virtuous mother" is actually a trope not uncommon in Eastern narratives. I haven't noticed it much, but will definitely be keeping an eye on it from now on.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hotarubi No Mori E]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
One of my favorite manga short stories, <i>Hotarubi no Mori e</i>&nbsp;by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Yuki&nbsp;</a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Midorikawa</a>, was just made into an anime film! I&nbsp;cried after reading the story, and I cried after the&nbsp;animated film ended too. One would think that already&nbsp;knowing the ending would have removed the emotion from&nbsp;the film, but I guess not.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s1600/hotarubi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s400/hotarubi.jpg" width="282" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">tears everywhere, seriously (<a href="https://minniemeorange.wordpress.com/2012/03/04/anime-movie-review-hotarubi-no-mori-e/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />[spoilers ahead]<br /><br />I haven't read much manga recently, but what stories&nbsp;I've read from Midorikawa still remain glowing in my&nbsp;memory. She always takes a single, strange premise -- <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=11498">a criminal investigator that can make people do as he says</a>, <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=6781">a boy who inherits his grandmother's "book of names" of spirits</a> -- and uses story to cast light into the unique possibilities given by that premise, really stretches and shines it out to its full potential.<br /><i><br /></i><i>Hotarubi no&nbsp;</i><i>Mori e</i> in particular is my favorite of hers, because it's so wonderfully concise, whole, and  focused. A human and a spirit meet and become friends, despite a peculiar limitation: if the spirit ever encounters human touch, he will vanish from the world.<br /><br />Significant events and points of growth in the characters' relationship revolve around the problem of contact. When the two first meet, they carry a stick between them to hold hands. One day, when the human falls from a tree, the spirit races to catch her -- before pulling back at the last moment to let her crash. Afterward, she weeps -- "Never touch me, ever!" -- and those different facets of the premise sparkle to light. You understand it without the burden of over-narration; you understand simply, just as it happens. <i>He can't protect her. He can't even comfort her</i>. You watch her sob and sob and the spirit sits close by, face hidden by his mask.<br /><br />When people say that they just <i>had</i>&nbsp;to keep reading/watching/consuming because they want to see what will happen -- this story really dazed me with that desperation. The conflict seems so <i>impossible</i>&nbsp;-- you know what's going to happen, what <i>must</i>&nbsp;happen -- but does it? Is there any other way that this story could end?<br /><br />Do yourself a favor and find out! :)</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
Where can I find this? I would like to watch/read it!</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
