<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Anime | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/anime/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T20:33:57-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wolf Children Ame and Yuki]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolf_Children">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br /></div>(spoilers)<br /><br />I watched <em>Wolf Children: Ame and Yuki</em> the other day and was taken aback at how I pretty much had tears flowing continuously down my face, starting from the dam scene until the end of the movie . (What is it like to love someone and then see their body thrown into the back of a garbage truck? <em>Oh God</em>)<br /><br />It’s a story that I would be surprised to find in the US, because despite the fact that the title alludes to the wolf-shapeshifting children, the story is just as much about their mother, Hana, and her struggles to raise the children, aided only by her dead partner’s dwindling savings. She learns about natural birth to avoid going to hospitals; she fights off health inspectors; at some point her daughter accidentally ingests detergent and there’s an amusing scene of her rushing off into the night and then glancing desperately back and forth between a children’s hospital and a pet clinic.<br /><br />Though Hana misses her partner, at no point does she ever really find a replacement for him, or need another man at all. Even when she moves into the countryside, she receives assistance from the entire community there (though there is vaguely tsundere old man involved). Though her partner was a wolfman and is the reason why her children are also partially wolves, he just isn’t a part of the equation after he leaves. It sounds simple, but it’s such a relief that there are stories out there about women persevering, doing their own thing against all odds, and ultimately finding a place where they (and their children) can just be themselves.<br /><br />It’s also just a relief to see a woman who isn’t vilified for being a single mother, who isn’t ultimately viewed as lesser and unwhole for her lack of a man, who loses him and continues to move on with her life. Despite what much media would have you believe, without men, women keep existing and struggling towards their own goals.<br /><br />It's true that Hana’s motivations center almost entirely on the health of her children, which on its own isn’t terribly stereotype-breaking, but I appreciated how Hana didn’t lose her personality to become a faceless machine of a mother figure, a character wholly defined by her offspring’s emotions. Her bright attitude could have been unbelievable, but was acceptable to me because it is something established as a defining trait: "Even at my father’s funeral I laughed." And even so, it doesn’t mean she’s perfect: she often admits her ignorance (and remedies it thoroughly researching all her problems), she cries, she bandages her fingers, she panics, and rubs her back when it aches. You also get a glimpse of Hana's life as it was before motherhood, and a little "after," once her children have embarked <br /><br />And now that all of that is said — though <em>Wolf Children</em> impressed me with its focus on Hana as a single mother, after talking about this movie with Heather, I learned that the "virtuous mother" is actually a trope not uncommon in Eastern narratives. I haven't noticed it much, but will definitely be keeping an eye on it from now on.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sword Art Online: So Pretty]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/11/14/sword-art-online-so-pretty/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/11/14/sword-art-online-so-pretty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
So I found a gifset of Sword Art Online on Tumblr and decided that I wanted to watch it, because the art is pretty and also because the characters looked familiar, probably because Sword Art Online is one of the light novels I bought (and subsequently lost) some time ago.  <br /><br />Well, no matter!<br /><br />Sword Art Online (SAO) details the adventures of Kirito, who is one of ten thousand players trapped in the newly-released "virtual reality" MMORPG of the same name. The creator of SAO, who turns out to be some kind of eccentric psychopath, removes the "Log Out" button on the first day of open play and announces that everyone will have to reach and defeat Floor 100 in order to return back to the Real World. In the meantime, if you die in the game, you die in real life.<br /><br />I was excited because Kirito has bangs (my favorite ridiculous anime hair affectation) and spends the opening looking Dark and Tormented (my favorite ridiculous anime stereotype). Additionally, the "main" female character, Asuna, appears in the opening running around and doing things.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-SVwGKD2OF2Y/UKRq787wvXI/AAAAAAAACyY/FAquBkYgszk/s1600/sao.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="387" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-SVwGKD2OF2Y/UKRq787wvXI/AAAAAAAACyY/FAquBkYgszk/s640/sao.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">go, asuna, go! clear that low bar of agency!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />[spoilers ahead]<br /><br />Inevitably this first season was full of the same old tired female character stereotypes/storylines/actions, including but not limited to:<br /><br /><ul><li>female characters that basically act as pretty receptacles and mirrors for Kirito's feelings, for example:</li><ul><li>Silica, Dragon Tamer Girl: who appeared for one episode to be Kirito's "little sister," with bonus panicked upskirts</li><li>Lisbeth, Smith Girl: who appeared for one episode to be a love interest that is irrelevant after the one episode</li></ul><li>male characters not caring that female characters don't like them or want to be near them, for example:</li><ul><li>That one guy refuses to stop being Asuna's escort, and says he'll only leave her alone if Kirito wins against him a duel (what)</li><li>The leader of Asuna's guild, who, when Asuna tells him she wants to leave the guild, says she can only leave if Kirito wins against him in a duel (what)</li></ul><li>There's also a sub-plot that involves a woman who is murdered by her husband because, in the life-threatening situation of Sword Art Online, she stopped being "cute and obedient" and became instead a "lively and active" guild leader...<em>what?</em> It's obvious that this particular guy character is horrible, but I guess I'm bewildered by this story, which seemed to come out of nowhere, and didn't really serve to teach any characters about anything. Maybe if at the end Kirito had thought something like, <i>Wow, this really makes me appreciate Asuna's fighting skill more</i>...?</li></ul><br />The things that I <em>did</em> enjoy about this anime were the little game-related details, which take on a "private joke" feeling that I think was delightful and <em>not</em> uncomfortably blatant with fanfare and winking ("Hey! That was a game reference! Get it? Eh? <em>Ehhhh</em>?"). Characters gossip about other characters who have legendary status because their "HP bar has never fallen to yellow." At some point Kirito hits a wall in anger and the wall flashes with a notification -- <code>IMMORTAL OBJECT</code> -- indicating that it's inanimate and&nbsp;indestructible&nbsp; Best part: this little moment turns out to have plot significance later. Whoa! I <em>really</em> appreciate the meaningful subtlety.<br /><br />It's also fun to view what happens to characters as they become trapped in the digital world, though I wish it were explored more, perhaps in lieu of unnecessary female character fanservice. Some people commit suicide; some dedicate themselves to fighting on "the front lines" to free everyone; some people become merchants and smiths to support the fighters. One old man, thinking that he'd never get his real-life job back anyway, decides that he'll perfect in-game fishing.<br /><br />Inevitably Kirito and Asuna fall into a relationship, an unexpectedly intense and serious romance that involves them getting married (in-game) and living together in a cabin in the woods (on the game's Floor 22) and eventually meeting a girl that they "adopt" as their daughter (who later turns out to be a game process AI). Something that's refreshing about their relationship is the trust they have in each other -- Kirito&nbsp;occasionally&nbsp;hangs behind while Asuna fights, and at one point just smiles when someone tries to warn him to get his wife out of the way of a giant attacking fish. Though they were rarer than the opposite, I appreciated the parts where Kirito gave Asuna a place to stand on her own and defend and be appreciated for her actions and thoughts and talents, which weren't all Kirito-centered (for example, her&nbsp;experimentation&nbsp;with cooking and seeing which mixture of in-game loots and essences could make real-world flavors like soy sauce).<br /><br />Given the intensity of their dedication to each other (Kirito declares to Asuna that his entire self belongs to her; Asuna says that if Kirito dies, she'll commit suicide), it's uncomfortable and bewildering why the second season of SAO, which is still on-going, keeps pushing this love triangle forward between Kirito and his sister-who-is-actually-his-cousin. I mean, this isn't going to pan out, right? Is this just an excuse to keep having unrequited romantic (slash incestuous and forbidden) tension in the show to keep people watching? Is devoted love so boring? After all that the two characters have been through together, and after the show gives you so much reason to invest in the semi-doomed lovebank of Kirito/Asuna, it's hard to see this extra, new girl as anything but annoying fan service. <br /><br />Something else a little depressing is the impending descent of Asuna into a caged bird that doesn't do much but stare forlornly into space whenever her captor, a despised fiancé in a real-world arranged marriage who is keeping her unconscious and trapped in a new MMORPG, comes to threaten her warmly with sexual assault or erasure of her memories. In the most recent episode, Asuna sneakily watched him unlock the door to her cage, which made me assume hopefully that she would try to escape on her own. Unfortunately, she just collapsed on her knees and cried, "Save me, Kirito!"<br /><br />It's not that I blame her for her circumstances or think that she could fight her way out of it if she wanted...I just don't want her to become a full-on damsel in distress. :(<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-LxyJxHtHaZ4/UKRswdDNWJI/AAAAAAAACyg/8JOOm1RLdCk/s1600/sao2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="366" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-LxyJxHtHaZ4/UKRswdDNWJI/AAAAAAAACyg/8JOOm1RLdCk/s640/sao2.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">low bar of agency: not cleared (<a href="http://kimmygawa.tumblr.com/post/34445253622/weird-guy-that-smell-asunas-hair-made-her-cry">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Having met the end of the anime that's presently out, I've been devouring the light novels, where fanservice-y upskirts are not as prominent and where Asuna is more of an active character during the "fairy" arc, escaping and fighting and doing what she can. As a series the whole thing is&nbsp;<i>really </i>fun to watch -- it's&nbsp;beautiful, and really stretches, embroiders, and <i>uses</i> its theme of video game worlds and realities.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>cosbabyfive</div>
<div class='content'>
Asuna Yuuki is a heroine and the partner of Kirito in the Sword Art Online series. Her original avatar in <a href="http://www.cosplayfield.com/sword-art-online-alo-c-545_550.html" rel="nofollow">ALfheim Online</a>, was as Fairy Queen, Titania. She wore a white outfit, with a white long skirt, tube top showing her belly, along with a red ribbon that goes around the top part of her top that comes together to make a bow. She goes barefoot, and wears a white strip around her ankles! This <a href="http://www.cosplayfield.com/sao-alfheim-online-asuna-yuuki-cosplay-costume-p-523.html" rel="nofollow">Asuna Yuuki cosplay costume</a> looks like a long dress, and this is why I love it very much!</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hotarubi No Mori E]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
One of my favorite manga short stories, <i>Hotarubi no Mori e</i>&nbsp;by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Yuki&nbsp;</a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Midorikawa</a>, was just made into an anime film! I&nbsp;cried after reading the story, and I cried after the&nbsp;animated film ended too. One would think that already&nbsp;knowing the ending would have removed the emotion from&nbsp;the film, but I guess not.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s1600/hotarubi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s400/hotarubi.jpg" width="282" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">tears everywhere, seriously (<a href="https://minniemeorange.wordpress.com/2012/03/04/anime-movie-review-hotarubi-no-mori-e/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />[spoilers ahead]<br /><br />I haven't read much manga recently, but what stories&nbsp;I've read from Midorikawa still remain glowing in my&nbsp;memory. She always takes a single, strange premise -- <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=11498">a criminal investigator that can make people do as he says</a>, <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=6781">a boy who inherits his grandmother's "book of names" of spirits</a> -- and uses story to cast light into the unique possibilities given by that premise, really stretches and shines it out to its full potential.<br /><i><br /></i><i>Hotarubi no&nbsp;</i><i>Mori e</i> in particular is my favorite of hers, because it's so wonderfully concise, whole, and  focused. A human and a spirit meet and become friends, despite a peculiar limitation: if the spirit ever encounters human touch, he will vanish from the world.<br /><br />Significant events and points of growth in the characters' relationship revolve around the problem of contact. When the two first meet, they carry a stick between them to hold hands. One day, when the human falls from a tree, the spirit races to catch her -- before pulling back at the last moment to let her crash. Afterward, she weeps -- "Never touch me, ever!" -- and those different facets of the premise sparkle to light. You understand it without the burden of over-narration; you understand simply, just as it happens. <i>He can't protect her. He can't even comfort her</i>. You watch her sob and sob and the spirit sits close by, face hidden by his mask.<br /><br />When people say that they just <i>had</i>&nbsp;to keep reading/watching/consuming because they want to see what will happen -- this story really dazed me with that desperation. The conflict seems so <i>impossible</i>&nbsp;-- you know what's going to happen, what <i>must</i>&nbsp;happen -- but does it? Is there any other way that this story could end?<br /><br />Do yourself a favor and find out! :)</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
Where can I find this? I would like to watch/read it!</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
