<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Story | miscware]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/story/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-05T17:09:36-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nat]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lone Survivor & Meaningfulness]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/05/lone-survivor-meaningfulness/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/05/lone-survivor-meaningfulness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VLOhbqzGTUk/UBggO-tiRlI/AAAAAAAAB3g/4k3a6a5Q5kg/s1600/lonesurvivor.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VLOhbqzGTUk/UBggO-tiRlI/AAAAAAAAB3g/4k3a6a5Q5kg/s1600/lonesurvivor.jpg" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>0.</h2></div><div class="p1"><i>Lone Survivor </i>was the game I was most excited to obtain through a Humble Indie Bundle months ago, because the big grainy pixels looked so delicious, so fat with mood and atmosphere. And weirdness! And mysteriousness!</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Spoilers ahead.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>1.</h2></div><div class="p1">One of my favorite parts of adventure games is the characterization that rises through interaction with items. Do characters like a certain item, or dislike it? Does the item bring up deep heartbroken memories of the past? How do they parse and react, and what does their rumination say for who they are? I'm reminded of Nancy Drew's endearing enthusiasm for lifting up random objects ("This plastic DNA model will be useful!") and Phoenix Wright's skeptical amusement when things like puppies are added to his inventory.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">The most interesting item in the game for me was the toy cat, which I enjoyed petting all the time to accrue invisible "sanity" points. Engaging with the cat toy in particular puts you in the shoes and brain of the lone survivor himself, tinkering with a plush at the end of the world, just to have something light-hearted to do.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>2.</h2></div><div class="p1">Speaking of the cat plush, I loved the detail of this game — the unidentifiable flesh-like substances stretching across the wall — the way your map was dark unless you viewed it under sources of light — the specific food items like Delicious Ham, the creepy bottomless repositories of pills and Rotten Meats.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>3.</h2></div><div class="p1">A criticism of <i>Lone Survivor</i> seems to be that it was not scary enough. I played it at the height of summer and even then it was plenty terrifying, even if most of my stress and fear stemmed from being unable to hoard my bullets as obsessively as I would have liked.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Another scary part: putting your hand in that horrifying pink-red flesh-pixel hole. I <i>really </i>did not want to do that.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>4.</h2></div><div class="p1">The dream sequences were cool, and the characters therein intriguingly surreal, which I loved. Ultimately, however, I didn't feel that these scenes contributed to a larger understanding of what was going on, which was disappointing. Rather than deep, the first ending I received was vague, and a letdown. After carrying and caring for this dude I'd wanted a little more than a whiff of a broken heart. I wanted to know more about what this girl meant to the protagonist, how her departure left his life with zombie-filled corridors.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>5.</h2></div><div class="p1">I got my ending by playing as paragon as possible. I wanted to see if other endings would give me closure, so I found them on Youtube. Each one seemed vaguer than the last, and didn't interest me that much. I don't have a particular love of multiple endings and for me it's because they lack impact: I've only rarely encountered any set that comfortably resolves all issues and tension introduced in the game, and the way that such endings are reached never quite seems to match the decisions you made to get there.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">In the case of <i>Lone Survivor, </i>the decisions that you make add to an invisible calculator which eventually spits out one of these endings: for example, killing more monsters gives you endings that imply you're mentally unstable. But why? What is it about killing these things makes you this way? The worst ending can also be achieved not just by killing monsters, but "eating food when not hungry or hurt" and "sleeping for no reason" (per <a href="http://lonesurvivor.wikia.com/wiki/Endings">this wiki</a>). What's <i>that </i>connection?</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>6.</h2></div><div class="p1">This was my other favorite part: getting that white cat to come live with me. I guess it's strange to be saying that after my demands for meaningfulness, since other than the invisible points, hanging out with the cat doesn't reveal any more of the protagonist's inner story. But playing with the cat, I felt for the first time that I was doing something in the game that I personally wanted, like it was really <i>me</i> in there, and not me poking through things in a dude-shaped glove.<br /><br />Come here! Come <i>here</i>, little digital thing!<br /><br /></div><div class="p1"><i>come and be with me forever</i><br /><i><br /></i><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3tvhPIy5tDo/UilDcBOQcrI/AAAAAAAAEBc/f6aLd4GxHlk/s1600/Sunny.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3tvhPIy5tDo/UilDcBOQcrI/AAAAAAAAEBc/f6aLd4GxHlk/s1600/Sunny.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://lonesurvivor.wikia.com/wiki/Category:Characters">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><i><br /></i></div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wolf Children Ame and Yuki]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolf_Children">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br /></div>(spoilers)<br /><br />I watched <em>Wolf Children: Ame and Yuki</em> the other day and was taken aback at how I pretty much had tears flowing continuously down my face, starting from the dam scene until the end of the movie . (What is it like to love someone and then see their body thrown into the back of a garbage truck? <em>Oh God</em>)<br /><br />It’s a story that I would be surprised to find in the US, because despite the fact that the title alludes to the wolf-shapeshifting children, the story is just as much about their mother, Hana, and her struggles to raise the children, aided only by her dead partner’s dwindling savings. She learns about natural birth to avoid going to hospitals; she fights off health inspectors; at some point her daughter accidentally ingests detergent and there’s an amusing scene of her rushing off into the night and then glancing desperately back and forth between a children’s hospital and a pet clinic.<br /><br />Though Hana misses her partner, at no point does she ever really find a replacement for him, or need another man at all. Even when she moves into the countryside, she receives assistance from the entire community there (though there is vaguely tsundere old man involved). Though her partner was a wolfman and is the reason why her children are also partially wolves, he just isn’t a part of the equation after he leaves. It sounds simple, but it’s such a relief that there are stories out there about women persevering, doing their own thing against all odds, and ultimately finding a place where they (and their children) can just be themselves.<br /><br />It’s also just a relief to see a woman who isn’t vilified for being a single mother, who isn’t ultimately viewed as lesser and unwhole for her lack of a man, who loses him and continues to move on with her life. Despite what much media would have you believe, without men, women keep existing and struggling towards their own goals.<br /><br />It's true that Hana’s motivations center almost entirely on the health of her children, which on its own isn’t terribly stereotype-breaking, but I appreciated how Hana didn’t lose her personality to become a faceless machine of a mother figure, a character wholly defined by her offspring’s emotions. Her bright attitude could have been unbelievable, but was acceptable to me because it is something established as a defining trait: "Even at my father’s funeral I laughed." And even so, it doesn’t mean she’s perfect: she often admits her ignorance (and remedies it thoroughly researching all her problems), she cries, she bandages her fingers, she panics, and rubs her back when it aches. You also get a glimpse of Hana's life as it was before motherhood, and a little "after," once her children have embarked <br /><br />And now that all of that is said — though <em>Wolf Children</em> impressed me with its focus on Hana as a single mother, after talking about this movie with Heather, I learned that the "virtuous mother" is actually a trope not uncommon in Eastern narratives. I haven't noticed it much, but will definitely be keeping an eye on it from now on.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rise of the Guardians: Wow, That Was Legit]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/12/30/rise-of-guardians-wow-that-was-legit/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/12/30/rise-of-guardians-wow-that-was-legit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-k4Q8cJLnfbs/UOAAmZRWtzI/AAAAAAAAC84/CnhV2QzqQnE/s1600/Rise_of_the_Guardians_poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-k4Q8cJLnfbs/UOAAmZRWtzI/AAAAAAAAC84/CnhV2QzqQnE/s320/Rise_of_the_Guardians_poster.jpg" width="205" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rise_of_the_Guardians">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />After a lot of hemming and hawing because of the fact that it scored "only" <a href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/rise_of_the_guardians_2012/">74% on Rotten Tomatoes</a>, I decided to drag A along to see it in theaters because I figured the animation was worth seeing at least once on a huge screen.<br /><br /><i>I really liked it, </i>much more than <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/11/wreck-it-ralph-pretty-cool-and-shiny.html">Wreck-It Ralph</a>, the other visually ebullient film that I can't help comparing it to.<br /><i><br /></i> <br /><h3>Things I Really Liked About RotG (with spoilers for both it and <i>Wreck-It Ralph</i> below):</h3><br /><ul><li><b>Jack's problem is clearly defined</b>:&nbsp;<i>I don't know why I'm here, and I want to be seen</i>. By the end of the film, Jack's character also undergoes a transformation to solve his problem:&nbsp;<i>My purpose is to share my love of "fun" with children, and now they believe in me. </i>In contrast, Ralph's "transformation" seemed weak and frustrating to me personally; at the beginning he is a character who longs for recognition and acceptance, and at the end becomes happy because he gets...recognition and acceptance. It's just a little boring. It's like a story about someone who says, "You know what I would like? $5." And then that someone meets a princess who gives him $5. The end!</li><li><b>The other primary characters interacted with Jack in ways that helped him with his transformation.</b>&nbsp;Santa teaches Jack the idea of a "center," or something that Jack is <i>all about,</i>&nbsp;which Jack realizes he doesn't know. Tooth teaches Jack that he was someone before he was Jack Frost, and later is an example of how the Guardians have become misaligned with their previous love of caring for children. Bunny is a sort of litmus test for Jack's familiarity with the Guardians, and the Sandman's death was what triggered Jack's supercoldblizzard power (or whatever). The antagonist, Pitch, was also a foil for Jack, representing the "bad side" of wanting to be seen and recognized so badly that you would want children to fear you. In contrast, the interactions between Ralph and characters like Felix and <strike>Jane Lynch</strike> Sergeant Tamora were pretty shallow, and after the Hero's Duty part of the movie, whenever you saw Tamora it was really just for romantic comedy fluff that had nothing to do with the movie's title character.</li><li><b>The Tooth Fairy had her own not-man-related things going on, </b>including but not limited to control of whatever the fairy army is called and a love of gummy, bloody teeth that was amusingly ridiculous. Compare to the Sergeant, whose motivation is hate for the bug-things because they killed her husband (in her fake memories). It's true that Tooth was fangirly about Jack's teeth and all of her fairy minions were swooning over Jack's hoarfrost bangs but I'll take what I can get.</li><li><b>No romance! </b>(Beyond that too-long hug at the end between Tooth and Jack?)&nbsp;Just, thank you for not stuffing that into the movie, especially since it was already bursting its seams with all the fast-paced kingdom-touring and gold particle effects. (On a related note, #rainbowsnowcone and #frostbite seem to be what the shippers are calling Frost/Tooth.)</li></ul><br />There were a couple plot holes in the movie that bothered me somewhat (Why did they only need to round up teeth for one night to save Tooth? After everyone fell asleep in Jamie's room, why were they suddenly in the sleigh, still-sleeping, later?) but I have been reading <i>Wired for Story</i>&nbsp;by Lisa Cron recently, and one of its tenets is that good stories are not about what just events that happen, but about the changes that happen in their characters. I'm not ready to forgive all plot holes for this reason, but it does give me a new lens into what details are the most important in story. In the case of these two movies, Jack's change from the invisible, meaningless delinquent into someone that uses his fun for good is what made him so much more compelling to me, and enjoyable to watch as well.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Story in Trauma Team]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s1600/traumateam.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="163" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s320/traumateam.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.joystiq.com/2010/04/28/trauma-team-wii-review/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Time saved from <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/01/past-couple-days-in-series-of-instagram.html">not commuting during snowpacalypse</a>&nbsp;was spent playing Trauma Team, which I ordered (according to this hastily searched-up Amazon receipt) last March. &nbsp;(Spoilers ahead.)<br /><br />I adore the time-management micro-activities of Trauma Center, but was still surprised to find out how much I flat-out <i>enjoyed </i>Trauma Team. &nbsp;The fakey manga cutscenes re-used a lot of character art and implemented some tricks (scaling and translating a car, for example, instead of an actual animation of it driving off into the sunset), but I still enjoyed it much more than any dead-eyed mannequin gestures that seem to fill up so much of the cutscenes I've glanced in super-budget games nowadays (though to be completely honest, I haven't really sat down and played a lot of them).<br /><br />Cutscenes aside, Trauma Team did a good job of conveying story through its actual gameplay, some memorable scenes being:<br /><ol><li>The part in the mall where Maria, the "first response" character, has to take care of five dying patients on her own. &nbsp;I love getting perfect scores on these games and every time someone died I quit and started over in frustration. &nbsp;I even left the mini-game to try another story-line, and returned later with a feeling of dread -- only to realize that it was rigged. &nbsp;The patients were <i>supposed</i>&nbsp;to be near-death; once you rushed through at least one of them, back-up would arrive and restore everyone to full health, bringing a once-impossible situation to now a somewhat calming one (complete with soothing, <i>don't worry, your friends are here </i>music). &nbsp;For that moment, I really <i>was</i>&nbsp;Maria, and experiencing her prime character flaw of over-independence, of trying to do everything myself. &nbsp;(Until struck the inevitable Japanese group-focused armature of "Let's all work together!")</li><li>The part where Gabe is diagnosing the soldier, who is struggling to be-"bro" you in an attempt to make it seem you have having "<i>meaningless, friendly conversation</i>" when in reality you are in the process of diagnosing his viral hemorrhagic fever. &nbsp;In this case, the characters speaking to each other and working together were embedded in the "verbal questioning" mini-game, which was pretty elegant -- a lot more elegant than just clicking through conversation, though the mini-game itself probably lent itself to storytelling pretty easily.</li></ol><div>Sometimes you could just <i>see </i>the inconsistencies between Japanese thought and expectation of the US, and how it "really is." An easy example is when the characters were at the mall -- shopping for groceries, which is fairly typical in malls in Asia, and not so much here.<br /><br />Another example: unlike many US-developed games, this game set in America had a refreshing amount of ethnic diversity in the main character cast. &nbsp;Can you name a character who was a Mexican woman off the top of your head? &nbsp;One for whom it didn't really&nbsp;<i>matter</i>&nbsp;that she had dark skin, one who wasn't "stereotypically Mexican?" &nbsp;How about a character who is potentially Native American? The Mexican character was, unfortunately, the subject of many a boob-shot, and was also pretty frustratingly&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tsundere">tsundere</a>&nbsp;at times; and in general the females all had the same, petite facial structure. &nbsp;Personality-wise, though, they were all strong and interesting, with motives that 100% did not involve getting with the men around them. &nbsp;(Though there was a bit of Maria/That Dark Brooding guy near the end...before he went back to his lifestyle of alternating between doing surgeries and jail-time.)<br /><br />Some bonus fangirling: the best part of this game, hands-down, were Kimishima's cases. &nbsp;I <i>loved</i>&nbsp;piecing together the facts, figuring out how someone had died (though most of them were pretty straight-forward), learning about Kimishima's weird "I can hear the dead" cellphone and the fact that other characters accepted that she had such a device without complaint ("You and your voodoo cellphone..."). &nbsp;Gabe Cunningham's voice actor (apparently <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travis_Willingham">the same as for Roy in Full Metal Alchemist</a>) had <i>so much life</i>&nbsp;(the best part being when he sang "chunky~~" at the American politician). &nbsp;Also, Atlus's bold, colorful interfaces are so&nbsp;fun to interact with.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bridesmaids, and Stories With a Razor-sharp Focus and Relevant Characters]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/06/08/bridesmaids-and-stories-with-razor/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/06/08/bridesmaids-and-stories-with-razor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YUChNAAE1Qc/Te-9ugmFZVI/AAAAAAAAAQM/5ryyr5qIgk0/s1600/bridesmaidsposter.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YUChNAAE1Qc/Te-9ugmFZVI/AAAAAAAAAQM/5ryyr5qIgk0/s320/bridesmaidsposter.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://socialitelife.com/kristen-wiig-bridesmaids-movie-poster-promises-a-lot-01-2011">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />In (somewhat premature) celebration of making it through the Computer Science department and retaining our artsyness, yesterday <a href="http://www.imyjimmy.com/">Jimmy</a> and <a href="http://piriyuu.tumblr.com">Mari</a> and I went to Wann Izakaya for food and also saw <a href="http://socialitelife.com/kristen-wiig-bridesmaids-movie-poster-promises-a-lot-01-2011">Bridesmaids</a>, which Jimmy wanted to see because the director apparently studied the art of story under another story guy that Jimmy really admires.<br /><br /><span class="shh">Something like that...</span><br /><br />[spoilers ahead]<br /><br />The movie was pretty funny.  There were a ton of parts that were so awkward it was painful to watch (in a good way, I suppose).  I didn't mind to much while watching it, but afterward, talking about the story with Jimmy and Mari on the way home, it seemed to us that there was still a lot to be desired.<br /><br />Jimmy for one is a huge proponent of <a href="http://www.imyjimmy.com/post/3420065648/originality-vs-focus">focus in stories</a>, and thinks that every movie should have an <strong>armature</strong>, which is essentially "the moral of the story." The armature for The Godfather, for example, is that "Your family defines you."<br /><br />Throughout the entirety of Bridesmaids, the main character, Annie, appears to struggle with her negative outlook and lack self-confidence.  She's in a relationship with a clearly douche-y guy who doesn't care about her, she struggles with another character who appears to be stealing her best friend away, she ends up pushing away the people who <em>do</em> care about her because of her own pessimism.  Things begin to look up for her when she does decide to think positively, which occurs after her last, enormous mad outburst, and (apparently) due to one of her other "friends" tackling Annie on the couch and slapping her until Annie fought for herself.<br /><br />If you've been depressed and thinking negatively for months, Jimmy pointed out, thinking positively doesn't come easily.  It takes a little more than a fat woman to beat you up on your furniture to make you think positively.<br /><br />And once she does think positively, the solutions to all her problems just fell into her lap.  Sure, she attempted and seemed to fail at apologizing to her love interest after wronging him -- but that's only a small step out of the comfort zone that she's been hissing herself into the entire movie.  It's true that she never had to overcome anything greater than herself for the entire movie, but if doing so was so easy, why didn't it just happen fifteen minutes in?<br /><br />If a good movie should have focus, if every scene of it should mean something (much like how every sentence should mean something in <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2011/06/her-will-short-story-for-au-iii-legacy.html">a short story</a>), and a big theme, then this movie fell something short of "good." There seemed to be a lot of things that didn't really mean anything -- for instance, why was Annie a baker?  The majority of the things that she did in that movie were completely unrelated to baking, and she only ever baked anything in two scenes.  The first time that she baked something, it was after she met her love interest, and because he admitted he was a neighbor, I thought: Would she give it to her love interest?  But no: she just looked at it, then ate it.<br /><br />What is that supposed to mean?  Does she bake to try and calm herself?  If so, why doesn't she do it the other times that she panics during the movie?  Was she thinking about giving it to the love interest, and then was too afraid to do so?<br /><br />Why was it important for Annie to be a baker?  Was it just so that she could have a failed start-up, to show that she had ambition but had been broken by her failure?  If so, couldn't there have been a better way to do this, without giving her a completely superfluous label as "baker"?  Or, if she definitely is a baker, why wouldn't this show through in other aspects of her life?  She doesn't have recipe books.  She doesn't comment about the food that she eats.  She doesn't appear to have anything super baker-y in her room, which in a few shots is nice and elegant but completely lacking in description of the type of character that she is.  People's rooms can be the greatest indicator of what type of person they are -- clean, messy, cluttered -- my roommate's typography decorations and shelves of comic books speak differently than my wall of folded-up paper chopstick-covers and small shelve stuffed with PS2 games.  Mariko has a wire shelf of animu and Sakuracon badges.  Jimmy has a triplet of monitors for his computer, Molly's desk and windowsill is lined with classics and books about healthy eating.<br /><br />As Jimmy texted, a couple minutes ago: <em>Never have a batman movie that can also be a superman movie.  Character must be intrinsic to plot.  Annie could've been anything.</em><br /><br />Which means, really, that she wasn't anything.<br /><br />There were a lot of other unnecessary parts -- Annie's mother maybe finding a new partner at the end, two of the bridesmaids becoming completely irrelevant at the end of the movie, so on.  Anyway, it's a funny movie.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
