<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Story | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/story/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T20:13:04-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lone Survivor & Meaningfulness]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/09/05/lone-survivor-meaningfulness/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/09/05/lone-survivor-meaningfulness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VLOhbqzGTUk/UBggO-tiRlI/AAAAAAAAB3g/4k3a6a5Q5kg/s1600/lonesurvivor.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VLOhbqzGTUk/UBggO-tiRlI/AAAAAAAAB3g/4k3a6a5Q5kg/s1600/lonesurvivor.jpg" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>0.</h2></div><div class="p1"><i>Lone Survivor </i>was the game I was most excited to obtain through a Humble Indie Bundle months ago, because the big grainy pixels looked so delicious, so fat with mood and atmosphere. And weirdness! And mysteriousness!</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Spoilers ahead.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>1.</h2></div><div class="p1">One of my favorite parts of adventure games is the characterization that rises through interaction with items. Do characters like a certain item, or dislike it? Does the item bring up deep heartbroken memories of the past? How do they parse and react, and what does their rumination say for who they are? I'm reminded of Nancy Drew's endearing enthusiasm for lifting up random objects ("This plastic DNA model will be useful!") and Phoenix Wright's skeptical amusement when things like puppies are added to his inventory.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">The most interesting item in the game for me was the toy cat, which I enjoyed petting all the time to accrue invisible "sanity" points. Engaging with the cat toy in particular puts you in the shoes and brain of the lone survivor himself, tinkering with a plush at the end of the world, just to have something light-hearted to do.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>2.</h2></div><div class="p1">Speaking of the cat plush, I loved the detail of this game — the unidentifiable flesh-like substances stretching across the wall — the way your map was dark unless you viewed it under sources of light — the specific food items like Delicious Ham, the creepy bottomless repositories of pills and Rotten Meats.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>3.</h2></div><div class="p1">A criticism of <i>Lone Survivor</i> seems to be that it was not scary enough. I played it at the height of summer and even then it was plenty terrifying, even if most of my stress and fear stemmed from being unable to hoard my bullets as obsessively as I would have liked.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Another scary part: putting your hand in that horrifying pink-red flesh-pixel hole. I <i>really </i>did not want to do that.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>4.</h2></div><div class="p1">The dream sequences were cool, and the characters therein intriguingly surreal, which I loved. Ultimately, however, I didn't feel that these scenes contributed to a larger understanding of what was going on, which was disappointing. Rather than deep, the first ending I received was vague, and a letdown. After carrying and caring for this dude I'd wanted a little more than a whiff of a broken heart. I wanted to know more about what this girl meant to the protagonist, how her departure left his life with zombie-filled corridors.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>5.</h2></div><div class="p1">I got my ending by playing as paragon as possible. I wanted to see if other endings would give me closure, so I found them on Youtube. Each one seemed vaguer than the last, and didn't interest me that much. I don't have a particular love of multiple endings and for me it's because they lack impact: I've only rarely encountered any set that comfortably resolves all issues and tension introduced in the game, and the way that such endings are reached never quite seems to match the decisions you made to get there.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">In the case of <i>Lone Survivor, </i>the decisions that you make add to an invisible calculator which eventually spits out one of these endings: for example, killing more monsters gives you endings that imply you're mentally unstable. But why? What is it about killing these things makes you this way? The worst ending can also be achieved not just by killing monsters, but "eating food when not hungry or hurt" and "sleeping for no reason" (per <a href="http://lonesurvivor.wikia.com/wiki/Endings">this wiki</a>). What's <i>that </i>connection?</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>6.</h2></div><div class="p1">This was my other favorite part: getting that white cat to come live with me. I guess it's strange to be saying that after my demands for meaningfulness, since other than the invisible points, hanging out with the cat doesn't reveal any more of the protagonist's inner story. But playing with the cat, I felt for the first time that I was doing something in the game that I personally wanted, like it was really <i>me</i> in there, and not me poking through things in a dude-shaped glove.<br /><br />Come here! Come <i>here</i>, little digital thing!<br /><br /></div><div class="p1"><i>come and be with me forever</i><br /><i><br /></i><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3tvhPIy5tDo/UilDcBOQcrI/AAAAAAAAEBc/f6aLd4GxHlk/s1600/Sunny.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3tvhPIy5tDo/UilDcBOQcrI/AAAAAAAAEBc/f6aLd4GxHlk/s1600/Sunny.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://lonesurvivor.wikia.com/wiki/Category:Characters">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><i><br /></i></div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wolf Children Ame and Yuki]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/04/23/wolf-children-ame-and-yuki</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q0m6jPYOR0U/UXcmxeJsgFI/AAAAAAAADhQ/3DcTLZZuIS4/s1600/220px-O%CC%84kami_Kodomo_no_Ame_to_Yuki_poster.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolf_Children">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br /></div>(spoilers)<br /><br />I watched <em>Wolf Children: Ame and Yuki</em> the other day and was taken aback at how I pretty much had tears flowing continuously down my face, starting from the dam scene until the end of the movie . (What is it like to love someone and then see their body thrown into the back of a garbage truck? <em>Oh God</em>)<br /><br />It’s a story that I would be surprised to find in the US, because despite the fact that the title alludes to the wolf-shapeshifting children, the story is just as much about their mother, Hana, and her struggles to raise the children, aided only by her dead partner’s dwindling savings. She learns about natural birth to avoid going to hospitals; she fights off health inspectors; at some point her daughter accidentally ingests detergent and there’s an amusing scene of her rushing off into the night and then glancing desperately back and forth between a children’s hospital and a pet clinic.<br /><br />Though Hana misses her partner, at no point does she ever really find a replacement for him, or need another man at all. Even when she moves into the countryside, she receives assistance from the entire community there (though there is vaguely tsundere old man involved). Though her partner was a wolfman and is the reason why her children are also partially wolves, he just isn’t a part of the equation after he leaves. It sounds simple, but it’s such a relief that there are stories out there about women persevering, doing their own thing against all odds, and ultimately finding a place where they (and their children) can just be themselves.<br /><br />It’s also just a relief to see a woman who isn’t vilified for being a single mother, who isn’t ultimately viewed as lesser and unwhole for her lack of a man, who loses him and continues to move on with her life. Despite what much media would have you believe, without men, women keep existing and struggling towards their own goals.<br /><br />It's true that Hana’s motivations center almost entirely on the health of her children, which on its own isn’t terribly stereotype-breaking, but I appreciated how Hana didn’t lose her personality to become a faceless machine of a mother figure, a character wholly defined by her offspring’s emotions. Her bright attitude could have been unbelievable, but was acceptable to me because it is something established as a defining trait: "Even at my father’s funeral I laughed." And even so, it doesn’t mean she’s perfect: she often admits her ignorance (and remedies it thoroughly researching all her problems), she cries, she bandages her fingers, she panics, and rubs her back when it aches. You also get a glimpse of Hana's life as it was before motherhood, and a little "after," once her children have embarked <br /><br />And now that all of that is said — though <em>Wolf Children</em> impressed me with its focus on Hana as a single mother, after talking about this movie with Heather, I learned that the "virtuous mother" is actually a trope not uncommon in Eastern narratives. I haven't noticed it much, but will definitely be keeping an eye on it from now on.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bioshock Infinite & Forgiveness]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/04/22/bioshock-infinite-forgiveness/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/04/22/bioshock-infinite-forgiveness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9uZ6HN-IXTs/UXYTGzatClI/AAAAAAAADhA/KAfV2urg_hk/s1600/Bioshock-Infinite-Review1-620x350.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9uZ6HN-IXTs/UXYTGzatClI/AAAAAAAADhA/KAfV2urg_hk/s1600/Bioshock-Infinite-Review1-620x350.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.geekbinge.com/2013/04/18/bioshock-infinite-review/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><h2><br /></h2><h2>0.</h2>Bioshock Infinite spoilers ahead.<br /><br /><br /><h2>1.</h2>I finished <i>Bioshock Infinite</i> this weekend. I enjoyed it I guess. I play so few first-person shooters that I might as well go for the newest, most-polished one if I’m going to play anything while waiting (wistfully) for the next Metroid Prime. I have a penchant for headshots that seems to surprise people, but it is faster and cleaner and ultimately less squicky than melee in this game, which consists of scooping flesh from the faces of your opponents with a rotating hook-thingy. I saw the pink-red eye sockets of my first victim and felt ill and decided to go guns from then on, despite my usual powerful desire to greedily hoard any item I acquire in a game, including ammo.<br /><br /><br /><h2>2.</h2>The racism was also squicky. People seem to be very happy to engage in racism when it’s not real life, and defend its use as an edgy plot device. Ultimately I'm just exhausted by it, exhausted by black people apologizing to you over sudsy puddles, exhausted by Chinese people shouting for mercy in pidgin English before being disemboweled. I’m exhausted by the obsession of recreating racist worlds.<br /><br />In <i>Bioshock Infinite</i> you play as Booker Dewitt, and Booker doesn’t really care about racism one way or another. Oh, no, wait — I once ran into a black person who apologized for smoking in the back of a building, and Booker said something like, "Do what you want, I don’t care." That's Booker for you: except in combat, and except for the couple of times when he shouts after his sidekick, Elizabeth, Booker is cool as a cucumber. The setting of Columbia — the racism, the religion — slides off him like water off a duck's back.<br /><br /><br /><h2>3.</h2>Columbia (and its racism?) seems to be the system installed by its founder, a man named Comstock. Comstock later turns out to be you, which made something twist around in my stomach. <em>What?</em> How could Booker be Comstock? What in this story ever alluded to the idea that Booker could ever turn out to be Comstock? Booker is like a duck that’s been floating around in an indoor swimming pool, suddenly being told that with one little nudge he could have been the creator of that indoor swimming pool. Okay, not the best analogy, but look at him! He's a <em>duck</em>! How could he have gone from not caring about a black guy smoking in the back of a building, to someone who likens black people to dogs and says they should be thankful for the food and shelter given to them by their slavers?<br /><br /><br /><h2>4.</h2>There's really something to be said about how completely wonderful it feels when your brain finds patterns. I screamed with happiness when we ended up in Rapture again. I grabbed Andou's shoulder when Elizabeth looked over and said, "There's always a man, a city, and a lighthouse." My brain was like, <em>Hey, I know that! I thought that that beginning was all just homage, but it was on purpose! There's always a lighthouse!</em><br /><br />So that's what I wish I could pull in from an alternate dimension of game development: that Booker could have hesitated over racism — that he had had a chance to show that he could have been power-hungry, or obsessed with redemption, or obsessed with power enough to show how a the slightest nudge could have made him a Comstock monster. It would have been nice to see Booker reject his baptism and, when Elizabeth said there existed an alternate universe in which Booker accepted, to realize exactly what that meant. <br /><br /><br /><h2>5.</h2>Here was another fun part of the game's story: the first mention of quantum physics. Both Andou and I leaped and began to freak out. Oh my gosh, quantum physics. Quantum mechanics. Schrödinger's Cat. Is Columbia an epic experiment? Are we alive and dead?<br /><br />That paradox was so delicious that in some ways I wish that it had been everything, that somehow the setting could have abandoned its blaring, boring, meaningless racism and instead mused and ruminated on the significance or futility of our choices, and the consequences and not-consequences that bloom simultaneously after each. (Spare or kill? Bird or cage?)<br /><br />Booker already seems like a character set up perfectly for the agony of decision and regret: he kills Native Americans at Wounded Knee and seems to spiral downward from there, attempting (in one timeline) Christianity to clean away his presumed guilt. His room is cluttered with evidence of gambling, drinking. <em>Get the girl</em>, the game chants, <em>and wipe away the debt</em> — and imagine if Anna was some orphan he attempted to save, if she was a symbol of him trying desperately to do something good in his life, even if it meant the massacre of Columbia's peons.<br /><br /><br /><h2>6.</h2>Heck, the racism would have been way more interesting if it had been flavored with Booker's hypothetical thirst for forgiveness. Maybe the Booker that gets baptized can't deal with his being a murderer, and redefines people of color to be less than human to cope. Baptized Booker can't wait for his death to redeem him, so he takes heaven into his own hands, and decides who is saved and who is Sodom.<br /><br />As for the Booker that doesn't get baptized, maybe he encounters Anna on the way home, and uses her as his redemption instead. "I don't care how many people die," Booker could snarl at one point, "if it means that you are safe," if it means that his debts can be wiped away. Who are these Columbians anyway? Cult freaks — less than human.<br /><br />Ultimately both Bookers end up throwing away others for their own "Good." So how important was that baptism, in the end? How malleable is fate, after all is said and done?<br /><br /><br /><h2>7.</h2>There has to be room for Daisy Fitzeroy in this alternate dimension wish-fulfillment narrative as well, because I loved her before she was revealed to be an empty cliche of an Angry Black Woman. Maybe she could represent what it takes to forgive people who have transgressed against you, or what it takes to even decide whether or not people deserve to be forgiven.<br /><br />"Even you can be good again, Booker," Daisy might say if you made the right conversation choices. "Find forgiveness serving others." They can glance over at Elizabeth pointedly.<br /><br />"I'll have my debts forgiven, alright," Booker might mutter, still gruff.<br /><br /><br /><h2>8.</h2>All this forgiveness stuff could totally make Elizabeth's final standoff with her "mother" more impactful too. Maybe it could even tie in with Elizabeth's recurring issues with her supposed parents, her fury with them, how they "should" have been. How do Comstock and Booker try to protect her? How do their hopes and dreams live on through her, even when they die? Get it? Alive and dead at the same time? Eh? Ehhhh?<br /><br /><br /><h2>9.</h2>Yeah. A nugget of forgiveness would have been sick.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Delicious Rollback]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/02/24/the-delicious-rollback/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/02/24/the-delicious-rollback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Right now I am totally in love with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julietta_Suzuki">Suzuki Julietta</a>. She is the manga-ka of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kamisama_Kiss"><em>Kamisama Hajimemashita</em></a>, which recently got propelled in my mind to 5-star status after it started acquiring a time paradox, a plot device to which I am particularly weak. (How could she have planned that?! <em>Hoowww</em>?)<br /><br />Suzuki has a great grasp of storytelling and character development, something that I really appreciate in shoujo manga. Recently I described <a href="http://www.mangahere.com/manga/kamisama_hajimemashita/c065/">Chapter 65</a> (and 66) to Andou as an example. It goes like this:<br /><br />Nanami is making talismans for the shrine, so that visitors can come and get charms for things like "traffic safety," "love," "prosperous business." Tomoe sees them and goes, "Your handwriting is awful, let's make new talismans on the nice wood that I stored away." Nanami admits that she thought that wood was trash and threw it away and feels bad that she's disappointed him and hasn't made much headway in being a good god. Later that night, she notices Tomoe leaving and follows him mistakenly across some ethereal border and is almost smashed by a giant's foot. Tomoe saves her, and they wander around the night market searching for new talisman wood. Eventually Nanami separates from Tomoe and discovers two demons bullying a child, and when she tries to intervene, the two demons go for her instead. Wracking her brain for solutions, she eventually leads them beyond the ethereal border, where they are promptly smashed. They sneer that she will get stomped on too, but Nanami smiles and opens her coat to reveal: a talisman for traffic safety.<br /><br />There's just something <em>so delighful</em> about the story coming back full circle. In a sense you should have expected it — maybe you had the fun of figuring out yourself how Nanami could have made it out of her situation — even if you didn't, your brain lights up to realize the importance of something so seemingly insignificant. The final talisman also serves to answer her insecurities about being a bad god (even if her handwriting is bad, it <em>works!</em>), and as a bonus, makes Nanami to me a little more "real" — more of a person who is reacting to things in her environment, learning about them, using them.<br /><br />It's just <em>great</em>, and by no means an isolated formula. For example, in <a href="http://www.mangahere.com/manga/karakuri_odette/v01/c001/">the first chapter of Suzuki's other work, Karakuri Odette</a>, Odette begins attending high school, much to the hesitation of the school administrators. "Don't worry," says Odette's creator, "if she ever runs into problems, she'll emit a signal to me, and I'll pick her up right away." They agree and as Odette tries to learn more about what it means to be human, she asks her creator to make adjustments to her body: first, to add the ability to eat food, and second, to subtract from her robotic physical ability so she's only as strong as an average 15-year-old. Odette finds a new friend who is sickly and occasionally has seizures, and wanders around with her to a construction site, where both Odette and the girl fall into a well. Since she asked to be weakened, Odette can no longer climb out on her own — but then the girl starts to breathe desperately and beg for medicine — so Odette says, "Look away, don't look back until I say so," and when the girl turns away <em>Odette removes her head from her body</em> — which triggers the signal, and makes her creator come running.<br /><br /><em>So good!</em> There's just something utterly delicious of a small detail turning out to mean everything. This is something that I think is a challenge to do with games. When you pick up a key in level 1, for example, it's hard to imagine that it could be used to anything other than a treasure chest. (Though, knowing that, it would be fun to purposefully subvert this and make the key into an instrument for something else.)<br /><br />I've never played A Link to the Past, but apparently there's a great example of "small detail coming back to bite you" in it. It goes kind of like this: In one of the first towns you visit, there's a man who describes a nearby building as the old home of some evil bandit who for some reason couldn't stand the light. You play on, and on, and eventually, you return to the old home, and rescue the maiden in it, who begins to follow you around as you make your escape. At some point, you set a bomb off in a room, which collapses a ceiling and lets the light in — and when the maiden walks into it, she rips her skin off and become's the bandit. <em>The bandit, the dungeon's boss, has been following you this whole time! Whoa! Ahhh!</em><br /><br />Delicious.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rise of the Guardians: Wow, That Was Legit]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/12/30/rise-of-guardians-wow-that-was-legit/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/12/30/rise-of-guardians-wow-that-was-legit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-k4Q8cJLnfbs/UOAAmZRWtzI/AAAAAAAAC84/CnhV2QzqQnE/s1600/Rise_of_the_Guardians_poster.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-k4Q8cJLnfbs/UOAAmZRWtzI/AAAAAAAAC84/CnhV2QzqQnE/s320/Rise_of_the_Guardians_poster.jpg" width="205" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rise_of_the_Guardians">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />After a lot of hemming and hawing because of the fact that it scored "only" <a href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/rise_of_the_guardians_2012/">74% on Rotten Tomatoes</a>, I decided to drag Andou along to see it in theaters because I figured the animation was worth seeing at least once on a huge screen.<br /><br /><i>I really liked it, </i>much more than <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/11/wreck-it-ralph-pretty-cool-and-shiny.html">Wreck-It Ralph</a>, the other visually ebullient film that I can't help comparing it to.<br /><i><br /></i> <br /><h3>Things I Really Liked About RotG (with spoilers for both it and <i>Wreck-It Ralph</i> below):</h3><br /><ul><li><b>Jack's problem is clearly defined</b>:&nbsp;<i>I don't know why I'm here, and I want to be seen</i>. By the end of the film, Jack's character also undergoes a transformation to solve his problem:&nbsp;<i>My purpose is to share my love of "fun" with children, and now they believe in me. </i>In contrast, Ralph's "transformation" seemed weak and frustrating to me personally; at the beginning he is a character who longs for recognition and acceptance, and at the end becomes happy because he gets...recognition and acceptance. It's just a little boring. It's like a story about someone who says, "You know what I would like? $5." And then that someone meets a princess who gives him $5. The end!</li><li><b>The other primary characters interacted with Jack in ways that helped him with his transformation.</b>&nbsp;Santa teaches Jack the idea of a "center," or something that Jack is <i>all about,</i>&nbsp;which Jack realizes he doesn't know. Tooth teaches Jack that he was someone before he was Jack Frost, and later is an example of how the Guardians have become misaligned with their previous love of caring for children. Bunny is a sort of litmus test for Jack's familiarity with the Guardians, and the Sandman's death was what triggered Jack's supercoldblizzard power (or whatever). The antagonist, Pitch, was also a foil for Jack, representing the "bad side" of wanting to be seen and recognized so badly that you would want children to fear you. In contrast, the interactions between Ralph and characters like Felix and <strike>Jane Lynch</strike> Sergeant Tamora were pretty shallow, and after the Hero's Duty part of the movie, whenever you saw Tamora it was really just for romantic comedy fluff that had nothing to do with the movie's title character.</li><li><b>The Tooth Fairy had her own not-man-related things going on, </b>including but not limited to control of whatever the fairy army is called and a love of gummy, bloody teeth that was amusingly ridiculous. Compare to the Sergeant, whose motivation is hate for the bug-things because they killed her husband (in her fake memories). It's true that Tooth was fangirly about Jack's teeth and all of her fairy minions were swooning over Jack's hoarfrost bangs but I'll take what I can get.</li><li><b>No romance! </b>(Beyond that too-long hug at the end between Tooth and Jack?)&nbsp;Just, thank you for not stuffing that into the movie, especially since it was already bursting its seams with all the fast-paced kingdom-touring and gold particle effects. (On a related note, #rainbowsnowcone and #frostbite seem to be what the shippers are calling Frost/Tooth.)</li></ul><br />There were a couple plot holes in the movie that bothered me somewhat (Why did they only need to round up teeth for one night to save Tooth? After everyone fell asleep in Jamie's room, why were they suddenly in the sleigh, still-sleeping, later?) but I have been reading <i>Wired for Story</i>&nbsp;by Lisa Cron recently, and one of its tenets is that good stories are not about what just events that happen, but about the changes that happen in their characters. I'm not ready to forgive all plot holes for this reason, but it does give me a new lens into what details are the most important in story. In the case of these two movies, Jack's change from the invisible, meaningless delinquent into someone that uses his fun for good is what made him so much more compelling to me, and enjoyable to watch as well.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
