<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Pscs | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/pscs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-23T10:13:34-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[PSCS] Game Design Class 5: Sound and Music]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/06/pscs-game-design-class-5-sound-and/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/06/pscs-game-design-class-5-sound-and</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<i>This quarter I am facilitating a game design class at Puget Sound Community School for fun and lols. &nbsp;This is my story.</i><br /><br /><i>Other weeks can be found <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/search/label/pscs">here</a>.</i><br /><br />Last week's game was <a href="http://www.newgrounds.com/portal/view/587905">/ ESCAPE \</a>. &nbsp;It's a simple yet compelling game; you press the escape key to wall-jump, timing it right so you don't get&nbsp;electrocuted&nbsp;by spikes embedded by the walls or the huge laser approaching you from the bottom.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Y_rajI-3FEw/T0pxVu3Q9mI/AAAAAAAAArg/iUKjsetx2c4/s1600/escapescreen.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Y_rajI-3FEw/T0pxVu3Q9mI/AAAAAAAAArg/iUKjsetx2c4/s400/escapescreen.png" width="300" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of / ESCAPE \</td></tr></tbody></table><br />The students said they could feel a sense of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)">flow</a>, and that when they lost, it was in a way so brief and shameless that they found themselves launching right back into the game again without really feeling like they had ever "stopped" playing. &nbsp;The fact that the music continued to play on even after death contributed to this, and someone pointed out that the background music made them want to tap ESC to the beat, which was relevant, because the topic of the day was sound.<br /><br />I started with asking what games they felt had strong "sound design," whatever that means, and people listed off games like Metroid and Limbo for its sense of loneliness, Bioshock for its background music immersing you into its bygone pseudo-golden era. &nbsp;Andou supplied me with a particularly moving section of Limbo with which to show the class and everyone shuddered appreciatively.<br /><br /><br /><br /><center><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/i3wmQb7LWZc" width="560"></iframe></center><br /><br />Some applications of sound that I found presented on the internets, as well as some that we brainstormed:<br /><br /><ul><li>Sound can make you feel emotional -- sad, afraid, victorious</li><li>Sound can be used as positive or negative feedback -- <i>You did something right!</i> &nbsp;Or, <i>NO, STOP IT</i></li><li>Sound can be used to give NPCs life, i.e. when they look over at your character dashing by them in a loud rush</li><li>Sound can be used as a reward, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TgjHZa6Ag58">a la Zelda</a></li></ul>I also found and presented parts of&nbsp;<a href="http://cruiseelroy.net/2011/06/portal-2-music/">this very lovely breakdown</a>&nbsp;of what makes the music in Portal 2 so delightful and downright wonderful, which was good especially for me since I consider myself not extremely music-savvy, and I think would be hard-pressed at times to think about music and the effect that it's having on me and my psyche. &nbsp;Contrast with Andou, who at any given moment during a game or movie will remark something like, "Oh look, it's an intimate moment because romantic music is playing," and I'll realize that oh right, there <i>is</i>&nbsp;music playing.<br /><br />Following that article, I talked about encoded and embodied sounds, the ~*Universal Language*~ of music and how music in games, rather than speaking about the actions occurring <i>now</i>, may be more important in telling the player what will happen <i>next</i>: in the case of Limbo especially, blaring horns signal significant events, echoing splashes mean you're moving deeper into an enormous lonely world.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xpmvxtRvu9E/TzDJwo1gXCI/AAAAAAAAAo0/XXvw6iYdY3Q/s1600/wordloops.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="512" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xpmvxtRvu9E/TzDJwo1gXCI/AAAAAAAAAo0/XXvw6iYdY3Q/s640/wordloops.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a screenshot of wordloops</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I finished by showing them the game <a href="http://axcho.com/">Alex</a>&nbsp;programmed for the most recent Global Game Jam; something called <a href="http://axcho.com/wordloops">Wordloops</a>, based on this year's theme of "ouroboros."&nbsp;&nbsp;The idea is that you connect words together, starting the next word on the letter the previous word ended with, and after you fill certain criteria you "complete the loop" and proceed on to Loop N+1. &nbsp;Alex told me that it's much better to make loops of small words, since you're trying to get the most loops out of 3 minutes of play, but I personally found it really satisfying to make nice, long, wandering loops, and one of the students helped me see why: it's because when you type a letter, a sound plays, and that sound goes higher the more letters you play. &nbsp;It's the sound of <i>increasing</i>, <i>progressing,</i>&nbsp;<i>getting better</i>. &nbsp;And it's at odds with the idea that<i>&nbsp;the smaller loop is best</i>.<br /><br />Sounds!<br /><b><br /></b><br /><b>Sources</b><br /><ul><li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/2263/gdc_2005_report_what_makes_music_.php">Gamasutra: GDC 2005 Report: What Makes Music for Games 'Music For Games'</a></li><li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/2232/postcard_from_gdc_2005_gdc_mobile_.php">Gamasutra:&nbsp;Postcard From GDC 2005: GDC Mobile - Novel Ways to Use Audio in Games</a></li><li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/2189/enhancing_the_impact_of_music_in_.php">Gamasutra: Enhancing the Impact of Music in Drama-Oriented Games</a></li></ul></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[PSCS] Game Design Class 4: Winning, Hardcore vs Casual, and Gameplay Depth]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/30/pscs-game-design-class-week-4/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/30/pscs-game-design-class-week-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<i>This quarter I am facilitating a game design class at Puget Sound Community School for fun and lols. &nbsp;This is my story.</i><br /><br /><i>Other weeks can be found <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/search/label/pscs">here</a>.</i><br /><br />I'm a little belated with this post, if not just because I personally felt "meh" about it (which probably means that it might have been worse for the students themselves). &nbsp;Firstly, we critiqued Making Monkeys.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eyjfrSSrYVU/Tyd9DbYC5xI/AAAAAAAAAoc/HBrzqgLtUhs/s1600/makingmonkeys.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="460" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eyjfrSSrYVU/Tyd9DbYC5xI/AAAAAAAAAoc/HBrzqgLtUhs/s640/makingmonkeys.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of making monkeys, by <a href="http://greg-anims.com/">greg-anims</a></td></tr></tbody></table><br />The general consensus was that it was fun, unique, challenging. &nbsp;We pointed out the nice progression of the levels -- each one had something new to learn -- and talked about the types of rewards and goals in the design: the short-term win of the coffee cup, the long-term win of the entire game with your progress laid out visibly. &nbsp;The little narratives acted as both a silly reward for the previous level and a hint for the upcoming level. &nbsp;Some students found bugs but I didn't write any of them down, so they're Lost in Time and Space now.<br /><br />I couldn't think of a topic that I felt like discussing, so I chose <a href="http://onlyagame.typepad.com/only_a_game/2006/03/performance_met.html">this article</a> at random from a list of game design resources <a href="http://evolutionlive.blogspot.com/">Alex</a> gave me and just tried to talk about it, whiteboard and all. &nbsp;It was not too compelling and people were distracted, probably because "me talking" wasn't that intriguing.<br /><br />I switched topics then to the difference between "hardcore" and "casual" gaming, just to see what people thought of it (again referencing <a href="http://onlyagame.typepad.com/only_a_game/2007/08/game-literacy.html">another article from Only a Game</a>). &nbsp;Some of the students were adamant that the labels didn't mean anything, that "people just love games" and stereotypes seek to destroy the simple, human integrity of us all, to which I agree, kinda. &nbsp;I've always felt something snubby about declarations of <i>I'm a hardcore gamer </i>when all the game companies I've worked at have legitimate, game-loving audiences who can play just as much as any COD player, just doesn't relish the violence or complexity of it.<br /><br />An interesting term I learned in relation to the hardcore/casual duality was the idea of "game literacy;" that maybe an important delineation between hardcore and casual is not necessarily the time spent playing, or the motivations, but the breadth of game knowledge in general, and the ease with which one could pick up another game.<br /><br />Another idea was "game depth," and I tried to tie this together with ideas of winning and losing from earlier -- what happens in games when you "never really lose," but just have opportunities to achieve better, a la Angry Birds? &nbsp;What kind of decisions can you make in a game that is shallow, and one that has depth? &nbsp;How important are those decisions to the game itself? &nbsp;In Angry Birds, you can choose your angle and your velocity; in Tetris, your rotatation and speed; in a game like Magic, you can choose your deck, your strategy, your technique. &nbsp;It always seems like games with depth are "better," but I adore Limbo and concede that it's shallow gameplay-wise -- you solve the puzzles, you get to the end, that's it. &nbsp;I love story, but "Game" in its unique form is something that can be cooked and devoured a thousand times and still taste different the thousand and first.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[PSCS] Game Design Class 3: Rewards, Goals, and Motivation]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/23/pscs-game-design-class-week-3/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/23/pscs-game-design-class-week-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<i>This quarter I am facilitating a game design class at Puget Sound Community School for fun and lols. &nbsp;This is my story.</i><br /><br /><i>Other weeks can be found <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/search/label/pscs">here</a>.</i><br /><br />First thing last Tuesday was going over last week's assigned game, <a href="http://www.newgrounds.com/portal/view/586994">Pixel 2</a>, which has some marvelously colorful particle effects. &nbsp;Since we had talked a bit about <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/01/pscs-game-design-class-week-2.html">tutorials</a>&nbsp;in the past class, I had asked everybody to keep an eye on how Pixel 2 teaches you how to play the game, and it turns out it does so pretty bluntly.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Ypu35aRRuI0/Tx4n4pMgrUI/AAAAAAAAAnM/XCTY9HfIHbE/s1600/pixel2.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="468" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Ypu35aRRuI0/Tx4n4pMgrUI/AAAAAAAAAnM/XCTY9HfIHbE/s640/pixel2.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">pixel 2 tutorial screenshot</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Everyone agreed that the game was "pretty fun," mostly because it was very satisfying to collect the pixels, and people enjoyed the way that pixels were shot out at enemies anytime you collected pixels. &nbsp;We also discovered the "teleportation" aspect of the game, but were mixed about whether it added to the game or not. &nbsp;The player is moved around with the mouse, and can be held stationary with the space bar while the mouse moves the gun around, shooting at surrounding enemies; but if you release the space bar, the player will automatically "teleport" to the mouse's present position.<br /><br />I didn't get that far in the game due to lack of time and the fact that all the particles make my laptop run slowly, but the students also pointed out that some of the upgrades obtained in the game later are unlabeled, so their function is hard to remember.<br /><br />After that, we moved on to the topic for the day, which was reward systems. &nbsp;I referenced a lot of <a href="http://onlyagame.typepad.com/only_a_game/2005/08/designing_rewar.html">this overview on reward types</a>, though the students were able to name off some rewards easily: leveling up, getting money, getting new items, getting to explore new places. &nbsp;I talked about schedules for rewards, as well as what I felt was a pretty interesting point from that article:<br /><br /><blockquote>If you have ever wondered why games with poor game mechanics can still entertain players, it is perhaps because many poorly designed games are at least easy to play - and if they provide rewards according to a reliable schedule, they will entertain...it is the delivery of rewards, and not the quality of the game mechanics, which maintains a player's interest.</blockquote><br />Case in point: &nbsp;FarmVille, and other games nowadays like EA's Theme Park which rely on people optimizing for rewards (described with a fair amount of pessimism in <a href="http://insertcredit.com/2011/09/22/who-killed-videogames-a-ghost-story/">who killed video games?</a>).<br /><br />The next thing I talked about was how the rewards mentioned above were all extrinsic motivations, contrasted with intrinsic motivations, detailed wonderfully in <a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/dan_pink_on_motivation.html">this TEDTalk about "the surprising science of motivation"</a>:<br /><br /><br /><center><object height="374" width="526"> <param name="movie" value="http://video.ted.com/assets/player/swf/EmbedPlayer.swf"> </param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /> <param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always"/> <param name="wmode" value="transparent"> </param><param name="bgColor" value="#ffffff"> </param><param name="flashvars" value="vu=http://video.ted.com/talk/stream/2009G/Blank/DanielPink_2009G-320k.mp4&su=http://images.ted.com/images/ted/tedindex/embed-posters/DanielPink-2009G.embed_thumbnail.jpg&vw=512&vh=288&ap=0&ti=618&lang=&introDuration=15330&adDuration=4000&postAdDuration=830&adKeys=talk=dan_pink_on_motivation;year=2009;theme=the_creative_spark;theme=not_business_as_usual;event=TEDGlobal+2009;tag=Business;tag=Science;tag=brain;tag=creativity;tag=social+change;tag=work;&preAdTag=tconf.ted/embed;tile=1;sz=512x288;" /> <embed src="http://video.ted.com/assets/player/swf/EmbedPlayer.swf" pluginspace="http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" wmode="transparent" bgColor="#ffffff" width="526" height="374" allowFullScreen="true" allowScriptAccess="always" flashvars="vu=http://video.ted.com/talk/stream/2009G/Blank/DanielPink_2009G-320k.mp4&su=http://images.ted.com/images/ted/tedindex/embed-posters/DanielPink-2009G.embed_thumbnail.jpg&vw=512&vh=288&ap=0&ti=618&lang=&introDuration=15330&adDuration=4000&postAdDuration=830&adKeys=talk=dan_pink_on_motivation;year=2009;theme=the_creative_spark;theme=not_business_as_usual;event=TEDGlobal+2009;tag=Business;tag=Science;tag=brain;tag=creativity;tag=social+change;tag=work;&preAdTag=tconf.ted/embed;tile=1;sz=512x288;"></embed> </object></center><br /><br />As soon as I described the candle problem one of the students yelled, "What?! &nbsp;But that's easy!" right off the bat, so I guess it just goes to show you how they've already been brought up with fancy intrinsic motivations (or maybe it just proves that I shouldn't have drawn the box first, and then the tacks inside the box).<br /><br />Last topic was goals, the discussion of which I also referenced <a href="http://onlyagame.typepad.com/only_a_game/2007/05/process_without.html">Only a Game</a>&nbsp;as well as relevant HCI/UX points like <i>Show your player how far they've gotten! &nbsp;Show them all the things they've done! &nbsp;Short-term goals and long-term goals and transparent progress, yeah!</i><br /><br />With most topics I usually stop to let everyone try and see what video games may exhibit characteristics of whatever I'm talking about, which leads inevitably to fun tangential discussion about WoW, about achievements, about gamification and whether it works or not. &nbsp;The only unfortunate thing is that I haven't played most of the games that they have, since the only console I own that came out in the past seven years is the Wii. &nbsp;Even playing flash games stresses out the machines I own.<br /><br />Another thing I learned personally is this: even if the class is going to be mostly discussion and mostly me talking, even if there's no formal note-taking or tests, it's<i>&nbsp;good </i>to be writing stuff on the board. &nbsp;The moment I markered out "extrinsic" people looked up from their laptop screens. &nbsp;Hurray!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[PSCS] Game Design Class 2: Types of Players]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/14/pscs-game-design-class-week-2/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/14/pscs-game-design-class-week-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Last Tuesday was day two of the <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/search/label/pscs">game design class</a> I'm facilitating at <a href="http://pscs.org/">PSCS</a>. Having no experience teaching game design, it's mostly an experiment, an exercise in semi-public speaking, and a way for me to talk more about game design, which I really like.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Yc0bvPPVwkE/TxJ3WaiffmI/AAAAAAAAAmk/xQZlYahQ7zg/s1600/five5.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="322" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Yc0bvPPVwkE/TxJ3WaiffmI/AAAAAAAAAmk/xQZlYahQ7zg/s640/five5.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of <a href="http://www.newgrounds.com/portal/view/586264">five/5</a></td></tr></tbody></table><br />Last week I had the students watch <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XAoW9fjKmo4">Wolfire's design critique of World of Goo</a>, and then assigned everybody (including myself) to play ()<a href="http://www.newgrounds.com/portal/view/586264">Five/5</a>, a game we chose at random from the front page of Newgrounds. We were all going to return and talk about it, and these were the major points we came up with about the game:<br /><br /><ul><li>the graphics and sound are nice</li><li>the mechanic was fun to figure out and work with</li><li>except the part where the background patterns (varied, moving, and eye-catching) mislead you in thinking they're relevant, which they aren't, in that some of us were able to finish without giving them a second thought</li><li>and, there was also a pretty high uncertainty about whether the game was fundamentally buggy.</li></ul><br />Apparently, even after thinking they're uncovered the secret of the continuity mechanism, there were still times in which two pieces of perfectly-fitting-together map did not allow free passage between them. &nbsp;This suggests the game may have fared better with a little more feedback; that is, if it had somehow told you when you were doing things wrong (maybe by flashing that nice background), maybe you would be able to differentiate between when you were doing something wrong, or when you were doing something right and the game was messing up (unless the game was <i>really</i>&nbsp;buggy).<br /><br />The main idea I wanted to discuss this time was that you need to design for your players, so I also had them take the <a href="http://survey.ihobo.com/BrainHex/">Brainhex</a>&nbsp;questionnaire for funsies to see what type of gamer they were. &nbsp;Apparently this class is chock full of Mastermind/Conqueror/Achiever types, but someone pointed out quickly that they felt more like a Seeker, and we made a disassociation between identities and behaviors (i.e. it's more important to design for an "Achiever behavior" rather than "an Achiever person," since everyone may want different things at different times). &nbsp;We talked about AI difficulty and what types of behaviors it might please or not. &nbsp;For example, an AI in a racing game which slows down or speeds up depending on how well or poorly a player is doing would help a novice player because they wouldn't feel so strongly the sting of defeat. &nbsp;Someone with Conqueror behavior, however, who loves epic wins, would find an AI that sticks close to her back bumper frustrating -- she would only ever win by a hair. &nbsp;(I got this example from a website whose link I've misplaced, but I'll credit it soon.)<br /><br />I also talked about PhotoCity (of course!) and the unexpected behaviors that may occur from players. &nbsp;Our game meant for casual crowdsourcing, became instead a tool for the hardcore player way into 3d building reconstruction. &nbsp;The "playtest" took the game to a place way different than we expected! &nbsp;Whoa! &nbsp;See all the amazing things that can happen after playtesting?<br /><br />At some point I ran out of things to talk about and had some minutes left so I talked about tutorials, heavily referencing <a href="http://www.auntiepixelante.com/?p=465">this</a>&nbsp;cool article. &nbsp;I first asked what the students knew about tutorials and they explained they didn't have much need of them, since they already knew how to play games for the most part; when they got to a new one, they just clicked through.<br /><br />Me: "Well, there had to be a time when you <i>didn't</i>&nbsp;know how to play games already. &nbsp;What was the first game you played?"<br /><br />One of them: "I think...yeah, it was Grand Theft Auto 3."<br /><br />Oh...oh.<br /><br />"Haven't you guys ever played Mario?!"<br /><br />"A little," they admitted. &nbsp;"I haven't beaten it."<br /><br />I drew the first level of Mario on the board anyway and talked a little, and before I knew it, class was up.<br /><br />I still feel weird about this -- I feel simultaneously like there's not enough to talk about, or not enough interesting things to talk about which don't involve flashing lights and nice graphics, which is untrue. &nbsp;At the same time, rather than talk about articles and writing, I wish that I could teach them about paper prototyping, or really try and design a game out that they could program. &nbsp;But I guess an hour a week for nine weeks has its limitations, and it's good to start somewhere.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[PSCS] Game Design Class 1: Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/04/pscs-game-design-class-week-1/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/04/pscs-game-design-class-week-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Yesterday I facilitated my first class at the <a href="http://pscs.org/">Puget Sound Community School</a> (PSCS). The class is called "Make Games: Design," and is a companion to Alex's "Make Games: Programming," previous iterations of which <a href="http://evolutionlive.blogspot.com/2010/10/teaching-flixel.html">written about before</a>.<br /><br />There are four boys in the class. I had been hoping to intrigue some girls into it, and during my pitch before the school kept eyeing the ones in the front row.  <i>Yeah!  Girls can play games too!  Check it ouuutt!  </i>In retrospect, I realize that I might have erred in my pitch by not mentioning that our discussions will not center around the intricacies of triple-A titles these girls may have never heard of, much less played. Saying that might have made the class seem more accessible. As it was, the kids that joined my class were all those that had been huddled in the back of the room on their laptops.<br /><br />Which isn't a bad thing; it just makes me wince a little to see a group of laptop kids completely girl-less.  Then again, girls don't all have to like computers.<br /><br />Anyway, the class was off to a good start.  My four students are incredibly bright and eager to participate in a way that's refreshing and relieving -- after all, I've myself been a part of a wordless classroom a teacher is trying to engage.  After introductions, I asked what everyone's favorite games were, and why.  By the end, we had talked about Portal 2, WoW, Skyrim, Skyward Sword, The Darkness, and they all had good keywords to say about the games -- things like, <i>This game was good because of its goals -- because of its progression -- because there's always brand new content -- because of good feedback...</i><br /><br />And, inversely, <i>This game [Skyward Sword] was bad because they had this whole world you could explore, except not really because all you could find were these treasure chests you couldn't even interact with...</i><br /><i><br /></i><br />Something that I heard too often for my taste were things like <i>This game is just AWESOME!</i>  Somehow one of them had convinced me to watch <a href="http://www.youtube.com/embed/AtM3PGyiQUc">the trailer for Metal Gear Solid 5</a> and I watched them salivate with a sort of horror.  Really?  <em>Really?</em><br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8rlbB9C4rJk/TwvDScY1OII/AAAAAAAAAl8/dZI4u-KteLQ/s1600/mgs5.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="174" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-8rlbB9C4rJk/TwvDScY1OII/AAAAAAAAAl8/dZI4u-KteLQ/s320/mgs5.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">this silver-haired bishounen is holding up a freshly-extracted spinal column</td></tr></tbody></table><br />My head resonates with<i> </i>something that sounds disturbingly like <i>Kids these days!  </i>But I can't let my heavy cynicism and bitter boredom with big-budget graphics-intensive gaming get in the way of talking about core design.  Which, though I only have about 9 hours to do it over the course of the next 9 weeks, I definitely want to do -- and if at the end of it these people appreciate games not just for their diamond fluff, but <i>also </i>because they understand their design and creation, I'll consider this experiment in facilitating a success.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
