<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Heartrate Games | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/heartrate-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-10T08:28:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bunnies and Lozenges]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/04/18/bunnies-and-lozenges/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/04/18/bunnies-and-lozenges</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JW-pVscwaS0/Tayu5BUus6I/AAAAAAAAAME/uBGOdUevr-s/s1600/bunnyscreen.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="360" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JW-pVscwaS0/Tayu5BUus6I/AAAAAAAAAME/uBGOdUevr-s/s640/bunnyscreen.png" width="640" /></a></div><br />Exercise game, previously called "Bunnies and Monsters," is moving smoothly.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1OWMm4MSXiI/TaywZfKQcnI/AAAAAAAAAMM/oQBou52MVK8/s1600/monsterscreen.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="360" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1OWMm4MSXiI/TaywZfKQcnI/AAAAAAAAAMM/oQBou52MVK8/s640/monsterscreen.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Thanks for the lozenge, Teddy!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I believe to make the models Teddy used either Blender or Maya to create a .fbx file.  At first I tried to copy the downloaded .fbx model into one of the assets folders, and then tried to make a prefab, but for some reason there was a problem generating colliders; things fared better when I<br /><ol><li>Went to <strong>Assets &gt; Import Package...</strong> and found the .fbx file</li><li>Selected the imported model, then selected <strong>Generate Colliders</strong> in the <strong>FBXImporter</strong> tab of the Inspector</li><li>Created a new prefab, then dragged the model into it</li></ol></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[O the Places You'll Go]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/04/17/o-places-youll-go/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/04/17/o-places-youll-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KcWBOVnS9w0/TauiwPgs-KI/AAAAAAAAALs/IaAgb42rZqc/s1600/unityterrain.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="360" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-KcWBOVnS9w0/TauiwPgs-KI/AAAAAAAAALs/IaAgb42rZqc/s640/unityterrain.png" width="640" /></a></div><br />There's something really fun about making maps or 3d terrain.  I feel like I can see new stories rising at every line and edge.<br /><br />For our introductory game using the <a href="http://heartrategames.com/">HeartRate Games</a> API that I helped to create, we're building a really simple game involving bunnies and monsters (both arbitrarily chosen during brainstorming), where bunnies are things to be chased and monsters are things to be crushed at high velocity.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4WL8NEf6E0E/TaulAVabpXI/AAAAAAAAAL8/kSWXBjWDzw4/s1600/DSC_0375.JPG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="426" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4WL8NEf6E0E/TaulAVabpXI/AAAAAAAAAL8/kSWXBjWDzw4/s640/DSC_0375.JPG" width="640" /></a></div><br />To learn Unity in the first place, Mari and I read through <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Unity-Game-Development-Essentials-Goldstone/dp/184719818X">Unity Game Development Essentials</a>, which was a pretty good primer, though it's hard for me to remember some of the tutorials now that I'm trying to work through things on my own.  I think that's more a fault of the fact that I've never done game development, really, much less much manipulation of 3d objects.  In our Computer Graphics class it was all C++, compile, see if your shadows rendered properly, change stuff, compile again.<br /><br />Anyway, the basics I know of Unity should be enough to implement a basic skeleton of a game, more as a proof of concept than anything polished and pretty.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aZRyFlgj0ek/TaukuK2N3mI/AAAAAAAAAL0/wYT4Lr-cZjI/s1600/DSC_0377.JPG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="426" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-aZRyFlgj0ek/TaukuK2N3mI/AAAAAAAAAL0/wYT4Lr-cZjI/s640/DSC_0377.JPG" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">dat skeleton</td></tr></tbody></table><br />It's a shame that we won't be able to do something uber-fancy, but there's definitely not enough time in eight weeks, amidst my other classes, to do anything else. D: In particular we were brainstorming various challenges to an exercise game, and came up with some --<br /><br /><ul><li>How do you make an exercise game engaging all the way through, so people don't get bored in the middle?</li><li>How can you make sure people can rest when they're tired and not get too penalized?</li><li>How can you even force people to rest during long stretches of exercise?</li><li>When people go up to a stationary bike at the gym, they may just be concerned with exercising for a period of time; so how do you time a game and make sure that people can finish a round in 20 minutes or 30 minutes, and feel satisfied?</li></ul><br />Thus, bunnies and monsters. &nbsp;Our bunnies are the main incentive -- they speed up when players need to speed up -- and monsters to be defeated can have constraints on their vanquishing, which in turn puts constrains on a user's action. &nbsp;One monster could require speeding up very fast momentarily to flatten it; another maybe could be unbeatable, and thus can only be dealt with by sneaking past it, slowly, or at a constant heart rate.<br /><br />We were also exploring different ways that we could use a game to guide people through proper warming up, then exercise, then cooling down, through different stages of a level.  What I mostly want to do is make it so that an exercise game is capable of educating people about exercise, which is something I feel I never really received properly; for example, you're told in your P.E. class that it's good to warm up and cool down, but why, exactly?  What's the difference between diastolic and systolic blood pressure?  What's their proper ranges, and what does it mean if their numbers are too high or too low?<br /><br />Nowadays you could just Google this information, but learning it in the context of exercising would be more fun, I think.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
