<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Writing | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T09:11:38-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Story: Monsterfolk]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/monsterfolk/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-09T14:32:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/monsterfolk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The most recent issue of AU is out at Bulldog News!</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/monsterfolk1.JPG" alt="AU Issue X at Bulldog News"/></p>

<p class="caption">Such AU Issue X!</p>


<p>This time the theme was <em>Monster</em> and for this story I have to admit that I was heavily inspired by <em>Howl&rsquo;s Moving Castle</em> and <em>Shadow of the Colossus</em>. <a href="https://twitter.com/couch_crusader">Chris</a> helped me come up with a name for my main character, though I hope that name isn&rsquo;t <em>too</em> obvious.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still working on a place to host my writing online. For now, if you&rsquo;re in Seattle, you can pick up a copy at Bulldog News!</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/monsterfolk2.JPG" alt="Monsterfolk at Bulldog News"/></p>

<p class="caption"><em>Monsterfolk</em>, complete with some sketches I did, which the editors asked to add!</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Story: Chronectomy]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/au13-submissions/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-09T13:06:27-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/au13-submissions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/chronectomy1.JPG" alt="AU Issue VIII at Bulldog News"/></p>

<p class="caption">AU Issue VIII at Bulldog News</p>


<p>I&rsquo;m into my last couple months as a UW student, and these are my last couple months to submit to <a href="http://strayingfromreality.wordpress.com/">AU</a>, UW&rsquo;s speculative fiction journal. Since the <a href="/blog/2012-12-30-short-story-golemists-work.html">last time I&rsquo;ve written about it</a> I&rsquo;ve had two more acceptances! The story that I&rsquo;ll talk about in this post is <em>Chronectomy</em>, written for the Winter 2012, Issue VIII prompt: <em>chronos</em>, or time.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/chronectomy2.JPG" alt="Chronectomy!"/></p>

<p class="caption">Chronectomy! I LOVE what the editors did with the "O's."</p>


<p>I came up with an idea almost immediately and wrote furiously for a couple hours before realizing I was writing entirely the wrong story, and redid the entire thing. I&rsquo;m still working on a place to host my short stories online, but at least for now you can read <em>Chronectomy</em> on <a href="http://neauro.com">my portfolio</a>.</p>

<p>[ spoilers follow ]</p>

<p>I was really happy with the way I described the chronectomy clinic in this draft, but there were a couple problems overall that made me realize I had to totally redo it:</p>

<ul>
  <li>I intended this draft's appeal to be that the audience has no idea what's going on, but I realized that I wanted to write something a little deeper. In this draft, once you realize that the clinic is about removing memories, there's not much else to get out of it.</li>
  <li>The protagonist of this draft, Alice, doesn't have a very clear motive. Again, I was relying on there to be some kind of "Oohh, why is she here?" feeling to pull the audience through, but I wasn't confident that all this exposition and description would be fun to read on its own, when you don't even know why the character is there.</li>
  <li>At the end, I wanted to pull a sort of "Whoa! Bet you didn't see that coming!" moment, where the clinician suddenly steals the protagonist's memories for himself — but I realized that by the time you reach the end, you don't know enough about him at all to care that he stole her memories, nor do you know why he did so. You also never know the protagonist well enough to care that her memories were stolen, since she's shrouded in mystery for the draft's majority.</li>
  <li>Since the original prompt was related to "time," my initial intention was to explore what people would do with time — selling it, donating it, using it to heal their mental trauma, and so on. When the clinician starts reciting all these uses to the protagonist, I realized that those things were all way more interesting than what was happening right then in the story, and that furthermore, all these uses were just being talked about, and not actually experienced.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, I realized the better perspective to use for this story was not Alice but the clinician, and why he would steal someone else&rsquo;s memory in the first place.</p>

<p>Draft below the cut.</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr/>


<p>The clinic was a low building perched on a strip, cornered between a sit-down pho place and a hole-in-the-wall that dispensed frozen yogurt from ancient, sticky machines. It was delicious, in part because of the sheer novelty of getting yogurt from a machine you expected would only cough out rust and coppery water. And it was cheap — a dollar six for a cup that sat easily in your palm, and only fifty cents more for a tablespoon of chopped pineapple and chocolate chips.</p>

<p>Her lips pursed and she felt tears well in her eyes. It made the building, already blurry with heat, even more hazy and dream-like. There were protestors lined up on the curb outside the clinic and she marched across the parking lot clutching the bulky duffel bag like a shield. As she approached, one of the protestors stabbed his spork into a soft boulder of yogurt freckled with rainbow sprinkles, and lifted one of the signs that was leaning on the clinic wall.</p>

<p>&ldquo;All of life is a gift,&rdquo; he managed loudly, and as yogurt spilled on his shirt the rest of the group cackled. A girl hit him playfully on the shoulder. It seemed the appointment was during the high school shift.</p>

<p>She tried not to look at them, but couldn&rsquo;t help glancing down as she stepped over their polished legs. One girl cried, &ldquo;Just be strong! Don&rsquo;t throw yourself away!&rdquo; And one boy called, &ldquo;Come on, we&rsquo;ll buy you a yogurt if you cancel,&rdquo; and the girls again squealed with feigned indignation between yogurt-dripping laughs.</p>

<p>She swallowed and reached for the door. There was a sticker on it, a logo of beige hands holding two sides of an hourglass and pouring the grains from one side into the other. Her sweating palms slid on the searing metal of the door handle and she winced. The laughter rang in her ears. One of the boys had a familiar laugh, bright, the too-loud kind that was swollen with all the air in his lungs and was let out in booms that encompassed everyone an drew them in. Her heart clenched. And she yanked the door as hard as she could.</p>

<p>The door rattled fiercely and did not open. Her perspiring hand slipped off the handle and she nearly fell back.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You have to push,&rdquo; the boy told her, and pronounced each with so slowly that she had pushed the door and moved inside before he finished the sentence.</p>

<p>It was air-conditioned inside, and the cool air soothed her flushed cheeks. After the outside, which had been blurry with heat, the details of the inside of the clinic seemed unreasonably sharp. There was no chrome in sight, no blustering or chirping machines, no bubbling beakers. The walls were off-white and decorated with fake paintings of pastel flowers straining as if to escape their plastic frames. The furniture was like stuff she might have seen in a normal doctor&rsquo;s office, plastic cushions that were easy to clean and squeaked a little when she set her bag down.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Good morning! I can help you here,&rdquo; said the person at the counter, a man her age who had just walked in and was tugging a white doctor&rsquo;s coat sleeve hastily over a tattoo on his forearm. She approached cautiously, eyes cast on the little bit of ink she could see beyond the cuff.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Film,&rdquo; he explained with a smile, and tugged the sleeve up to show her, a tattoo&rsquo;d sleeve of cinema tape encircling a tab arm. &ldquo;They like that I keep it under wraps.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She made her mouth into a smile for him. He had had a tattoo too — also a sleeve, though the opposite arm. He had gotten it on a trip he had taken by himself to Hawand it symbolized &ldquo;freedom.&rdquo; (Now she wondered, Freedom from what? And, He probably was lying about going alone, wasn&rsquo;t he?)</p>

<p>She managed to uncoil her knotting throat and said, &ldquo;Thanks for taking me on such short notice. I saw the clinic isn&rsquo;t usually open at this time.&rdquo;</p>

<p>He smiled at her. &ldquo;No problem. It does keep the protestors off our back to accept patients at strange times. Those kids they post out there don&rsquo;t really care one way or another.&rdquo; He gestured at a door in the lounge. &ldquo;You wanna come back?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Shouldn&rsquo;t I fill out some paperwork or something?&rdquo;</p>

<p>He cocked his head. &ldquo;Do you want to?&rdquo;</p>

<p>And have a trail that connected her with a chronectomy, something that future employers would find and wonder and not give her the benefit of a doubt about?</p>

<p>&ldquo;Not really,&rdquo; she admitted.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Then, no paperwork. I will need payment up front though. In case you forget later.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Um,&rdquo; she murmured, &ldquo;I heard that I could get any fees waived if I&hellip;donated&hellip;?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;In that case,&rdquo; he said, &ldquo;all you need to fill out is this waiver.&rdquo; He slid a pink slip toward her and she plucked a pen from a little hourglass container where it had been stabbed upright into sand-colored lentils. She read it briefly and checked the appropriate boxes.</p>

<p>I agree to donate. I understand my donation waives all fees.</p>

<p>I understand I will not be able to review the [something something — a Latin word]. I agree they will be the sole property of Chosen Life, to dispose of at will.</p>

<p>There was a signature area at the bottom. She hadn’t been asked for ID. She considered and then wrote Alice on the line. Who cared?</p>

<p>She marked the right boxes and slid the paper back. He looked at it briefly and then filed it away.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Then,&rdquo; he said, gesturing to a door connecting the lounge and the back of the clinic, &ldquo;follow me.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She hesitated. Wariness bloomed in her. It was strange that the clinic was empty; it was strange that the only person here was a man, and a pretty young one at that, maybe nothing more than an intern. But she had trusted her gut before and it had let her down, further than she had ever known she could go. She walked through the door.</p>

<p>The clinician was waiting for her on the other side. He led we through a small hallway. &ldquo;What was your name, again?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Alice,&rdquo; she decided.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, Alice,&rdquo; he said, opening a door for her, &ldquo;you can call me Liu. I&rsquo;m not a doctor — not yet — but I am a certified chronectomist. Please have a seat. We can have you out of here in fifteen minutes, max.&rdquo;</p>

<p>So Liu was some kind of neotech grad student. Just like&hellip;</p>

<p>Stop. Don&rsquo;t even start. She forced herself to take a breath, which juddered in her throat. She expected one of the long tables with adjustable height and a paper on it, but the room had a divan like her psychiatrist. She hesitated when she saw it and Liu laughed.</p>

<p>&ldquo;None of that feely-weepy stuff here. Just make yourself comfortable while I set up.&rdquo; He glanced up at the clock in the room and then began to rummage around the drawers, fumbling with white plastic instruments sealed in bags.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Can I ask a couple questions?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Sure! Fire away. And hold out your right arm.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She pulled back her sleeve and he velcroed a strap over her arm that squeezed it uncomfortably.</p>

<p>She swallowed. &ldquo;Is it true that I&rsquo;ll age a little bit? Physically?&rdquo;</p>

<p>He smiled, as if to say, It&rsquo;s okay, I get this question all the time. &ldquo;No, you won&rsquo;t. The procedure is called a chronectomy, but what&rsquo;s really extracted are memories — the footprints of time on your brain. If anything, technically, you’ll be getting a little younger. Hmm, looks like your blood pressure’s just a tad low.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Yeah. Is that okay?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s fine.&rdquo; He turned and reached for one of the instruments that was unearthed. Curious, she strained to see. There were two rings. &ldquo;Now, hold out your middle fingers. Politely, of course.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She did.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Is it possible that I might lose other memories I don&rsquo;t want to?&rdquo; she asked.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Nope, and you’ll see why in a bit.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;What happens to them? After they&rsquo;re&hellip;after I donate them? I know I won’t have a say in them anymore, but&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It’s fine, I can answer that. A couple things can happen to them.&rdquo; He had a little vial and waggled it around as he spoke. &ldquo;Usually it gets sold. Depending on the content, you can help other people with it — sometimes the government will buy it for war veterans — ’time heals all wounds,’ you know. Psychologists and the like can use it for research. And — this is not Chosen Life, understand, but in the black markets — sometimes people come and they’ll sell their memories of studying for a test to richer students. There are growing markets over in Asia where people are selling hours of studying for a pretty prime price. It’s fascinating.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Spoken like a true grad student.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Of course, it all depends on the memory. Are you ready to get started?&rdquo;</p>

<p>She swallowed. &ldquo;Yes.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Liu nodded. He rolled a tray beside her and, after unpackaging it, handed it to her. It was a simple mask, like a.surgeon’s mask, but made of soft cotton. He put one on as we&rsquo;ll, but it was impermeable pale green plastic and rubber.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Put this on.&rdquo;</p>

<p>She did. The mask&rsquo;s rubber band was too tight and quickly tangled in her hair. Liu tugged it a couple times and when he was certain it was secure around her mouth and nose he rapped the vial one last time against his palm and then opened it carefully. There was a dropper protruding from the inside of the lid and he filled it up with clear liquid, and pinched it onto her cotton mask.</p>

<p>It soaked into the cotton. She jumped. It had a strong smell that she wasn’t expecting. It smelled like — like —</p>

<p>&ldquo;Take a deep breath,&rdquo; he told her. She had stopped breathing in panic. She took a deep breath and the smell took form. It was like drinking cold water on a hot day but instead of trickling down ice cold between her ribs it trickled upward, a fuzzy warmth that permeated against the roof of her mouth, the veins behind her eyeballs, the place in her brain that ached every morning she woke up and realized she was without him. She trembled and her eyes began to water. She felt separated from her limbs,and for that reason fumbled when Liu started to shove something into her hands. Her fingers fumbled around the strange object. It took her a while to realize it was a pen.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Write as you answer,&rdquo; Liu said. His voice was a whisper, but it reverberated throughout her body. &ldquo;What does it smell like?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Like his jacket,&rdquo; she said, through a haze. Her voice was loud. She heard her teeth clicking as she spoke, as if she were underwater. Her hand scribbled. &ldquo;Like his cologne. Like our pillows in the morning.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Omen Sits on a Fissure’s Edge, Where the Core of the Earth Once Stretched Up to Reach the Stars, and, Finding the Skyscape Out of Reach, Collapsed Its Crags on Veins of Silver and Opal.]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/06/02/omen-sits-on-fissures-edge-where-core/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/06/02/omen-sits-on-fissures-edge-where-core</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
While it gathered its strength, refugees and wrens came between the seams of obsidian to erect homes strung like beads between wires and bridges: a necklace of a town, a veil on the sky-staring bride.<br /><br />Because of the earth’s longing, they say, things happen here not by science but by intention, and the citizens are fluent in the tongue of symbols. They set their calendars not to the sun or moon, but to the shadows of wrens whose flocks the wind sings into staffs and blots. They sequence their itineraries to the shapes of leaf-stripped branches. Those seeking counsel spin at the edge of the canyons and upon stopping take the advice of a mushroom spotted in the bramble — or a drop of rain falling on the right ring finger — or a whiff of windfallen apples fermenting on the jags. A child playing on the bridges might, upon seeing her ball wince away from a sharp stone, decide then that it’s time for her to travel the world and grow into herself.<br /><br />But it is hard to leave the guidance of the wishing earth, to go to the villages where only words mean anything, and the denizens refuse to listen unless you hollow yourself like a shell and echo their noises back to them. Many soon return, stumbling back, their knees and knuckles embracing veins of silver and opal. They tip their heads back, and the clouds touch their cheeks with rain, and purr with thunder. When they return, they stay, and would only leave again to meet the stars.<br /><hr /><div style="font-size: 90%;">Figment Theme 5/22/2013: There are so many cities in the world, and a nearly infinite number of fictional towns in addition. Pick an intangible noun (think “hope,” “friendship,” “fear,” “loathing,”) and write a short scene set in a town with that name.</div></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>nadine a.</div>
<div class='content'>
That, and Palimpsest :)</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
Very evocative, I like it! :D Were you inspired by David Abram&#39;s work (The Spell of the Sensuous, Becoming Animal) at all?</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Figment Daily Theme 5/6/2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/05/08/figment-daily-theme-562013/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/05/08/figment-daily-theme-562013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="p1">"Life isn't kind," my mother would always say, "so why should you be?"</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">She would say it as she snatched quarters from the rattling cups that people shook on street corners, as she puppeted muscles in centimeters to collide knees and toes into the edges of furniture. She did it not with viciousness but with a sense of duty. Life isn’t kind. Life isn’t kind. She raised the banner of it with every missing umbrella (or broken umbrella, on a blustering day), with every bout of apprehension (during speeches, but especially first dates), with every misremembered promise (easily shucked off on days when the wind blew and bit the bones).</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Life isn’t kind. She did these things to others, but she did them for me. I couldn’t know life, so this is how she showed it to me. Missed buses, muddy white dresses, crumpled fenders, ruptured skin. Withered ardor, drifted friendships, secrets and promises slipped from mouth and mind. This is how I knew I wasn’t missing anything. My body would have only grown to leak blood and tears and perspiration — to be a vessel for illness and expectations — whipped from one day to the next by hunger and desire.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Life passed before us like a television drama. "Life isn’t kind," she chanted. "But death is." We dripped with the wails of war and heartbreak but never chilled; we chased the somersaulting springs and never tired. We welcomed the newcomers who traded their scars for a view of my face, my limbs, all approximated from the bodies of the handful that attended the wake. At night I liked to show them the procession of comets and meteorites, all swathed with wishes. They always cried to see their own hopes racing away from them, their old fuzzy future becoming the stone past. I have never cried, but I comfort them the way I’ve seen comforting happen. Death is kind, so you might as well be kind.</div><hr /><div style="font-size: 90%;">Prompt:&nbsp;<i>"Life isn't kind," my mother would always say, "so why should you be?"</i>&nbsp;Use this line as inspiration for a short story or poem.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Story: Golemist's Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/12/30/short-story-golemists-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/12/30/short-story-golemists-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-fv-rh8_DYVI/UNPFitXzX1I/AAAAAAAAC7o/-u6dZbVbFVk/s1600/golemists's+work_pattern.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-fv-rh8_DYVI/UNPFitXzX1I/AAAAAAAAC7o/-u6dZbVbFVk/s640/golemists's+work_pattern.png" width="492" /></a></div><br /><br /><a href="http://strayingfromreality.webs.com/">AU</a> is in its third year now, and grown so much! The inside of this quarter's edition is unexpectedly lovely. To check it out, you'll have to get it yourself, since I've tried and failed and subsequently quit attempting to make myself take pictures and upload them for this post.&nbsp;It's available on campus and neighboring book-related businesses until supplies run out. My particular story can also be accessed <a href="http://neauro.com/storything/golemist.html">here</a>, because I wanted some content to practice styling, and playing around with for lightweight parallaxing.<br /><br />[ spoilers ]<br /><br />Inspiration didn't quite strike me for any of the themes last year, but it did for this particular theme, "Homeland." I was feverishly thinking of ways to riff off the idea of <em>returning home</em> when I was shuffling my white/green tokens deck, and then looked down into my hand and saw Wayfaring Temple.<br /><br /><em>Oh my gosh</em>, I thought, <em>what if your home returns to YOU?</em><br /><em><br /></em>I used <a href="http://johnpolacek.github.com/superscrollorama/">SUPERSCROLLORAMA</a>&nbsp;for the sillyness at the end.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
