<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Writing | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T19:24:11-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Omen Sits on a Fissure’s Edge, Where the Core of the Earth Once Stretched Up to Reach the Stars, and, Finding the Skyscape Out of Reach, Collapsed Its Crags on Veins of Silver and Opal.]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/06/02/omen-sits-on-fissures-edge-where-core/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/06/02/omen-sits-on-fissures-edge-where-core</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
While it gathered its strength, refugees and wrens came between the seams of obsidian to erect homes strung like beads between wires and bridges: a necklace of a town, a veil on the sky-staring bride.<br /><br />Because of the earth’s longing, they say, things happen here not by science but by intention, and the citizens are fluent in the tongue of symbols. They set their calendars not to the sun or moon, but to the shadows of wrens whose flocks the wind sings into staffs and blots. They sequence their itineraries to the shapes of leaf-stripped branches. Those seeking counsel spin at the edge of the canyons and upon stopping take the advice of a mushroom spotted in the bramble — or a drop of rain falling on the right ring finger — or a whiff of windfallen apples fermenting on the jags. A child playing on the bridges might, upon seeing her ball wince away from a sharp stone, decide then that it’s time for her to travel the world and grow into herself.<br /><br />But it is hard to leave the guidance of the wishing earth, to go to the villages where only words mean anything, and the denizens refuse to listen unless you hollow yourself like a shell and echo their noises back to them. Many soon return, stumbling back, their knees and knuckles embracing veins of silver and opal. They tip their heads back, and the clouds touch their cheeks with rain, and purr with thunder. When they return, they stay, and would only leave again to meet the stars.<br /><hr /><div style="font-size: 90%;">Figment Theme 5/22/2013: There are so many cities in the world, and a nearly infinite number of fictional towns in addition. Pick an intangible noun (think “hope,” “friendship,” “fear,” “loathing,”) and write a short scene set in a town with that name.</div></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>nadine a.</div>
<div class='content'>
That, and Palimpsest :)</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
Very evocative, I like it! :D Were you inspired by David Abram&#39;s work (The Spell of the Sensuous, Becoming Animal) at all?</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Figment Daily Theme 5/6/2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/05/08/figment-daily-theme-562013/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/05/08/figment-daily-theme-562013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="p1">"Life isn't kind," my mother would always say, "so why should you be?"</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">She would say it as she snatched quarters from the rattling cups that people shook on street corners, as she puppeted muscles in centimeters to collide knees and toes into the edges of furniture. She did it not with viciousness but with a sense of duty. Life isn’t kind. Life isn’t kind. She raised the banner of it with every missing umbrella (or broken umbrella, on a blustering day), with every bout of apprehension (during speeches, but especially first dates), with every misremembered promise (easily shucked off on days when the wind blew and bit the bones).</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Life isn’t kind. She did these things to others, but she did them for me. I couldn’t know life, so this is how she showed it to me. Missed buses, muddy white dresses, crumpled fenders, ruptured skin. Withered ardor, drifted friendships, secrets and promises slipped from mouth and mind. This is how I knew I wasn’t missing anything. My body would have only grown to leak blood and tears and perspiration — to be a vessel for illness and expectations — whipped from one day to the next by hunger and desire.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Life passed before us like a television drama. "Life isn’t kind," she chanted. "But death is." We dripped with the wails of war and heartbreak but never chilled; we chased the somersaulting springs and never tired. We welcomed the newcomers who traded their scars for a view of my face, my limbs, all approximated from the bodies of the handful that attended the wake. At night I liked to show them the procession of comets and meteorites, all swathed with wishes. They always cried to see their own hopes racing away from them, their old fuzzy future becoming the stone past. I have never cried, but I comfort them the way I’ve seen comforting happen. Death is kind, so you might as well be kind.</div><hr /><div style="font-size: 90%;">Prompt:&nbsp;<i>"Life isn't kind," my mother would always say, "so why should you be?"</i>&nbsp;Use this line as inspiration for a short story or poem.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Short Story: Golemist's Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/12/30/short-story-golemists-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/12/30/short-story-golemists-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-fv-rh8_DYVI/UNPFitXzX1I/AAAAAAAAC7o/-u6dZbVbFVk/s1600/golemists's+work_pattern.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-fv-rh8_DYVI/UNPFitXzX1I/AAAAAAAAC7o/-u6dZbVbFVk/s640/golemists's+work_pattern.png" width="492" /></a></div><br /><br /><a href="http://strayingfromreality.webs.com/">AU</a> is in its third year now, and grown so much! The inside of this quarter's edition is unexpectedly lovely. To check it out, you'll have to get it yourself, since I've tried and failed and subsequently quit attempting to make myself take pictures and upload them for this post.&nbsp;It's available on campus and neighboring book-related businesses until supplies run out. My particular story can also be accessed <a href="http://neauro.com/storything/golemist.html">here</a>, because I wanted some content to practice styling, and playing around with for lightweight parallaxing.<br /><br />[ spoilers ]<br /><br />Inspiration didn't quite strike me for any of the themes last year, but it did for this particular theme, "Homeland." I was feverishly thinking of ways to riff off the idea of <em>returning home</em> when I was shuffling my white/green tokens deck, and then looked down into my hand and saw Wayfaring Temple.<br /><br /><em>Oh my gosh</em>, I thought, <em>what if your home returns to YOU?</em><br /><em><br /></em>I used <a href="http://johnpolacek.github.com/superscrollorama/">SUPERSCROLLORAMA</a>&nbsp;for the sillyness at the end.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Magnets] Cloudsong]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/05/02/magnets-cloudsong/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/05/02/magnets-cloudsong</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-dOPxYDZfD1Y/T6AbZI3dMcI/AAAAAAAAA1E/cH3YgwJIWFs/s640/blogger-image-1892673679.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="400" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-dOPxYDZfD1Y/T6AbZI3dMcI/AAAAAAAAA1E/cH3YgwJIWFs/s400/blogger-image-1892673679.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i>I fished a symphony</i></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i>from a thousand clouds wet with dawn &amp; diamond thunder</i></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i><br /></i></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i><br /></i></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i><br /></i></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i><br /></i></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">Andou's reaction: "Your thunder is now DIAMONDS"</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Magnets] Springlather]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/04/11/magnets-springlather/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/04/11/magnets-springlather</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-q10BqL2UPVc/T4Z3fVnfCHI/AAAAAAAAAw0/1a8BKgKug7g/s640/blogger-image-1409451663.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-q10BqL2UPVc/T4Z3fVnfCHI/AAAAAAAAAw0/1a8BKgKug7g/s640/blogger-image-1409451663.jpg" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i>summer riping</i></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i>with petalfall lathered in rain</i></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><i>the pink death of spring smeared sweetsmelling</i></div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
