<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: List | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/list/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T19:51:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cool Things Learned Today From the Internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/22/cool-things-learned-today-from-internet/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/22/cool-things-learned-today-from-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<h2> Tree rot</h2>happens when a tree sustains a large wound near or on its trunk and fungus moves in before the tree can "callous" over the hurt area.  The fungus eat away at the wood fiber, but some trees (like oak) can remain structurally sound by "compartmentalizing the decay," or allowing the fungus to eat away only at the wood that is already dead at the tree's center, and not at the tree's new growth rings.  Some trees can even develop a "rams-horn," which is when tree growth curves inward.  This keeps the tree standing sturdy. (via <a href="http://www.austintreeexperts.com/blog/cavity-tree-internal-decay-hollow/">Austin Tree Experts</a>)<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-BdYY4s26jBY/T0XZcn1geNI/AAAAAAAAArA/tP0MrKqFKxQ/s1600/1238007.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="310" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-BdYY4s26jBY/T0XZcn1geNI/AAAAAAAAArA/tP0MrKqFKxQ/s320/1238007.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">...party on the inside<br />photo by Randy Cyr, Greentree, Bugwood.org&nbsp;(<a href="http://www.forestryimages.org/browse/detail.cfm?imgnum=1238007">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><br /><h2> Horsetail Fall</h2>is a waterfall in Yosemite National Park which, once a year during a sunset in the last week of February, becomes illuminated by sunlight and becomes a "natural firefall."&nbsp;(via <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/pictureshow/2012/02/21/147206195/from-waterfall-to-lavafall-yosemites-fleeting-phenomenon">NPR: From Waterfall To Lavafall: Yosemite's Fleeting Phenomenon</a>)<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-V1sMGPwF21M/UCLtn4ZaQLI/AAAAAAAAB-I/kFmg9Uq5k-o/s1600/5486125788_a30f77e0c1.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-V1sMGPwF21M/UCLtn4ZaQLI/AAAAAAAAB-I/kFmg9Uq5k-o/s320/5486125788_a30f77e0c1.jpg" width="213" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">by Joe Azure, used through CC (<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/joe-azure/5486125788/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><h2> Octopi</h2>die soon after performing what needs to be done to ensure the birth of new octopi.  In the male's case, this means doling out sperm; in the female's case, it means after laying globby strings of eggs and guarding them for about a month, during which she will not hunt and may ingest her own legs for sustenance. (via <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Octopus#Reproduction">Wikipedia</a>)</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Newly Learned Things Concerning Raising a Dog]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/09/06/newly-learned-things-concerning-raising/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/09/06/newly-learned-things-concerning-raising</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
So much (mostly online) research on shiba inu has gotten dog-related information spilling out of my ears, so I decided to keep it all <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0ApA7ip7Sl9C8dC1uM0V3TEQ5R19pVmVGNjRSZjkyeEE&amp;hl=en_US">organized</a>.<br /><br />Here are the more interesting things I learned, which may only be interesting and novel because I have never owned a dog before:<br /><br /><br /><h3>There is such a thing as a raw food diet for pets.</h3>The diet has you feeding your dog raw meat -- chicken, beef, pork, deer.  There is also a "prey model" variation in which meat is fed to an animal in the same proportions and states that it would obtain in natural settings.  (To illustrate, there's a weirdly endearing photo of a kitten feasting on a cottontail rabbit on the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raw_feeding#Prey_model">wikipedia page</a>.)<br /><br />In addition to raw food research, I was surprised to learn that some pet foods like Purina, which always seemed pretty classy, is apparently <a href="http://www.dogfoodadvisor.com/dog-food-reviews/purina-dog-chow/">really bad</a>.<br /><br />To me, the take-aways of a raw diet are as follows:<br /><br /><ul><li>Dogs are carnivores.  Eating raw meat, along with loving you, is what it has evolved to do.</li><li>Some kibble is highly processed and contains questionable items like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Omnivore%27s_Dilemma">corn and soy</a>.</li><li>The <a href="http://truthaboutpetfood.com/articles/they-talk-but-can-they-give-answers.html">advertising</a> and studies behind pet food can also be questionable, as someone discovered when she called pet food companies to ask about the content of the food and how it was made.</li><li>Raw meat and meaty bones (RMBs) scrub a dog's mouth more effectively than kibble or even kibble specialized to brush your dog's teeth.  Also, raw diets may lead to a dog smelling better, being more energetic and obedient, and feeling nicer to the touch.</li><li>Though there is bacteria and parasites in raw meat, there are things you can do to lessen the chance of infection in your dog, and in general dogs are pretty well-built to withstand the stuff that they put in their mouths.</li></ul><br />I've looked at a lot of sites about this topic, some that speak <a href="http://rawfed.com/myths/">more strongly</a> than others, and though the overall consensus is that there is "no data" for whether a raw food diet is noticeably better for your dog or not, I'm more inclined treat the food industry with suspicion concerning the questionable things it already does to humans.  That being said, I would feel torn feeding a shiba something like beef knowing that cows are <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAFO">raised so badly</a> anyway.<br /><br />Still, the idea of feeding a shiba inu a nice fresh fish makes me happy.  Also, now that I think about it, my old cat Dusty didn't subsist completely on pet food either; he had dry kibble and also human tuna, which we started feeding him once a day (and which he loved) after he got urinary tract infection and had to have surgery.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/auroraki/4137744452/in/photostream" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="426" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-0R0GvnE5Yyw/TmcXLLVI-0I/AAAAAAAAAc8/YBSoh4SQMl4/s640/4137744452_149316bb07.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">if my lola's cats can handle this, i'm sure US cats can too</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><br />As a note, I found <a href="http://rawfeddogs.net/Recipes/">a website with a variety of raw food recipes</a> -- though I wasn't sure what I was expecting when I started browsing it, hahaha.<br /><br /><br /><br /><h3>Raw bones are okay to give to a dog; cooked bones aren't.</h3>Cooking makes bones brittle and easily splintered, which is not good.<br /><br /><br /><center><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="345" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/t10yEI64nzc" width="560"></iframe></center><br /><br /><br /><h3>Dog-training is like programming.</h3>Someone on the Shiba Inu Forum <a href="http://www.shibainuforum.org/forum/comments.php?DiscussionID=8321">complained that her puppy was "stealth peeing,"</a> saying, "She doesn't give any warning when she pees on the carpet - she'll be sitting and she'll stand up and pee. No sound, no movement around looking for a place to go. Just up and squat, done in a second.  Generally, we try to grab her and take her outside as soon as we see it, but she's usually done before we can grab her..."<br /><br />To which someone replied, "This may be a habit she has picked up. She may have learned that if she pees a little bit, you will take her outside to pee."<br /><br />And for some reason this amazed me.  Dogs are <em>literal</em>.  Quite computer-like.<br /><br /><br /><br /><h3>Dogs become easily hydrated, but are also easily over-watered,</h3>which can lead to messes.  Who knew?  When I had Dusty, I just allowed him to have access to water all day.  I guess when you have puppies, it's a good idea to give them water and monitor them and make sure you can take them outside when you can.<br /><br /><br /><br />To conclude, here is another shiba inu video that Kelly showed me, to remind me of what the point of all this trouble is.<br /><br /><br /><center><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="345" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/hwvCDA5CuEc" width="420"></iframe></center></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>nadine a.</div>
<div class='content'>
For some reason what I really want to feed a dog is fish!  Raw fish, or maybe little fish snacks.  Hopefully I can find ones with no added salt once the time comes!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Mari</div>
<div class='content'>
Just make sure you don&#39;t feed your dog overly-seasoned foods (salty, etc) or feed them off the table. The former is unhealthy and the latter will teach them bad manners, even though their adorable behavior may make you want to give in :P</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>nadine a.</div>
<div class='content'>
I haven&#39;t read it!  But I have added it to the reading list!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
Have you read Temple Grandin&#39;s book Animals Make Us Human? Awesome, awesome book about animal psychology and behavior...</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cool Things I've Learned Watching the Blue Planet]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/09/05/cool-things-ive-learned-watching-blue/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/09/05/cool-things-ive-learned-watching-blue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Nowadays I get easily frustrated by movies.  The last straw was <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Picture_Perfect_(1997_film)">Picture Perfect</a>.  The main character, a woman, decides to focus on her career instead of on men, and succeeds in her work so drastically that her male boss is threatened by her, and passes her over for a promotion until she proves her "stability" to him be being in a relationship.<br /><br />Cool.  Thanks, romance movies.<br /><br />In any case, nowdays it's easier to stomach documentaries, particularly nature-related ones like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Blue_Planet">The Blue Planet</a>.  Which is amazing!  I can't even imagine how they could have gotten some of this footage.<br /><br />The following are things that blew my mind the most.<br /><br /><br /><h3>There is life on earth that does not depend on the sun.</h3><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9Mt-1cxO72w/TmURm86YtoI/AAAAAAAAAbQ/pNVUZ_bmbr8/s1600/deepseavolcano.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="488" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9Mt-1cxO72w/TmURm86YtoI/AAAAAAAAAbQ/pNVUZ_bmbr8/s640/deepseavolcano.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a colony beyond sunlight</td></tr></tbody></table><br />White crabs, fish, 2-meter long <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pompeii_worm">Pompei worms</a>, and hundreds of other species live near underwater volcanic vents, completely independent from the sun.  Their survival instead depends on bacteria that can derive sulfides from the vent, and are to these creatures what plants are to us.  Volcanic vents like these are also often only active for a couple decades or so.<br /><br /><br /><h3>Shearwater birds can dive down to a depth of several meters.</h3><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uEs0yq0SkPM/TmUPzv9nenI/AAAAAAAAAbA/Khxv6vVLvJc/s1600/dolphinsandbirds.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="478" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-uEs0yq0SkPM/TmUPzv9nenI/AAAAAAAAAbA/Khxv6vVLvJc/s640/dolphinsandbirds.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">dolphins and shearwaters underwater</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I mean, puffins can dive as well but I guess I was just shocked to see birds and dolphins swimming and eating <em>together</em>.  In this part of the documentary, a school of mackerel were cornered from above by the shearwaters and from below by the dolphins, and then later were set upon by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yellowfin_tuna">yellowfin tuna</a> (i.e. albacore).<br /><br /><br /><h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firefly_squid">Firefly squid</a> have photophores not only on their tentacles, but over their entire body.</h3><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-F37c8zxsaOQ/TmUQ9RmhHQI/AAAAAAAAAbI/G4DNX-JI23k/s1600/fireflysquid.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="488" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-F37c8zxsaOQ/TmUQ9RmhHQI/AAAAAAAAAbI/G4DNX-JI23k/s640/fireflysquid.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">pretty!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />This was in the episode titled "The Deep" which in general was full of beautiful luminescent stuff, including <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_vM1KhgloUA">Sea Gooseberries</a>, which I saw for the first time at the Monterey Bay Aquarium.<br /><br /><br /><h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capelin">Capelin</a> fish lay their eggs on beaches.</h3><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xc2iwaQqZtU/TmUTyjIiANI/AAAAAAAAAbY/kZ3Fgwns7eU/s1600/fishfish.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="482" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xc2iwaQqZtU/TmUTyjIiANI/AAAAAAAAAbY/kZ3Fgwns7eU/s640/fishfish.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">omg so many of them</td></tr></tbody></table><br />At the end of June/early July, capelin beach themselves to lay and fertilize their eggs.  This is possibly because the eggs are safer from predation here than in the open water.  Eggs laid here may also develop faster.<br /><br /><br /><h3>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marine_Iguana">marine iguana</a> is the only lizard that can swim, and feeds on seaweed and algae.</h3><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VDCxpPe0NGU/TmUUVHIdvmI/AAAAAAAAAbg/904B0nrAqbU/s1600/iguana.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="482" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VDCxpPe0NGU/TmUUVHIdvmI/AAAAAAAAAbg/904B0nrAqbU/s640/iguana.png" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">ye. &nbsp;eat that algae</td></tr></tbody></table><br />In order to eat, it dashes down to rocks between strong breaker waves and eats the seaweed before dashing back up to safety again.  Or else it swims, though the documentary stated that only males can swim?  Weird.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
