<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Design | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-10T08:28:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Racermate Wireframes]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/07/23/racermate-wireframes/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/07/23/racermate-wireframes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-JQd6Q9TXR70/UA1-MoE_1MI/AAAAAAAABvU/_vonhJbyc5s/s1600/thumbnail.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-JQd6Q9TXR70/UA1-MoE_1MI/AAAAAAAABvU/_vonhJbyc5s/s320/thumbnail.png" width="233" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">"before and after" comparisons for racermate wireframes</td></tr></tbody></table><br />A couple days ago I made up wireframes for a theoretical redesign of the <a href="http://www.racermateinc.com/">Racermate</a>&nbsp;website, where a couple friends of mine work.<br /><br /><br /><h2> Front Page</h2>First was the front page, which I found personally bewildering: the buttons that frame either side of the wall of "newsletter" text at the center of the page don't have much context, or direction.&nbsp;"MultiRider Software," "MultiRider Center Locations" -- what is that, what do I do with it, why is it relevant? "Wingate Testing with Velotron" -- what does this indicate or mean to a new user? "ErgVideo.com" seems to open a new website completely, how is it affiliated to Racermate, what does it do?<br /><br />For the redesign, I focused on making the site informative to new users.&nbsp;I kept much of the information in the header "The WORLD LEADER in ELECTRONIC BICYCLE ERGOMETERS..." and "OFFICIAL BIKE TRAINERS OF..." -- because they're good explanations of "This is who we are, this is why we are trustworthy."<br /><br />I made the top navigation buttons larger than in the original design, and made them more self-explanatory: "COACHES" in the original turned into "Find a coach;" "MultiRider" became "MultiRider: Ride Together" to give the user more grounding on what they would learn about when clicking through. This would also expand users' knowledge of Racermate products right on the front page; MultiRider can be immediately understood as a social application of a RacerMate product.<br /><br />The next two "rows" of information also serve to focus and explain Racermate through images, rather than text. The first row is a carousel of images, text description, and links to different Racermate products; the next, a much more involved "This is who we are" statement.<br /><br />Because word of mouth is important to this product, part of the front page is also devoted to testimonials sent in by happy consumers.<br /><br /><br /><h2> Product Display Page</h2>Talking with friends at Racermate, I learned that online orders make up a little more than half of the total number of orders that this company gets. But when I went through the website myself, I found the <a href="http://www.computrainer.com/rm_inc/sales/pricing_ordering.html">order page</a> bewildering and cluttered with a variety of colors of clots of text. As a new user unfamiliar with the product, I didn't understand what exactly the product would be when I ordered it, or what would come with it, or what exactly it is meant to do. To get a full picture of what some products do requires that the user navigate to half a dozen completely different pages. Ordering information is also separated from a product overview, and ordering online requires that the user:<br /><br /><ol><li>Learn about the product by navigating around "Products" and all related pages in the top navigation</li><li>Click "Sales" in the top navigation</li><li>Hover over desired product</li><li>Click "Pricing &amp; Information"</li><li>Parse a long order page</li><li>Click "Add to Cart"</li><li>Complete order</li></ol><br />For the redesign, I made the product name and brief description most prominent, and after that, an easy way to switch between views of different product models. Another prominent part of the product display page are images of the product. Features can be described in the text to the right of the product images, or reviewed with more detail further down the page. In the redesign, the steps for ordering online now are:<br /><br /><ol><li>Click "Products" in the top navigation, or hover over "Products" and select desired product</li><li>Learn about product and its models on a single page</li><li>Click "Add to Cart"</li><li>Complete order</li></ol><div><br /></div><br /><h2> What's next?</h2><br />A low-fidelity prototype would ensure that the navigation of the website actually makes sense; users would have to be able to know how to complete certain tasks, such as <i>Find out what exactly you get when you order a CompuTrainer</i>, and with real copy provided, we could ensure that the right kind of information is shown on the right pages. (For example, do people want to know more about certain complex features? Less?) User testing would also target current users who use the website as a hub for Racermate-related news, and ensure that they aren't alienated.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Craving Wireframes]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/07/23/craving-wireframes_23/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/07/23/craving-wireframes_23</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UOK1u90PvxE/UAY-27akyRI/AAAAAAAABuw/sbJA9KIYHlg/s1600/craving.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="308" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UOK1u90PvxE/UAY-27akyRI/AAAAAAAABuw/sbJA9KIYHlg/s400/craving.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><br />These are mock-ups from an idea I had two years ago, for a website that would aggregate photos people took of food at restaurants. The idea was that if you were hungry, but not sure what exactly you wanted to eat, you could just sit here and click <i>Random picture!</i>&nbsp;until you saw something sufficiently appetizing, nearby, and cheap.<br /><br />The first thing to do was to make sure that this idea wasn't already done. Looking around, we (me and <a href="http://joshuahou.com/">Joshua Hou</a>, my then partner) turned up a couple similar sites, including:<br /><br /><ul><li><b>Yelp</b>: the obvious comparison. But, though at the time it incorporated user-contributed photos of food, it didn't do it to the extent that we wanted to support it.</li><li><b>Google Hotpot</b>: newly released at the time, but, despite its food-related name, still not all about photos of food.</li></ul><br />The main task that I wanted to support foremost was, <i>Look at pictures of food, and see where they are.</i>&nbsp;For that reason, the two main things on the front page are some random featured food (indicated by numeral 1), and a map (numeral 3). You can also specify and limit what area food is shown from (numeral 6).<br /><br />The other main task here is <i>Find a specific kind of food,</i>&nbsp;which is supported by the search bar at the top of the page.<br /><br />Another aspect of the site is the ability to comment and rate dishes -- but since this should really be secondary to "Look at delicious things!" it's limited to ratings on a five-star scale, and a short description.<br /><br />Views of specific dishes (the wireframe on the bottom-left) show all the photos associated with the dish, as well as comments and ratings. Views of specific restaurants show all photos associated with the dishes at that restaurant, with the idea that a restaurant-specific page would become a crowdsourced visual menu. Which brings me to one question that I have about the concept of this site: how does having photos of food affect the stakeholders here? Fancy restaurants seem fond of depicting menu items with a variety of delicious buzzwords and nothing else, and when you, as the diner, finally receive your food, part of the pleasure is the surprise of seeing what it looks like. Along with general usability testing, questions like this would be part of "next steps" for this design.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Craving Wireframe Sketches]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/07/17/craving-wireframes/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/07/17/craving-wireframes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
The past few days I've been trying my hand at making <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Website_wireframe">wireframes</a>, which are basically very simple website layouts. I was like, Cool, this is cool, I've already got tons of very simple website layouts!<br /><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-W-x0LGMljC0/UAY51Gw9R7I/AAAAAAAABuE/lac_3wtOvEY/s1600/craving+screen.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="412" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-W-x0LGMljC0/UAY51Gw9R7I/AAAAAAAABuE/lac_3wtOvEY/s640/craving+screen.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a wild wireframes appears!</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br /></div><div>I scanned in some old notebook pages for my old "Craving" project, which would be a website that would aggregate photos of foods at restaurants, and enticingly display them at random to hungry people wondering where to eat. I then cleaned them up and was imminently bewildered at how to best place together these sketches.</div><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JOnKy7QP4zE/UAY6cJVazII/AAAAAAAABuM/isk5b_SogAI/s1600/craving_wireferames.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-JOnKy7QP4zE/UAY6cJVazII/AAAAAAAABuM/isk5b_SogAI/s400/craving_wireferames.jpg" width="308" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">maybe like...this...?</td></tr></tbody></table><div><br /></div><div>Then someone was like, "You should try Illustrator," so I finally installed my copy of it and found <a href="http://www.adobe.com/designcenter/video_workshop/">these great tutorial videos</a>&nbsp;and set off. I have to admit that Illustrator-made wireframes in general bewilder me -- it seems so much easier to just make sketches, and then move on to code. But, Illustrator is pretty fun to use.</div><div><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UOK1u90PvxE/UAY-27akyRI/AAAAAAAABuw/sbJA9KIYHlg/s1600/craving.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="247" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UOK1u90PvxE/UAY-27akyRI/AAAAAAAABuw/sbJA9KIYHlg/s320/craving.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">illustrator: the perfect square-drawing software</td></tr></tbody></table></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Casual Game Binge & Speculation]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/09/05/casual-game-binge-speculation/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/09/05/casual-game-binge-speculation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've spent most of the weekend playing hidden object games to try and understand them better.  The only one I'd been familiar with before was the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Her_Interactive#Nancy_Drew_Dossier"><em>Nancy Drew Dossier</em></a> series, which I'd hesitate to call a "hidden object game" because it feels like it contains more small puzzles than actual "hidden object scenes" where you're given a I-Spy list of things to spot.  Then again, most hidden object games also have small puzzles, so the whole "hidden object" genre in general seems pretty fluid.  And I think I ended up playing some games which, like NDD, seem to be general puzzle-solving adventures.<br /><br />My intention in playing these was to investigate and note what I felt were good and bad design choices, and in general to try and get a grip of what people expect hidden object games to offer.  I played all the games for at least an hour.  Spoilers may follow.<br /><br /><br /><h2>Drawn: Dark Flight</h2><em>Drawn: Dark Flight</em> is the sequel to <em>Drawn: Painted Tower</em>, and the premise of the game is to light beacons in order to help a young woman become the Queen of Stonebriar.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-GNFAGWpWiIM/TmVvGlWpz3I/AAAAAAAAAbo/HFuaZLF0Kis/s1600/29csw1y.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="240" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-GNFAGWpWiIM/TmVvGlWpz3I/AAAAAAAAAbo/HFuaZLF0Kis/s320/29csw1y.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://luv-of-mylife.blogspot.com/2010/09/adventure-games-drawn-dark-flight.html">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><h3>Things I Liked:</h3><ul><li>The art is beautiful.  I'm a sucker for dust motes (which seem to be a common theme of most hidden object environments), and the mostly-somber painted style was also very beautiful to look at.</li><li>I like the subtlety of hints -- for instance, the hint <em>You can climb up a paper-thin rope</em> cluing me into using the fact that I had to use my "Sketch of A Rope" object.  Haha it's a dead giveaway, but better than a completely dead giveaway, you know?  You still feel kinda smart solving it.</li><li>The use of the "drawn stuff/paper/sketches" theme and the variety of puzzles yielded by it was also pretty cool.</li></ul><br /><h3>Things I Didn't Like:</h3><ul><li>Whenever I try to navigate backwards, I keep accidentally hitting the inventory box at the bottom of the screen. This is because your inventory resides at the bottom of the screen, and also near the bottom of the screen is an invisible hitbox you click in order to navigate backward.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kq-05kOuSss/TmV-I_0nqhI/AAAAAAAAAcA/0sOM5n6ajaA/s1600/hitbox1.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="180" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-kq-05kOuSss/TmV-I_0nqhI/AAAAAAAAAcA/0sOM5n6ajaA/s320/hitbox1.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">dang you, invisible hitbox</td></tr></tbody></table><br />This was an annoyance across most games that I played.  This is related to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fitts%27s_law">Fitts's Law</a>, which is a model of human movement that basically says, <em>The bigger the button is, the easier it is to point at it.</em>  With computers, the edges and corners of a screen are easy to point at, because the mouse cursor remains at the edge or corner of a screen regardless of how much further you move it -- thus, I personally found it annoying to want to move "back" and having to restrain myself from going all the way to the bottom of the screen.  I suspect (though do not know) that the act of moving backward is more common than looking at your inventory item, so I think that whole lower area of the screen should be reserved for navigation.</li><li>When you pick up an item, it goes straight to your inventory, and you don't really have a chance to examine it, much less know what it is that you now have in your inventory.  Maybe it's Zelda that's made me feel like I should be rewarded/acknowledged every time I come into possession of something, but when you grab something and it spontaneously goes into your pocket before you're even sure what it is, it feels a little forced.</li><li>Wait, so who am I again?  And why do I care about this girl I don't know becoming the queen?  I know it's a sequel but it would have been nice to have a little more intrigue. I didn't play the entire game, though, so maybe there's more interestingness in the plot later.</li></ul><br /><br /><br /><h2>Shiver: Vanishing Hitchhiker</h2>You pick up a hitch hiker.  As you drop her off in a small town, you realize she left something behind.  It's a teddy bear...from your childhood!  This hidden object game has a horror/scary flavor to it.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-AuKGZza-Myc/TmV1RuKrcTI/AAAAAAAAAbw/NGw9feKdBPQ/s1600/Shiver-Vanishing-Hitchhiker.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="240" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-AuKGZza-Myc/TmV1RuKrcTI/AAAAAAAAAbw/NGw9feKdBPQ/s320/Shiver-Vanishing-Hitchhiker.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.downloadall.in/download-shiver-vanishing-hitchhiker-collectors-edition/shiver-vanishing-hitchhiker/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><h3>Things I Liked:</h3><ul><li>The hidden object scenes were slightly different -- rather than just searching the scene, to find some objects, you had to manipulate the environment in some way.  For example, some objects would be hidden in a box you'd have to open, or you might have to put together a photograph's torn edges in order to really "find" the photograph.</li><li>I liked the use of the flashlight to illuminate only some parts of a hidden object scene as you were searching, and also as a method of exploring the environment; at one point in the basement area my flashlight fell onto a bright-eyed rat and I jumped in my seat, haha.  Limiting a player's view = good shock/scare value.</li><li>Speaking of good shock/scare values, this game did a good job with creepy things, for example that one hidden object scene where you had to find a hand, and the hand was a plastic doll's hand in a meat grinder.</li><li>The environment would also move on its own sometimes, with shadows in the windows or eyes at the keyhole -- cool stuff like that.</li><li>When I was trying to reconstruct steps in the basement and was failing, the main character himself said, "I have to go from the lowest step." I like that the character himself said something, rather than the game putting up a dialog for me to follow -- it's a little more natural-feeling.  On the other hand, I guess this too can have <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ptitlez17dr6puup2l">its pitfalls</a>.</li><li>The story started becoming really, really intriguing after a while, and I really want to play more to see what's actually happening in this strange little town!</li></ul><br /><h3>Things I Didn't Like:</h3><ul><li>Again, objects that you picked up abruptly went into your inventory without announcement or examination.</li><li>And again with that "let's reserve the bottom of the screen for the inventory" thing.</li><li>Something else this game does that seems common to hidden object games -- <em>really</em> abrupt hidden object scenes.  Like, you approach a desk, and click it, and without warning there's a list of objects at the bottom of the screen.  Huh?  No instruction?  Why do I specifically need to find <em>wrench, oil can, screwdriver, wood planar</em>?  At then at the end I suddenly get to keep the screwdriver?!  A lot of puzzles in hidden object games seem to throw you in without any instruction, but for a hidden object scene it's a little weird, because you have the list at the bottom that is not strictly a part of or even in its entirety related to the "game world" at all.  I wonder players find this treatment of hidden object scenes pretty normal.  If they do, that is pretty interesting as an example of unspoken expectations between the players and the developers.  It would be like making a shooting game and not teaching the player how to use a gun.  Maybe there <em>are</em> games like this now.</li><li>I was also kind of sad there was so little opportunity to learn about the main character of the story, who (judging by the first scene of the game) was slightly psychic.  At the very least he wasn't utterly freaked out by the appearance of ghosts later in the game, and when I hovered over his camera on the bottom-right side the tooltip said that it could see ghosts.  So...alright then.  My desire to learn more about the main character may have come about through playing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phoenix_Wright">Phoenix Wright</a>, and I wish you were able to "interact" with the main character to learn who he is, really.  Phoenix Wright is lovable because of his dryness, which is readily evident by what he thinks about the various things you choose to examine in different scenes of the game.  But especially with these hidden object games, you're given such a richer-looking environment than what's seen in a DS -- why not interact with it a little more?</li><li>Without knowing more about who the character is, the premise of why he ventured into the village -- to seek the girl who may be from his past -- feels forced and weak.  What are the stakes here?  I think that there's another <em>Shiver</em> game out there, but even if this is a sequel, it should be able to stand up on its own and explain itself.</li><li>At some point I couldn't find some object and started clicking all over the screen randomly, and my cursor started spinning around of its own accord moved off the screen.  For a second I thought this was creep-factor stuff, but then later realized this was the game's way of penalizing me for clicking around randomly.  In which case, a "Don't do that or else I'll make your cursor crazy" warning would have been nice.</li></ul><br /><br /><br /><h2>Tiger Eye: Curse of the Riddle Box Part 1</h2>A woman with an affinity for metal finds a shapeshifter man in a game that is based off a paranormal romance novel.  As a sidenote, this game was developed by <a href="http://passionfruitgames.com/download/">the people who developed NDD</a>.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-B6KKeIL0o9M/TmV9MvC8DaI/AAAAAAAAAb4/dDd3UwnhBMw/s1600/TigerEye-screenshot.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="240" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-B6KKeIL0o9M/TmV9MvC8DaI/AAAAAAAAAb4/dDd3UwnhBMw/s320/TigerEye-screenshot.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://blog.libraryjournal.com/inthebookroom/2010/12/02/interactive-digital-romance-gets-its-game-on/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><h3>Things I Liked</h3><ul><li>The hidden object scenes were <em>related to what was going on in the story presently</em>.  Have a dream about metal weaponry?  Find metal weaponry in a Chinese dirt market!  Need to assemble a bike?  Find the bike parts in an alleyway!</li><li>The things that you find in scenes also correlate to puzzles -- for example, collecting metal capsules which were then used in a word puzzle.</li><li>You have more hints than other games, and the number of hints you have is directly correlated with your actions, and if you don't use hints you are rewarded (by bonus material at the end of the game).</li><li>If you click around too much, your cursor freezes and the game explains to you what you did that it didn't like.</li><li>Good voice acting!</li><li>And pretty scenes!</li><li>The puzzles are very varied and fun to solve.</li><li>Bonus: I love when the thing that I'm searching for is <em>everywhere</em>!  For example, one scene where pieces of paper were strewn all over the room.  Collecting everything in sight is just a rush.  Maybe it's the mad, doober-collecting player that Zynga has bred in me.</li><li>Super Bonus: A female protagonist who is like, "I can't wait for the handyman, I'll just fix the bathroom myself."</li></ul><br /><h3>Things I Didn't Like</h3><ul><li>The object you had to find were pretty small, even in full-screen mode.</li><li>Each puzzle that you had to complete had instructions telling you what to do on the bottom.  A lot of other hidden object games just throw you in.  The puzzles are simple enough that you can figure out what to do on your own, and if you are given the chance to figure out a puzzle from scratch, I think the sense of accomplishment is greater.  At the very least there's less of a "hand-holding" feeling.  If you really need to give instructions, you could give the player a chance to ask for it via a hint.</li><li>A lot of these puzzles could have really used a "Restart" button.  Too often I messed around with pieces I had to assemble somehow, got completely confused, and then just wanted to start over fresh, without having to move all the pieces back out of the way myself.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-j3QJTKzOuEk/TmWO_oaLnyI/AAAAAAAAAcI/_KZXCcyDlQI/s1600/tigereyepuzzle2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="241" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-j3QJTKzOuEk/TmWO_oaLnyI/AAAAAAAAAcI/_KZXCcyDlQI/s320/tigereyepuzzle2.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">okay...I just want to start over</td></tr></tbody></table><br /></li><li>I also wish there had been an ability to exit a puzzle I was stuck at to take a break and check out another puzzle for a while.</li><li>Also, though there's a row of puzzle hints you can use at the top of the puzzle (visible in the above screenshot), they were unresponsive to clicking.  And though the number of hints I had was still visible in its usual place in the bottom-right, I couldn't use them.  Confusing.</li></ul><br /><br /><br /><h2>Mystery Legends: The Phantom of the Opera</h2>It's based off Phantom of the Opera.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Iz93vPSUv7g/TmWSCNv-TLI/AAAAAAAAAcQ/_l1Gukesrpc/s1600/Mystery-Legends-The-Phantom-of-the-Opera-the-phantom-of-the-opera-17346742-1280-800.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Iz93vPSUv7g/TmWSCNv-TLI/AAAAAAAAAcQ/_l1Gukesrpc/s320/Mystery-Legends-The-Phantom-of-the-Opera-the-phantom-of-the-opera-17346742-1280-800.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.fanpop.com/spots/the-phantom-of-the-opera/images/17346742/title/mystery-legends-phantom-opera-wallpaper">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><h3>Things I Liked</h3><ul><li>Again, gorgeous art.  DUST MOTES.  YES.  There were also small moving elements I liked, like little spiders everywhere.  But again, I wish I'd been able to get a rise out of the main character by clicking them.  Is she afraid of spiders?  Is she not?  I'll never know.</li><li>Good tutorial for how to navigate, and I also like that navigational arrows are labeled with where you'll go should you decide to click.  It's especially useful for this game because there are <em>so many places.  The map is also helpful in marking the rooms that have something of note in them.</em></li><li>When you find things, they vanish, and sometimes what's left behind is creepy!  Like this one mannequin had a helmet, and when you found the helmet it revealed this rather disturbed-looking head.  That is a really good use of that mechanic.</li><li>The inventory at the bottom of the screen is hidden a little better.</li><li>I like the mysterious hints that you pick up, i.e. the Green Faerie Absinthe Recipe.  Pretty fantastical.  Didn't play far enough to see whether this really played into the story well (other than it being a recipe for something you need to collect items to make).</li><li>Bonus: There's a reference to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wicked_play"><em>Wicked</em></a>!<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6pObbsr44wo/TmWkuF9r-dI/AAAAAAAAAcw/qP404sB3mmQ/s1600/phantom.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="180" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6pObbsr44wo/TmWkuF9r-dI/AAAAAAAAAcw/qP404sB3mmQ/s320/phantom.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">can you find it?!</td></tr></tbody></table><br /></li></ul><br /><h3>Things I Didn't Like</h3><ul><li>I would have wanted more opportunity to examine things, and more narration to help me learn more about the protagonist, etc.</li><li>There were so many...<i>places</i>, haha. &nbsp;Maybe I've become too casual for my own good.</li></ul><br /><br /><br /><h2>Mystery Case Files: Ravenhearst</h2>The Queen of England has enlisted your help in investigating a haunted manor.  You uncover what mysterious and terrible things happened therein by collecting the pages of a woman's diary.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HXL6hsDpM-E/TmWf3t-mxFI/AAAAAAAAAcg/su4x2AV3_wI/s1600/post-45137-1181170982.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="240" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-HXL6hsDpM-E/TmWf3t-mxFI/AAAAAAAAAcg/su4x2AV3_wI/s320/post-45137-1181170982.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.macclubindonesia.com/forums/showthread.php?11136-Mystery-Case-Files-Ravenhearst">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><h3>Things I Liked</h3><ul><li>To actually collect the diary entries, you have to piece them together, which turns out to be unexpectedly challenging. o__o<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-yMGgVv_HvCs/TmWfsoSKvDI/AAAAAAAAAcY/CU3hA9YlCNA/s1600/ravenhearst%2Bpuzzle.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="240" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-yMGgVv_HvCs/TmWfsoSKvDI/AAAAAAAAAcY/CU3hA9YlCNA/s320/ravenhearst%2Bpuzzle.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the answer is so close, yet so far</td></tr></tbody></table><br /></li><li>I liked the whispers in the background -- occasionally you'd hear a <em>Help me</em> or <em>This place is evil!</em> whispered alongside the background music.  "This place is evil" seems a little corny but I still appreciated it, haha.  Audio mechanics, though, remind me of accessibility -- a game that relied more heavily on sound effects as part of the plot would be inaccessible to the deaf.  It also makes me think of how sound does not matter with many Flash games, since people play them at work with the sound turned down.  How often do people play hidden object games with the sound up?  You <em>could</em> potentially play games like these in small intervals on work breaks.</li><li>Stuff in the background changes subtly -- for example, clicking on a painting of a woman may change her face very subtly into a skull.  Once I clicked on a card and it  tore in half, revealing a scrawled red <em>HELP</em>.  This is what I mean when I say I like interacting with the environment more. :D Plus, this is how you can contribute and really strengthen your theme.</li><li>This game has a pretty cool type of puzzle where you come up against a door which is locked with a completely bizarre-looking mechanism.  No instructions -- just figure it out.  "Click everything!"<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uyRFO3xFd38/TmWiJ3mhxPI/AAAAAAAAAco/LYrYRx709fo/s1600/ravenhearst%2Bpuzzle2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="240" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-uyRFO3xFd38/TmWiJ3mhxPI/AAAAAAAAAco/LYrYRx709fo/s320/ravenhearst%2Bpuzzle2.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">just, GO!</td></tr></tbody></table><br /></li><li>Clicking stuff at random reveals a help dialog!</li></ul><br /><h3>Things I Didn't Like</h3><ul><li>Clicking stuff at random, after the help dialog shows up, gives you a dialog that you shouldn't do that, and then punishes you by removing around a minute of the time you're given to solve a "level." What!  I can't just have a warning at first?</li><li>When you click on something in a hidden object scene that is not on your I-Spy list, there's this...really abrasive noise.  Which I guess deters you from clicking at random, but...man.  That noise is unpleasant.</li><li>There were small wording issues that I didn't like...when my list told me to find a "squash" it really meant find a "kabocha," and when it asked me to find a "shovel" it really wanted me to find a garden spade looking thing.  (Then, later, it asked me to find a "spade" which was an object that looked exactly like a "shovel"!) It's a pretty small issue but it brings to mind the problem with choosing hidden objects to be things that everyone will be able to figure out.  I guess if you're downloading this game from Big Fish it can be pretty assumed you have the internet to Google Image <em>wood planar</em>, so perhaps this is a trivial issue.</li><li>On a related note, one of the puzzles required me to play music on a piano keyboard, which would have stopped me in my tracks if I didn't know how to read music or play the piano.  One thing I like about the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Her_Interactive"><em>Nancy Drew Adventure</em></a> games is that if you will need some sort of knowledge to solve a puzzle, the game will provide it for you, for example in a book somewhere.  Then again, NDA is a game that could be purchased and installed from a store (i.e. no internet required), whereas these games are downloaded, so, maybe it's a trivial issue again.</li><li>The phrase "Hidden Clues Remaining" at the bottom-right -- I thought this meant the number of hints I had left overall, but it was actually the number of hidden things I had to find before I could unlock a diary page to piece together.  I don't remember the game explaining that, though.</li></ul><div><br /></div><div>Still not a casual game pro, but definitely getting more intrigued by them. &nbsp;It seems like a good area for building strong stories in an industry that otherwise doesn't seem like it has the time for them. &nbsp;Though recently I watched the gameplay trailer for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bastion_(video_game)">Bastion</a> and was pretty impressed and happy at how the game is narrated.</div><br /><center><iframe width="560" height="345" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/VZAuKkv4eZE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></center></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>nadine a.</div>
<div class='content'>
Let me know what you think once you do!</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Mari</div>
<div class='content'>
I haven&#39;t read everything yet but I&#39;ll check out all of them!</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good Design Moves Tumblr Has Made Recently Which I Really Appreciate]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/08/08/good-design-moves-tumblr-has-made/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/08/08/good-design-moves-tumblr-has-made</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<strong>Tiled Photosets</strong><br />If you wanted to post more than one picture at a time on Tumblr, it used to be that the pictures would be placed into a little slideshow applet.  It was really elegant and cute; you would see one picture at a time, and could press a little rounded arrow to move on to the next picture.<br /><br />The problem is, no one would use it.  Or at least, if people did post this way, it didn't get interacted with.  (At least, I didn't, and the rare frequency with which I met up with a photoset on my dashboard makes me think that others didn't really like this method of posting either.)  On Tumblr people just scroll, scroll, scroll.  Occasionally laugh.  And don't stop for your dang photosets.<br /><br />Then, suddenly!  A tiled photoset appears!<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CZrjAQAmsGI/TkCxzPGtDgI/AAAAAAAAAVg/78Ui_m8CiTk/s1600/photoset.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="526" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CZrjAQAmsGI/TkCxzPGtDgI/AAAAAAAAAVg/78Ui_m8CiTk/s640/photoset.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">with varied photo sizes, even!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />All of a sudden, you can see all the pictures in a photoset at once!  Plus the given layouts for different pictures make them all look really artsy, which Tumblr users love, because let's be honest, over half of us are there just reblogging stuff.  Though another mark of how cool this feature is is how people have taken creative liberties with it, making sets of images like <a href="http://natsura.tumblr.com/post/8598587153/flashinglightsandecstasy-lol-xd">this</a>, or <a href="http://natsura.tumblr.com/post/8572474978">this</a>, or even <a href="http://natsura.tumblr.com/post/8436544789">this</a>.<br /><br />Making a feature which fits with how people actually use the product, and allows them to be creative?  ++!<br /><br /><br /><strong>Reblogging Tags</strong><br />I actually just noticed this today.  Never again will I have to repopulate the tags of something that I'm reblogging.  As an example, <a href="http://textless.tumblr.com/">textless.tumblr</a> is a great blog for macro photography of insects (and other animals), and the photographer always dutifully tags all of his posts with whatever is pictured.  <em>Wooly Aphid.  Larva.  Wasp Mimic. Secropia Silkmoth.</em>  (These tags often even get cut off in the dashboard post.  I can't find an example now, but may later.)  In any case, though I love the accuracy of it, no way am I going to spend any time tagging these reblogs with anything more than "photo" and maybe "bug."<br /><br />Fortunately, now tags also get reblogged!  So, now reblogging things can make you feel even more productive with even less energy. :)<br /><br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-S_bvkOlgoOE/TkC4Lq-KX2I/AAAAAAAAAVo/bnrweSPmG8E/s1600/photoset2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="258" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-S_bvkOlgoOE/TkC4Lq-KX2I/AAAAAAAAAVo/bnrweSPmG8E/s400/photoset2.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">thanks, tumblr. &nbsp;you the bomb</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><strong>Edit:</strong><br />Now if only tags were easier to remove than pressing that teensy little X beside every rounded-corner box.<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oWzXOJfPEgI/TkNLEo_SODI/AAAAAAAAAV4/7vyWJbuxfDA/s1600/tumblr3.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="230" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-oWzXOJfPEgI/TkNLEo_SODI/AAAAAAAAAV4/7vyWJbuxfDA/s400/tumblr3.jpg" width="400" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><b>Edit 2:</b></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;">This feature was eventually removed. I wonder why :(</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
