<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Manga | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/manga/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T19:24:11-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Delicious Rollback]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/02/24/the-delicious-rollback/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/02/24/the-delicious-rollback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Right now I am totally in love with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julietta_Suzuki">Suzuki Julietta</a>. She is the manga-ka of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kamisama_Kiss"><em>Kamisama Hajimemashita</em></a>, which recently got propelled in my mind to 5-star status after it started acquiring a time paradox, a plot device to which I am particularly weak. (How could she have planned that?! <em>Hoowww</em>?)<br /><br />Suzuki has a great grasp of storytelling and character development, something that I really appreciate in shoujo manga. Recently I described <a href="http://www.mangahere.com/manga/kamisama_hajimemashita/c065/">Chapter 65</a> (and 66) to Andou as an example. It goes like this:<br /><br />Nanami is making talismans for the shrine, so that visitors can come and get charms for things like "traffic safety," "love," "prosperous business." Tomoe sees them and goes, "Your handwriting is awful, let's make new talismans on the nice wood that I stored away." Nanami admits that she thought that wood was trash and threw it away and feels bad that she's disappointed him and hasn't made much headway in being a good god. Later that night, she notices Tomoe leaving and follows him mistakenly across some ethereal border and is almost smashed by a giant's foot. Tomoe saves her, and they wander around the night market searching for new talisman wood. Eventually Nanami separates from Tomoe and discovers two demons bullying a child, and when she tries to intervene, the two demons go for her instead. Wracking her brain for solutions, she eventually leads them beyond the ethereal border, where they are promptly smashed. They sneer that she will get stomped on too, but Nanami smiles and opens her coat to reveal: a talisman for traffic safety.<br /><br />There's just something <em>so delighful</em> about the story coming back full circle. In a sense you should have expected it — maybe you had the fun of figuring out yourself how Nanami could have made it out of her situation — even if you didn't, your brain lights up to realize the importance of something so seemingly insignificant. The final talisman also serves to answer her insecurities about being a bad god (even if her handwriting is bad, it <em>works!</em>), and as a bonus, makes Nanami to me a little more "real" — more of a person who is reacting to things in her environment, learning about them, using them.<br /><br />It's just <em>great</em>, and by no means an isolated formula. For example, in <a href="http://www.mangahere.com/manga/karakuri_odette/v01/c001/">the first chapter of Suzuki's other work, Karakuri Odette</a>, Odette begins attending high school, much to the hesitation of the school administrators. "Don't worry," says Odette's creator, "if she ever runs into problems, she'll emit a signal to me, and I'll pick her up right away." They agree and as Odette tries to learn more about what it means to be human, she asks her creator to make adjustments to her body: first, to add the ability to eat food, and second, to subtract from her robotic physical ability so she's only as strong as an average 15-year-old. Odette finds a new friend who is sickly and occasionally has seizures, and wanders around with her to a construction site, where both Odette and the girl fall into a well. Since she asked to be weakened, Odette can no longer climb out on her own — but then the girl starts to breathe desperately and beg for medicine — so Odette says, "Look away, don't look back until I say so," and when the girl turns away <em>Odette removes her head from her body</em> — which triggers the signal, and makes her creator come running.<br /><br /><em>So good!</em> There's just something utterly delicious of a small detail turning out to mean everything. This is something that I think is a challenge to do with games. When you pick up a key in level 1, for example, it's hard to imagine that it could be used to anything other than a treasure chest. (Though, knowing that, it would be fun to purposefully subvert this and make the key into an instrument for something else.)<br /><br />I've never played A Link to the Past, but apparently there's a great example of "small detail coming back to bite you" in it. It goes kind of like this: In one of the first towns you visit, there's a man who describes a nearby building as the old home of some evil bandit who for some reason couldn't stand the light. You play on, and on, and eventually, you return to the old home, and rescue the maiden in it, who begins to follow you around as you make your escape. At some point, you set a bomb off in a room, which collapses a ceiling and lets the light in — and when the maiden walks into it, she rips her skin off and become's the bandit. <em>The bandit, the dungeon's boss, has been following you this whole time! Whoa! Ahhh!</em><br /><br />Delicious.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
