<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Game | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/game/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T10:18:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts Re: Thomas Was Alone]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/thomas-was-alone/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T09:52:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/thomas-was-alone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/twa.png" alt="Screenshot of Thomas Was Alone"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<a href="http://www.mobygames.com/game/windows/thomas-was-alone/screenshots/gameShotId,566500/">via</a>)</p>


<p><em>Thomas Was Alone</em> was super cute, if more ambiguous than I personally like. I liked the personality given to all the different shapes, though their common heroism and conceit got a little old as the game went on, which was why Laura&rsquo;s cynicism made her my favorite (though I felt compelled inexlicably to keep calling her &ldquo;Ruth&rdquo;). I loved that the levels were tilted, the play of light, the strange colors. (Though I wonder if any colorblind users had a hard time playing?)</p>

<p>One thing I think the game could have been improved was the game&rsquo;s sense of progression; though numbers ticked up each level, after a while they became meaningless, and now that the game is finished I&rsquo;m not totally sure what I would use them for. The introduction of each of the colored shapes, Thomas&rsquo;s &ldquo;death,&rdquo; and the era of the gray shapes seemed to be the largest movements in the story, and though each was accompanied with a fun snippet of &ldquo;The AIs are gaining sentience!&rdquo; flavor I didn&rsquo;t really have a sense that things were reaching their end until the end came suddenly to meet me. Some levels seemed like little &ldquo;drabbles&rdquo; and experiments, which I completed without much more effort than would take for me to click a cow in Farmville, and it would have been cool to see something else related to AIs breaking their previous ways of being. Breaking through the borders of levels — intentionally disobeying orders — something to add to the flavor text.</p>

<p>I played <em>Thomas Was Alone</em> on a projector and if you have the opportunity to do so yourself I recommend it. All those rectangles are like way better when they&rsquo;re as big as your face.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
