<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hcde | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/hcde/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T10:18:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Design: UniCycle]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/unicycle/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-09T15:22:52-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/09/unicycle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For HCDE 518 the theme of our projects was &ldquo;UX for Good.&rdquo; I teamed up with three others (Joshua Coppola, Irene Huberman, and Matt Yukubousky) who were interested in solving climate change, and after admitting that &ldquo;solving climate change&rdquo; was going to be out of scope for the quarter, we searched for ways that we could encourage people to make better environmental choices.</p>

<p>One problem in encouraging environmentally friendly choices is that the immediate results of such choices are often negative. Good environmental decisions don&rsquo;t pay off for the actual environment immediately, and often your only tangible &ldquo;reward&rdquo; is the fact that you&rsquo;ve spent more time or money being good, as in the case of going to farmer&rsquo;s markets to buy organic or local produce. (Though for some I know the payoff of farmer&rsquo;s markets is better-tasting food, and forming relationships with the community, etc.)</p>

<p>We were all interested in designing <em>something</em> for our nearby community, and at some point someone finally brought up the concept of &ldquo;freecycling,&rdquo; which is the term for a community that gives and gets items from each other for free. (In this sense, it&rsquo;s really more like &ldquo;free-reusing&rdquo; than &ldquo;free-recycling.&rdquo;) We realized that such a system is perfect for implementation in a college campus, where living situations are temporary and fluid, requiring people to predictably give and get furniture like beds and couches when the academic year turns. Additionally, undergraduates in particular, lacking free-flowing cash, have a need of used items like textbooks and whatever other paraphernalia required of them in classes, like clickers. Groups in Seattle exist already for freecycling, such as <a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/neo/groups/freecycleseattle/info">Seattle Freecycle</a>, but none geared specifically for students who might need to quickly get rid of a bed before move-out, or require a specific edition of a book for a class.</p>

<p>Realizations in hand, we established our design question: <strong>How can we use technology to encourage reuse of goods within the University of Washington community?</strong></p>

<p>And after Bruce Perry came up with the perfect name for our project — <em>UniCycle</em> — we were all in.</p>

<h2>Surveys</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/surveys.png" alt="Screenshot of some survey responses."/></p>

<p class="caption">screenshot of some survey responses</p>


<p>We developed a (somewhat long-ass) survey to kick off our user research, and distributed it across our social networks, the UW group we found at Reddit, and a Facebook group devoted to &ldquo;UW Textbook Exchange.&rdquo; The feedback we received overall to the idea of &ldquo;a site where people can easily exchange textbooks&rdquo; was very positive:</p>

<blockquote>“This idea is great and I hope it takes form soon! It eliminates the middle man like buffalo exchange that rips off the sellers and charges more for certain items to buyers to make profit." - /u/huskygurll</blockquote>


<p>On the bright side, we learned that there are some clear pain points when students try to get rid of their stuff. Though many students desire to sell their textbooks and furniture, many do not because they don&rsquo;t want to go through the hassle of setting up prices, haggling, meeting up with people. In the case of female students, there was also the extra overhead of making sure they were safe when interacting with strangers.</p>

<p>Though we initially wanted to create a site that was devoted to <em>just</em> students giving each other things for free, students' reported consciousness of money made this unfeasible. Survey participants reported occasinally that, if they could not get enough money for Item X, they&rsquo;d rather keep it. With this in mind, we decided to design a hub for students to not just give each other things for free, but also sell or barter them away. &ldquo;Free items&rdquo; could continue to be our main headliner, however, something to draw people in the same way that Priceline draws customers with their &ldquo;name your own price&rdquo; system.</p>

<h2>Design Mapping</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/designmapping.png" alt="Team UniCycle design mapping, and a close-up photo of the design mapping."/></p>

<p class="caption">design mapping</p>


<p>One design technique that was new to be this quarter was <strong>design mapping</strong>, which involves thinking through a user flow and taking note of everything that comes up using sticky notes. Green notes can stand for goals, pink notes for concerns, yellow for extra considerations, blue for possible new features — and so on. One thing I love about design mapping is that you are able to keep track of everything. When talking about how to support Yosh&rsquo;s desire to buy an old couch online, we don&rsquo;t need to silence the person that starts talking about bed bugs, and chastise them for going off-topic — we just add it to the map, and continue forward.</p>

<p>Design mapping helped us get a grip on the kinds of behaviors that we wanted to support with UniCycle: buy a used item, put a used item up for sale, contact a seller, and so on.</p>

<h2>Sketches</h2>


<p>We did a ton of sketches. Just, tons of them.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/sketches2.png" alt="Sketching UniCycle UI on a whiteboard."/></p>

<p class="caption">here are just a few of them</p>


<p>I have to admit that it was hard to come up with so many ideas individually and then have to figure out how to actually move forward. It took us most of the afternoon, a huge whiteboard, and a lot of back-and-forth to decide on the almost-final interface that we wanted to go with, Once we did decide, it was tough to decide who was going to have the responsibility of moving forward with creating a paper prototype, or creating a digital prototype with something like Axure, which some of us wanted experience using.</p>

<p>It was at this time that we decided to try out a search based on &ldquo;hashtags,&rdquo; like Twitter or Tumblr. Because people could sell a variety of items on this site, we thought this would best allow them to categorize their items as they see fit. Additionally, hashtags like <code>#chem300</code> could be catch-alls for whatever you needed for a Chemistry 300 course: textbooks, clickers, lab coats, and so on.</p>

<h2>Paper Prototyping</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/paperprototype.png" alt="Photos of the UniCycle paper prototype."/></p>

<p class="caption">photos of the paper prototype</p>


<p>I took partial responsibility for the paper prototype and the ensuing paper-scrap fest. Rendering the variety of items that people could &ldquo;search for&rdquo; using our paper UI was the most challenging bit, as was searching for the right pieces to show on the display. We created little modals to mimic &ldquo;Loading results&hellip;&rdquo; which were fun to use, and we also tried to solve for cases in which our paper prototype testers might search for an item that we didn&rsquo;t anticipate.</p>

<h2>Interactive Prototype</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/unicycle/unicycle_prototype.png" alt="Screenshot of UniCycle Interactive Prototype."/></p>

<p class="caption">screenshot of UniCycle's interactive prototype</p>


<p>Our final product was an interactive prototype made in Axure by all of us, using a pretty fantastic blend of Axure&rsquo;s built-in SVN versioning and Dropbox. It is currently hosted <a href="http://students.washington.edu/jhc1/hcde518/start.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>My most beloved aspects of it are those that give feedback to users' actions. For example, the main page features tickets that enumerate the number of goods reused thus far, to surface the fact that people really <em>are</em> accomplishing something great through their small actions.</p>

<p>We also have some special tweaks just for UW students. For example, if you are looking for a particular textbook, you can list it on UniCycle. If you&rsquo;re selling, you can list a book by ISBN and have the titles and authors filled in automatically. Once you list a book, you are also made aware of the number of people who might already have that book marked as &ldquo;wanted&rdquo; — which is intended to help people feel like it&rsquo;s easy to sell on UniCycle. We also surface &ldquo;duedates&rdquo; for items, valuable if a user is trying to get rid of a bed before their lease is up.</p>

<p>After having dealt with it for a majority of the quarter, I&rsquo;m not totally sold on Axure yet, and will not likely use it to personally make hi-fidelity prototypes in the future. At that point in the process, I&rsquo;d just prefer to code things up myself. Additionally, I personally love the speed and humble honesty of paper prototyping, compared to Axure&rsquo;s interactive prototypes, which to me slip somewhat into the uncanny valley.</p>

<p>That being said, I&rsquo;m sure there will come a time when Axure is uniquely valuable, and I did like having to <em>not</em> worry about vertically centering random elements in CSS. Coding UniCycle as the sole programmer in a team of four would have been extremely taxing and it&rsquo;s nice that using Axure allowed us to work on a level playing field.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>


<p>I don&rsquo;t know that I&rsquo;ll return to UniCycle given the plethora of other projects I have, but it would be great to see it go places, especially given the need for it at UW. Too much goes wasted, and I&rsquo;d love to see people get into the habit of asking their community for needed items, as well as help others when it&rsquo;s needed.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also made a <a href="/files/hcde518_portfolio_deck.pdf">portfolio deck</a> that goes over other details for this project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cultural Differences Across Pokemon X & Y Websites]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s1600/pokemonxy.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s640/pokemonxy.jpg" width="510" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshots of the websites for Pokemon X &amp; Y<br />Japan (above), Netherlands (bottom)</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1">A couple weeks ago we analyzed the marketing sites for Pokemon X and Y across different countries. It turns out that all sites for Pokemon X and Y are the same — except for the one in Japan, which is shown at the top of the screenshot above.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">The differences between the Japanese site and the rest-of-the-world sites include:</div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><h4>Feature Descriptions</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain more information about the game, for example, direct links to features like the Pokemon Global Link; on the Japanese site, these are internal.</div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Hype</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites feature a large image carousel on their homepage, which shows other features of the game, all shown to excite:&nbsp;<i>Discover the Might of Mega-Evolved Pokemon! A New World of Amazing Pokemon!</i></div><div><i><br /></i></div><div>In contrast, the front page of the Japanese site merely says:&nbsp;<i>Pokemon, heading to a brand new dimension</i>! (Referring, I think, to the 3D?)</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Obvious Marketing</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain immediate links to buy the game, as well as the 3DS; the Japanese site does not. (According to Julius, the 2DS isn't even available in Japan, perhaps because "Everyone there already has a 3DS!")</div></div><div><h4><br /></h4><h4>JavaScript</h4><div>The Japanese site has very little Javascript, and each page looks to be straight HTML. Additionally, text is often baked straight into the images, rather than being left as straight text, which is often the case in websites due to accessibility issues. (Text on images cannot be easily parsed by screenreaders. Some users also prefer to render text on websites to be more readable, for example, through the excellent&nbsp;<a href="http://www.beelinereader.com/">BeeLine</a>&nbsp;app.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Description vs. Instruction</h4><div>The Japanese site is more descriptive of the story and characters of the game; the non-Japanese site is more instructive of how to play the Pokemon game.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div class="p1">We chalked up the majority of the differences the fact that Pokemon is more popular in Japan; Japanese game-players may not need to be particularly taught about Pokemon, or persuaded to buy it. But, this exercise makes me more interested in other facets of Japanese web design. Why is there so much baked-in text, why aren't there fancy hover menu states, why is the design so flat compared to the chrome and bevels of the non-Japanese sites? Is web accessibility less important in the Japanese corner of the internet, or is it handled in a way that's different in the US?</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">One final note: out class lecture that week was done by Kate Edwards, current Executive Director of IGDA, who shared some cool stories regarding the "culturization" problems she's encountered when helping to ship games across international borders. Something she noted was that, in the Netherlands, "adult" games don't need to be localized into Dutch because the adults there prefer to play the games in English. So, the fact that the Pokemon X and Y site text is all written in Dutch…</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><br /><div class="p1">…well…you can totally still enjoy the world of Kalos as a grown-up grad student with a full-time job. Just saying!</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical Foundations of HCDE]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/03/19/theoretical-foundations-of-hcde/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/03/19/theoretical-foundations-of-hcde</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've been spending the past couple of weeks finishing up winter quarter. &nbsp;I took "Theoretical Foundations of Human-Centered Design and Engineering," in which I broke everything that I had assumed about HCDE's underlying theories, and then reconstructed it again, more tentatively. &nbsp;The essence of the class is this:<br /><br />HCDE is multidisciplinary. &nbsp;HCDE is the swordsman, archer, mage, token female healer, your entire roleplaying party <i>in one subject</i>. &nbsp;As such, the people who develop theories and "rules of thumb" for HCDE all come from varying backgrounds; you can find things relevant to HCDE across a range of journals and conference papers, from cognitive science to sociology to computer science. &nbsp;An advantage of this is the incredible breadth of information that goes into the formulation of this beautiful HCI thingcreature; a disadvantage is that everyone has different ideas of what HCDE should be, and sometimes not a clear idea of where to go <i>next</i>&nbsp;with the study of HCDE, since all our knowledge of it is so spread out. &nbsp;Just imagine what physics would have been like without everyone agreeing on that first instrumental apple-fall, much less talking about it with the same words.<br /><br />We learned about a handful of theories, most of which you can learn about on our group website, <a href="http://neauro.com/hcde501/">HCDE Bistro</a>, which aims to make these potentially&nbsp;mind-boggling&nbsp;theories digestible for the mental palate. &nbsp;In general.<br /><br />In the end, I didn't find myself particularly "aligning" with any theory as the end-all foundational theory for HCDE, but activity theory and semiotic engineering resonated with me in particular. &nbsp;Activity theory runs off the idea that humans have "needs" that they satisfy through interacting with the word (such as a "need" to eat to sustain oneself), and that their activities are performed with <i>intention</i>. &nbsp;Semiotic engineering frames design artifacts as objects of "discourse" through which the designer has a conversation with a user, with the goal being that the user should learn how to perform their tasks more effectively. &nbsp;Semiotic engineering to me sounded quite a bit like game design -- an artifact which is meant to communicate with a user and teach them best practices? &nbsp;Sign me uuup.<br /><br />At the end of the class we were to write a paper, and mine was about what a combined perspective of semiotic engineering and activity theory can help one understand about <strike>players</strike> users learning about how to work with a design beyond "this button does X." &nbsp;It is located <a href="http://neauro.com/hcde501/activityengineering.pdf">here</a>.<br /><br />In conclusion: HCDE has a lot of people asking questions of it. &nbsp;How do I best design for this person, this situation, with this technology? &nbsp;Activity Theory answers, <i>It depends on what the person's intentions are</i>; Distributed Cognition answers that&nbsp;<i>It depends on what other people or objects the person relies on to think and remember things</i>; Semiotic Engineering answers that&nbsp;<i>It depends on what the person learns from the designer's artifact</i>; and so on.<br /><br />HCDE: five hundred ways to say <i>It depends</i>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes I Wish Academic Papers Were Just Collections of Bullet Points]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/05/sometimes-i-wish-academic-papers-were/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/05/sometimes-i-wish-academic-papers-were</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<blockquote><h3>The analysis of activity from a computational perspective that brings out the mechanisms by which representational transformations are coordinated cannot be applied to the design of computer and [Computer-Supported Cooperative Work] in a straightforward manner. </h3><br /> <i>Perry, M. (2003) "Distributed Cognition."</i></blockquote></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HCDE 501 Notes: HCI's Search for Foundational Theory]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/09/hcde-501-notes-hcis-search-for/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/09/hcde-501-notes-hcis-search-for</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
The field of Human-Computer Interaction started in the 1980s, borne of cognitive and computer science.  It started with the idea that humans and computers both have behaviors that are algorithmic, and at a human's heart is a little processor chipping away at data and outputting actions accordingly.  Around this time, Xerox came out with The Graphical User Interface. &nbsp;It was a novel framework for user interaction, and people were like, "Whoa!" And thus was cognitive science applied to improving GUIs by the millions.<br /><br />Soon, however, people became dissatisfied.  HCI as it was, hand-in-hand with cognitive sciences, was as limited as a college girl off at Ivy League and still dating someone in senior year of high school.  They had a lot of good moments the past year, they had some times that were defining of each other's identity, but in the end, HCI just needed to broaden out, because humans don't have processor hearts.  Suchman (in <em>Plans and Situated Actions</em>) was arguing with AI researchers in the dorm hallway and HCI, having left her door open for potential visitors, overheard.<br /><br />"Human action is 'situated,'" Suchman said.  Humans respond to opportunity when it knocks, and are flexible to a change in resources.  "Computer programs may follow algorithms, but people do not."<br /><br />"Just look," Suchman said, "at all these people who struggled with the design of this photocopier (1987).  If people were <em>truly</em> algorithmic, they would have tried to solve their usability problems in the same way." Alas, everyone found their way to hatred of this copy-machine in a multitude of ways.<br /><br />This idea, this <em>situatedness</em>, drew right from Ethnomethodology, the guy in the opposite hallway, who grew up with nice sociology parents but had somehow turned out to be unusually rebellious and anti-theoretical.  He was all about moment-by-moment actions analyzed as reponses to events in a "local scene of action." He was all about figuring out what made you (or groups of you) tick, and making you efficient, consistent, coherent.  He was best friends with Anthropology, whose whole life was about having comprehensive knowledge about every acquaintance and passerby.<br /><br />Ethnomethodology was pretty cool, but his parents never got over it.  They couldn't compromise.  They tried to keep other people away from him, and to this day Ethnomethodology remained relegated to "a radical antitheory position."  His wish to work above generalization and abstraction were shoved into a corner, and eventually even Anthropology, once a wide-eyed fact-hoarder, left and became theoretical herself.<br /><br />It was alright.  Ethnomethodology continued.  He focused.  He loved conversation, eventually produced rules about it: "turn-taking," "repair," "back-channeling." In doing so he embraced something his parents had always wanted: generalization.  Soon he was spouting things like "highlighting for perception" and "professional vision," and every multi-syllable ambiguity sent him an inch further down "the slippery slope of theorizing."<br /><br />But it wasn't enough for the kind of foundational theory HCI was really looking for.  HCI hung out with him a couple times, but as the years went on their interactions degenerated from brief hellos, strained smalltalk, unanswered Facebook Event invites.  Ethnomethodology had an "attitude of indifference" which didn't seem that stable.  HCI kept a memory of empirical studies, of software usage data, but eventually all those nights she spent with him underneath the moon, talking -- just, <em>talking</em>, about anything -- faded.<br /><br />HCI <i>needed</i> that foundational theory. &nbsp;She wanted to learn more, not just about herself and her many facets (Psychology, Sociology, Computer Science, and so on), but about what she wanted to <em>do</em> with her life.  It wasn't so much about trying to make all these different parts of her speak on the same level, but more about having an understanding of her own identity above them all.  Without theory she couldn't compare the past to the present, couldn't learn about whether she was really becoming better.  She couldn't know whether her next step forward was actually a step back.  She couldn't know whether some pet peeve of hers was typical, couldn't decide what was important.<br /><br />Without theory, she couldn't be as good as Science, who was not useful because she was always real or always right, but because she was always helpful and wanted.  Science could stumble, could even make mistakes: but even those missteps led to progress.<br /><br /><br /><br />Source:<br />Kaptelini &amp; Nardi, <em>Acting with Technology: Activity Theory and Interaction Design.</em> 2009.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
