<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hcde | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/hcde/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-10T08:28:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cultural Differences Across Pokemon X & Y Websites]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s1600/pokemonxy.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s640/pokemonxy.jpg" width="510" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshots of the websites for Pokemon X &amp; Y<br />Japan (above), Netherlands (bottom)</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1">A couple weeks ago we analyzed the marketing sites for Pokemon X and Y across different countries. It turns out that all sites for Pokemon X and Y are the same — except for the one in Japan, which is shown at the top of the screenshot above.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">The differences between the Japanese site and the rest-of-the-world sites include:</div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><h4>Feature Descriptions</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain more information about the game, for example, direct links to features like the Pokemon Global Link; on the Japanese site, these are internal.</div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Hype</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites feature a large image carousel on their homepage, which shows other features of the game, all shown to excite:&nbsp;<i>Discover the Might of Mega-Evolved Pokemon! A New World of Amazing Pokemon!</i></div><div><i><br /></i></div><div>In contrast, the front page of the Japanese site merely says:&nbsp;<i>Pokemon, heading to a brand new dimension</i>! (Referring, I think, to the 3D?)</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Obvious Marketing</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain immediate links to buy the game, as well as the 3DS; the Japanese site does not. (According to Julius, the 2DS isn't even available in Japan, perhaps because "Everyone there already has a 3DS!")</div></div><div><h4><br /></h4><h4>JavaScript</h4><div>The Japanese site has very little Javascript, and each page looks to be straight HTML. Additionally, text is often baked straight into the images, rather than being left as straight text, which is often the case in websites due to accessibility issues. (Text on images cannot be easily parsed by screenreaders. Some users also prefer to render text on websites to be more readable, for example, through the excellent&nbsp;<a href="http://www.beelinereader.com/">BeeLine</a>&nbsp;app.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Description vs. Instruction</h4><div>The Japanese site is more descriptive of the story and characters of the game; the non-Japanese site is more instructive of how to play the Pokemon game.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div class="p1">We chalked up the majority of the differences the fact that Pokemon is more popular in Japan; Japanese game-players may not need to be particularly taught about Pokemon, or persuaded to buy it. But, this exercise makes me more interested in other facets of Japanese web design. Why is there so much baked-in text, why aren't there fancy hover menu states, why is the design so flat compared to the chrome and bevels of the non-Japanese sites? Is web accessibility less important in the Japanese corner of the internet, or is it handled in a way that's different in the US?</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">One final note: out class lecture that week was done by Kate Edwards, current Executive Director of IGDA, who shared some cool stories regarding the "culturization" problems she's encountered when helping to ship games across international borders. Something she noted was that, in the Netherlands, "adult" games don't need to be localized into Dutch because the adults there prefer to play the games in English. So, the fact that the Pokemon X and Y site text is all written in Dutch…</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><br /><div class="p1">…well…you can totally still enjoy the world of Kalos as a grown-up grad student with a full-time job. Just saying!</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Theoretical Foundations of HCDE]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/03/19/theoretical-foundations-of-hcde/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/03/19/theoretical-foundations-of-hcde</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've been spending the past couple of weeks finishing up winter quarter. &nbsp;I took "Theoretical Foundations of Human-Centered Design and Engineering," in which I broke everything that I had assumed about HCDE's underlying theories, and then reconstructed it again, more tentatively. &nbsp;The essence of the class is this:<br /><br />HCDE is multidisciplinary. &nbsp;HCDE is the swordsman, archer, mage, token female healer, your entire roleplaying party <i>in one subject</i>. &nbsp;As such, the people who develop theories and "rules of thumb" for HCDE all come from varying backgrounds; you can find things relevant to HCDE across a range of journals and conference papers, from cognitive science to sociology to computer science. &nbsp;An advantage of this is the incredible breadth of information that goes into the formulation of this beautiful HCI thingcreature; a disadvantage is that everyone has different ideas of what HCDE should be, and sometimes not a clear idea of where to go <i>next</i>&nbsp;with the study of HCDE, since all our knowledge of it is so spread out. &nbsp;Just imagine what physics would have been like without everyone agreeing on that first instrumental apple-fall, much less talking about it with the same words.<br /><br />We learned about a handful of theories, most of which you can learn about on our group website, <a href="http://neauro.com/hcde501/">HCDE Bistro</a>, which aims to make these potentially&nbsp;mind-boggling&nbsp;theories digestible for the mental palate. &nbsp;In general.<br /><br />In the end, I didn't find myself particularly "aligning" with any theory as the end-all foundational theory for HCDE, but activity theory and semiotic engineering resonated with me in particular. &nbsp;Activity theory runs off the idea that humans have "needs" that they satisfy through interacting with the word (such as a "need" to eat to sustain oneself), and that their activities are performed with <i>intention</i>. &nbsp;Semiotic engineering frames design artifacts as objects of "discourse" through which the designer has a conversation with a user, with the goal being that the user should learn how to perform their tasks more effectively. &nbsp;Semiotic engineering to me sounded quite a bit like game design -- an artifact which is meant to communicate with a user and teach them best practices? &nbsp;Sign me uuup.<br /><br />At the end of the class we were to write a paper, and mine was about what a combined perspective of semiotic engineering and activity theory can help one understand about <strike>players</strike> users learning about how to work with a design beyond "this button does X." &nbsp;It is located <a href="http://neauro.com/hcde501/activityengineering.pdf">here</a>.<br /><br />In conclusion: HCDE has a lot of people asking questions of it. &nbsp;How do I best design for this person, this situation, with this technology? &nbsp;Activity Theory answers, <i>It depends on what the person's intentions are</i>; Distributed Cognition answers that&nbsp;<i>It depends on what other people or objects the person relies on to think and remember things</i>; Semiotic Engineering answers that&nbsp;<i>It depends on what the person learns from the designer's artifact</i>; and so on.<br /><br />HCDE: five hundred ways to say <i>It depends</i>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes I Wish Academic Papers Were Just Collections of Bullet Points]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/05/sometimes-i-wish-academic-papers-were/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/05/sometimes-i-wish-academic-papers-were</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<blockquote><h3>The analysis of activity from a computational perspective that brings out the mechanisms by which representational transformations are coordinated cannot be applied to the design of computer and [Computer-Supported Cooperative Work] in a straightforward manner. </h3><br /> <i>Perry, M. (2003) "Distributed Cognition."</i></blockquote></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HCDE 501 Notes: HCI's Search for Foundational Theory]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/01/09/hcde-501-notes-hcis-search-for/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/01/09/hcde-501-notes-hcis-search-for</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
The field of Human-Computer Interaction started in the 1980s, borne of cognitive and computer science.  It started with the idea that humans and computers both have behaviors that are algorithmic, and at a human's heart is a little processor chipping away at data and outputting actions accordingly.  Around this time, Xerox came out with The Graphical User Interface. &nbsp;It was a novel framework for user interaction, and people were like, "Whoa!" And thus was cognitive science applied to improving GUIs by the millions.<br /><br />Soon, however, people became dissatisfied.  HCI as it was, hand-in-hand with cognitive sciences, was as limited as a college girl off at Ivy League and still dating someone in senior year of high school.  They had a lot of good moments the past year, they had some times that were defining of each other's identity, but in the end, HCI just needed to broaden out, because humans don't have processor hearts.  Suchman (in <em>Plans and Situated Actions</em>) was arguing with AI researchers in the dorm hallway and HCI, having left her door open for potential visitors, overheard.<br /><br />"Human action is 'situated,'" Suchman said.  Humans respond to opportunity when it knocks, and are flexible to a change in resources.  "Computer programs may follow algorithms, but people do not."<br /><br />"Just look," Suchman said, "at all these people who struggled with the design of this photocopier (1987).  If people were <em>truly</em> algorithmic, they would have tried to solve their usability problems in the same way." Alas, everyone found their way to hatred of this copy-machine in a multitude of ways.<br /><br />This idea, this <em>situatedness</em>, drew right from Ethnomethodology, the guy in the opposite hallway, who grew up with nice sociology parents but had somehow turned out to be unusually rebellious and anti-theoretical.  He was all about moment-by-moment actions analyzed as reponses to events in a "local scene of action." He was all about figuring out what made you (or groups of you) tick, and making you efficient, consistent, coherent.  He was best friends with Anthropology, whose whole life was about having comprehensive knowledge about every acquaintance and passerby.<br /><br />Ethnomethodology was pretty cool, but his parents never got over it.  They couldn't compromise.  They tried to keep other people away from him, and to this day Ethnomethodology remained relegated to "a radical antitheory position."  His wish to work above generalization and abstraction were shoved into a corner, and eventually even Anthropology, once a wide-eyed fact-hoarder, left and became theoretical herself.<br /><br />It was alright.  Ethnomethodology continued.  He focused.  He loved conversation, eventually produced rules about it: "turn-taking," "repair," "back-channeling." In doing so he embraced something his parents had always wanted: generalization.  Soon he was spouting things like "highlighting for perception" and "professional vision," and every multi-syllable ambiguity sent him an inch further down "the slippery slope of theorizing."<br /><br />But it wasn't enough for the kind of foundational theory HCI was really looking for.  HCI hung out with him a couple times, but as the years went on their interactions degenerated from brief hellos, strained smalltalk, unanswered Facebook Event invites.  Ethnomethodology had an "attitude of indifference" which didn't seem that stable.  HCI kept a memory of empirical studies, of software usage data, but eventually all those nights she spent with him underneath the moon, talking -- just, <em>talking</em>, about anything -- faded.<br /><br />HCI <i>needed</i> that foundational theory. &nbsp;She wanted to learn more, not just about herself and her many facets (Psychology, Sociology, Computer Science, and so on), but about what she wanted to <em>do</em> with her life.  It wasn't so much about trying to make all these different parts of her speak on the same level, but more about having an understanding of her own identity above them all.  Without theory she couldn't compare the past to the present, couldn't learn about whether she was really becoming better.  She couldn't know whether her next step forward was actually a step back.  She couldn't know whether some pet peeve of hers was typical, couldn't decide what was important.<br /><br />Without theory, she couldn't be as good as Science, who was not useful because she was always real or always right, but because she was always helpful and wanted.  Science could stumble, could even make mistakes: but even those missteps led to progress.<br /><br /><br /><br />Source:<br />Kaptelini &amp; Nardi, <em>Acting with Technology: Activity Theory and Interaction Design.</em> 2009.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No One Is Safe]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/11/21/no-one-is-safe/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/11/21/no-one-is-safe</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
From <em>Re-Space-ing Place: "Place" and "Space" Ten Years On</em>:<br /><blockquote>My goal [in this paper] is to understand two related developments over the last decade. <strong>One is the way in which the conceptual distinction between place and space has been taken up by [computer-supported cooperative work] researchers</strong>, and to see what kinds of light we might be able to cast on this by returning to the roots of this distinction in fields such as geography and urban studies that have something to say about the social organization of spaces. The other is the ways in which our heightened understanding of the issues of mobility and information as an aspect of everyday life, emerging out of studies and experiences with mobile technologies, might reinvigorate a conceptual exploration of questions of practice and spatiality, and help us deepen our understandings of the implications of arguments about place and space.<br /></blockquote><br />I'm always surprised by HCI's pure ability to study People Doing Things, whether its people out living their lives in the world, or <em>other people studying HCI.</em></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
