<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Kindle | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/kindle/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T20:13:04-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Have Just Discovered the World-shattering Usefulness Of]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/03/21/i-have-just-discovered-world-shattering/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/03/21/i-have-just-discovered-world-shattering</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://www.instapaper.com/">Instapaper</a>, which allows you to bookmark webpages to "Read Later," and batch-convert them into a Kindle-compatible file. Gone are the days when tantalizing articles found during the workday were e-mailed to myself and remained niggling and unread in my e-mail inbox. &nbsp;You can even sent e-mails themselves to be batch-converted! &nbsp;(Not that I feel tempted to do this, the computer-less world being my refuge from my e-mail inbox.)<br /><br />I mentioned this with excitement later to someone else who replied, "I already can do something like this with my iPad," but my love for simple e-ink which doesn't inspire theft on public transportation stands.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Owning a Kindle in Seattle as a Student]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/01/owning-kindle-in-seattle-as-student/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/01/owning-kindle-in-seattle-as-student</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-e7bdL7k_Dc0/Tx5Y6nhukPI/AAAAAAAAAoE/Uj4vbQx1NIA/s1600/KT-slate-02-lg._V166940136_.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="308" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-e7bdL7k_Dc0/Tx5Y6nhukPI/AAAAAAAAAoE/Uj4vbQx1NIA/s320/KT-slate-02-lg._V166940136_.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Kindle-eReader-eBook-Reader-e-Reader-Special-Offers/dp/B0051QVESA">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I thought that my loyalty to books would last -- I thought I would shun anything else that lacked their comforting weight, their pulpy baleen. &nbsp;And still I found myself drawn uncomfortably to the Amazon page for the Kindle for months, thinking, <i>Should I...?</i><br /><br /><i>No way. &nbsp;There are already so many physical books! &nbsp;So many!</i><br /><br />I finally relented after realizing that you can read PDFs on a Kindle, which is nice because my course this quarter requires a <i>lot</i>&nbsp;of reading, most of which I can no longer print out for free at the CSE undergrad labs. &nbsp;Squinting at scanned inky text on a screen that can sear it into your vision long after you've actually stopped reading is unpleasant, and so, Kindle.<br /><br />I learned then quickly of the resources available to Kindle users who belong in my particular demographic, that is, a student in Seattle:<br /><br /><h3>  You can get Amazon Prime for half its normal yearly fee.</h3>Students can pay half the standard $80 fee per year for free two-day shipping and access to Amazon's Kindle Lending Library, which can be browsed on a Kindle or online <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/search/ref=sr_nr_p_n_feature_browse-b_mrr_2?rh=n%3A283155%2Cp_85%3A2470955011%2Cp_n_feature_browse-bin%3A618073011&amp;bbn=283155&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1320670642&amp;rnid=618072011?tag=publishmarket-20">here</a>.  It says that you can borrow a book a month, but I think (<em>think</em>) that you can borrow a single book per month, but return it if you want to get another book before the time is up.  I am unclear on this and cannot completely verify yet, having difficulties finding the answer and also having not loaned out anything for a complete month yet.  The collection is enormous and what you'll notice about it immediately is the presence of The Hunger Games, the poster child of the Lending Library, a little medal of, <em>Look!  There are even recent, popular books here!  For free (for $49/year)!</em><br /><br /><h3>  You can borrow ebooks from the Seattle Public Library.</h3>The waiting lists are long, but there are enough "unpopular" books to tide you over until the holds let up.  You can have holds on 25 books maximum.  You can borrow 25 books maximum, each for up to 21 days maximum.  Here's the tricky thing that took me an annoying while to figure out: returning books is not done through the Seattle Public Library's <a href="http://spl.lib.overdrive.com/">online site</a>, but through the "Manage Your Kindle" link on Amazon.com.<br /><br />Browsing the ebook collection is also frustratingly tedious -- more on that later.  Suffice to say that browsing ebooks is something I reserve for mindlessly doing between builds.<br /><br /><h3>  There are tons of public domain books available on Amazon for free.</h3>They are odds and ends of things, but I really enjoy random tidbits like <em>Character</em> and <em>Home Vegetable Gardening -a Complete and Practical Guide to the Planting and Care of All Vegetables, Fruits and Berries Worth Growing for Home Use</em>, so, <a href="http://www.blogger.com/The%20http://www.amazon.com/s?ie=UTF8&amp;node=154606011&amp;redirect=true&amp;sort=daterank&amp;field-price=0-0">there</a> you go!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
