<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Misc | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T10:18:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Valentine's Day!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/14/happy-valentines-day/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/14/happy-valentines-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-L0g3kptX3tw/TzqSLgiURRI/AAAAAAAAAp8/SnmysZkNPHw/s1600/loveletter.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="240" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-L0g3kptX3tw/TzqSLgiURRI/AAAAAAAAAp8/SnmysZkNPHw/s320/loveletter.png" width="320" /></a></div><br />Celebrate it by checking out Alex's newly (and appropriately) released game, <a href="http://axcho.com/theloveletter/">The Love Letter</a>.  He also wrote about his endeavors <a href="http://evolutionlive.blogspot.com/2012/02/love-letter-released.html">here</a>.<br /><br />Other interesting fact I learned from Alex: the art is inspired partly a poster from <a href="http://ifartrainbow.com/">Enfu</a>&nbsp;-- you can tell by the outlines, which are dark blue rather than black!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Owning a Kindle in Seattle as a Student]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/01/owning-kindle-in-seattle-as-student/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/01/owning-kindle-in-seattle-as-student</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-e7bdL7k_Dc0/Tx5Y6nhukPI/AAAAAAAAAoE/Uj4vbQx1NIA/s1600/KT-slate-02-lg._V166940136_.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="308" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-e7bdL7k_Dc0/Tx5Y6nhukPI/AAAAAAAAAoE/Uj4vbQx1NIA/s320/KT-slate-02-lg._V166940136_.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Kindle-eReader-eBook-Reader-e-Reader-Special-Offers/dp/B0051QVESA">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I thought that my loyalty to books would last -- I thought I would shun anything else that lacked their comforting weight, their pulpy baleen. &nbsp;And still I found myself drawn uncomfortably to the Amazon page for the Kindle for months, thinking, <i>Should I...?</i><br /><br /><i>No way. &nbsp;There are already so many physical books! &nbsp;So many!</i><br /><br />I finally relented after realizing that you can read PDFs on a Kindle, which is nice because my course this quarter requires a <i>lot</i>&nbsp;of reading, most of which I can no longer print out for free at the CSE undergrad labs. &nbsp;Squinting at scanned inky text on a screen that can sear it into your vision long after you've actually stopped reading is unpleasant, and so, Kindle.<br /><br />I learned then quickly of the resources available to Kindle users who belong in my particular demographic, that is, a student in Seattle:<br /><br /><h3>  You can get Amazon Prime for half its normal yearly fee.</h3>Students can pay half the standard $80 fee per year for free two-day shipping and access to Amazon's Kindle Lending Library, which can be browsed on a Kindle or online <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/search/ref=sr_nr_p_n_feature_browse-b_mrr_2?rh=n%3A283155%2Cp_85%3A2470955011%2Cp_n_feature_browse-bin%3A618073011&amp;bbn=283155&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1320670642&amp;rnid=618072011?tag=publishmarket-20">here</a>.  It says that you can borrow a book a month, but I think (<em>think</em>) that you can borrow a single book per month, but return it if you want to get another book before the time is up.  I am unclear on this and cannot completely verify yet, having difficulties finding the answer and also having not loaned out anything for a complete month yet.  The collection is enormous and what you'll notice about it immediately is the presence of The Hunger Games, the poster child of the Lending Library, a little medal of, <em>Look!  There are even recent, popular books here!  For free (for $49/year)!</em><br /><br /><h3>  You can borrow ebooks from the Seattle Public Library.</h3>The waiting lists are long, but there are enough "unpopular" books to tide you over until the holds let up.  You can have holds on 25 books maximum.  You can borrow 25 books maximum, each for up to 21 days maximum.  Here's the tricky thing that took me an annoying while to figure out: returning books is not done through the Seattle Public Library's <a href="http://spl.lib.overdrive.com/">online site</a>, but through the "Manage Your Kindle" link on Amazon.com.<br /><br />Browsing the ebook collection is also frustratingly tedious -- more on that later.  Suffice to say that browsing ebooks is something I reserve for mindlessly doing between builds.<br /><br /><h3>  There are tons of public domain books available on Amazon for free.</h3>They are odds and ends of things, but I really enjoy random tidbits like <em>Character</em> and <em>Home Vegetable Gardening -a Complete and Practical Guide to the Planting and Care of All Vegetables, Fruits and Berries Worth Growing for Home Use</em>, so, <a href="http://www.blogger.com/The%20http://www.amazon.com/s?ie=UTF8&amp;node=154606011&amp;redirect=true&amp;sort=daterank&amp;field-price=0-0">there</a> you go!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodreads Ratings]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/23/goodreads-ratings/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/23/goodreads-ratings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--czAH4cCqME/Tx5KxR4KxbI/AAAAAAAAAn0/cI6PcDeoEXI/s1600/goodreads.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--czAH4cCqME/Tx5KxR4KxbI/AAAAAAAAAn0/cI6PcDeoEXI/s1600/goodreads.jpg" /></a></div><br />I've been a member of it since 2008, but it wasn't until recently that I found any affection for <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/">Goodreads</a>, a social networking website based on readers and writers. &nbsp;I haven't been able to find many people to interact with on it; for me, the greatest value is simply in being able to keep a list of books that I've read, and how much I like them, based on a simple scale of 1 to 5 stars.<br /><br />A scale of 1 to 5 is pretty limited, but can still mean different things to everyone, which is why I like that Goodreads has a little dialog hover helpfully over the stars when you're judging them. &nbsp;1 star, it says, stands for <i>I&nbsp;didn't like it.</i>&nbsp; 2, for <i>It was OK. &nbsp;</i>3: <i>I liked it.</i>&nbsp; 4: <i>I really liked it.</i>&nbsp; And 5: <i>It was amazing.</i><br /><br />My personal rating system goes like this:<br /><br /><ul><li>1 -- <i>I didn't like it.</i> &nbsp;This book made me ill. &nbsp;Reading it may have caused my opinion of humanity to degrade. &nbsp;I would grimace when remembering it, and anti-recommend it, fiercely. &nbsp;Examples: <i>Wild Animus, Bloodborn, Hot Gimmick S.</i></li><li>2 -- <i>It was okay.</i> &nbsp;I wouldn't read it again or recommend it, but there was some slight redeeming quality about it, even if it was just that it featured a fetish motif (ex. shapeshifters). &nbsp;Examples: <i>Other, Abandoned, Dead Until Dark.</i></li><li>3 -- <i>I liked</i>&nbsp;<i>it.</i>&nbsp; Reserved for books which kept me turning pages, but in the end were really just so-so. &nbsp;Examples: <i>Pants on Fire, A Lion Among Men, The Eye of the World.</i></li><li>4 -- <i>I really liked it.</i>&nbsp; Given to books which kept me hungry for more, and<i>&nbsp;</i>were well-written, and had me sitting back dazed for a little after finishing.&nbsp;Examples:&nbsp;<i>Delirium, Wintergirls, The Alchemist.</i></li><li>5 -- <i>It was amazing. </i>&nbsp;My label for books that <i>changed my life,</i>&nbsp;whether in terms of writing style, basic habits, or perceptions of morality/reality/x-ality. &nbsp;Examples being: <i>The Time-Traveler's Wife, Perdido Street Station, The Omnivore's Dilemma.</i></li></ul><div><br /></div><div>I read a quote somewhere I can't find now; the point of it was that it is unproductive to read a book and then wonder to yourself whether you liked it or not. &nbsp;My takeaway from the idea was that judgment is less productive than analysis -- that is, it's infinitely better to say, <i>"I liked X for Y reasons,"</i>&nbsp;both for yourself and for the writer as well, since the writer is given the opportunity to improve. &nbsp;But as Goodreads is a social network not just for readers but for writers (with little qualifying labels next to their names), I hesitate at leaving qualitative feedback. &nbsp;Writers are real! &nbsp;And they have feelings! &nbsp;I don't want to hurt those. &nbsp;Plus, popular books often have a multitude of reviews praising this or decrying that; I can't see myself adding anything of value to the discussions, especially when ratings in these cases have usually fallen into an equilibrium rating of 4 or so.<br /><br />I'll finish with a quote from <i>A Room of One's Own</i>&nbsp;by Virginia Woolf:</div><blockquote>At any rate, where books are concerned, it is notoriously difficult to fix labels of merit in such a way that they do not come off.  Are not reviews of current literature a perpetual illustration of the difficulty of judgment?  "This great book," "this worthless book," the same book is called by both names.  Praise and blame alike mean nothing.  No, delightful as the pastime of measuring may be, it is the most futile of all occupations, and to submit to the decrees of the measurers the most servile of attitudes.  So long as you write what you wish to write, that is all that matters; and whether it matters for ages or only for hours, nobody can say.</blockquote></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Jobs' 2005 Stanford Commencement Address]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/10/06/steve-jobs-2005-stanford-commencement/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/10/06/steve-jobs-2005-stanford-commencement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<br /><center><iframe width="420" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UF8uR6Z6KLc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></center><br /><blockquote>Sometimes life's gonna hit you in the head with a brick -- don't lose faith.  I'm convinced that the only thing that kept me going was that I loved what I did.  You've got to find what you love, and that is as true for work as it is for your lovers.  Your work is going to fill a large part of your life, and the only way to be truly satisfied is to do what you believe is great work.  And the only way to do great work is to love what you do.  If you haven't found it yet, keep looking, and don't settle.  As with all matters of the heart, you'll know when you find it.  And like any great relationship, it just gets better and better as the years roll on.  So keep looking.  Don't settle.<br /><br />Remembering that you are going to die is the best way I know to avoid the trap of thinking you have something to lose.  You are already naked.  There is no reason not to follow your heart.</blockquote><br /><br />My first class this week for my HCDE program started with the usual ice breakers, and led eventually to our professor hauling out dozens of <em>Wired</em> magazines from the early 90s, just as oddly textured and bright neon as the <em>Wired</em> magazines of present day.  One of the first things that I saw in my Septemer 1998 issue was an advertisement for FAT32, Microsoft's newest, fastest and most efficient file system.  One of the main features of this particular issue was Furby, and there was also a smaller article whose intent was to "debunk memes;" Bluetooth, it said, was estimated to be a hot topic for about the next 24 months, and would only really be marketable once portable devices like PDAs came to be everywhere.  <em>And even then, people looking to move data between gadgets might find it hard to sever their emotional connection to the entrenched wireline option.</em><br /><br />We started sharing articles.  Someone mentioned that in his issue, Apple was bringing back Steve Jobs as a consultant, and our professor said, "And that pretty much saved the company, didn't it?"<br /><br />I guess it's strange to think that this history of "silly technology" -- digital cameras boasting a whole three feet of electrical cord, failed internet "walled gardens" like AOL and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prodigy_(online_service)">Prodigy</a> -- is really quite young.  The Macintosh computer (pitched to shareholders in 1984) was the first commercially successful computer with a graphical user interface, and that computer, for me, is the cornerstone of what I'm studying now.  Human-Computer Interaction is not only my academic focus but something that permeates <em>my life</em>; I am at a computer or interacting with things thanks to computers throughout my day more often than I am not.  Working, writing papers for class, corresponding, paying bills, learning about health insurance and oppression and red spider lilies...<br /><br />COOL MAN, STEVE.  I'm glad that technology's history (and future?) is marked not with <em>Let's use this to get all the money</em>, but rather with, <em>Let's do this because this is what we love.</em></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RAWs vs. JPEG Fine]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/07/25/raws-vs-jpeg-fine/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/07/25/raws-vs-jpeg-fine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've done a lot of exploring in San Francisco this past weekend, as my more city-savvy friends have returned from Japan.  One of them lamented having not known about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raw_image_format">raws</a> before going, and we had a conversation about it, with me mostly being like, <em>Dude, raw may make your pictures better but so does having the proper aperture, shutter speed, white balance, ISO,</em> etc.<br /><br />I've only tried shooting raw once, <a href="http://www.flickr.com/search/?w=11378171@N02&amp;q=%22golden%20gardens%22">with somewhat non-exceptional results</a>.  The only thing that came out of this experience was that raws took forever to edit (on my poor, slow computer) and I didn't really see much difference in quality.<br /><br />Fast forward to exploration weekend, wherein I decided I would give raws another shot (if you will) and then realized that <em>they are really cool</em>.  There are <a href="http://www.luminous-landscape.com/tutorials/understanding-series/u-raw-files.shtml">other places</a> where you can learn exactly what raws are, so I won't go into that here, but rather just talk about my experiences.<br /><br />What I found really amazing about the raw images that I took was the capacity that I had to edit them.  With my normal fine jpegs, I pretty much just threw them into Photoshop, and adjusted the middle bar of Levels slightly to the right to get rid of some of the grays.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hQG8cREC90M/Ti5OEXhbfvI/AAAAAAAAATE/b3uwemzEG4g/s1600/lessgraylol.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="198" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hQG8cREC90M/Ti5OEXhbfvI/AAAAAAAAATE/b3uwemzEG4g/s320/lessgraylol.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">now it's less gray lol</td></tr></tbody></table><br />And that was about the extent of my editing, unless I was trying to fix white balance or whatever.  Occasionally I would touch the other two bars, but pictures would inevitably look way too bright or way too dark afterward.  Plus, editing was pretty linear -- stuff as a whole would just keep getting brighter (and way too bright), or else much darker.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P7Cj8Myg8VI/Ti5Op5X5iGI/AAAAAAAAATM/37N4R2Ll0eQ/s1600/lessgraylol2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="217" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-P7Cj8Myg8VI/Ti5Op5X5iGI/AAAAAAAAATM/37N4R2Ll0eQ/s320/lessgraylol2.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">now it's more white lol</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Enter raws, which are apparently just like having an undeveloped shot of film, in which all its possibilities of exposure are retained.  Also enter the Conservatory of Flowers, which is what I did in order to take tons of pictures of flowers, despite the fact that flower picture-taking is uber-typical.  Here is my original photo of a flower --<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-yEDrWjcps4w/Ti5Pdj-LUQI/AAAAAAAAATU/j7XaEkY1-HI/s1600/sunday72.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="213" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-yEDrWjcps4w/Ti5Pdj-LUQI/AAAAAAAAATU/j7XaEkY1-HI/s320/sunday72.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><br />And here are two edited versions --<br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: -webkit-auto;"><br /></div><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_oo9KWAgCFM/Ti5PmQ47RyI/AAAAAAAAATc/mlRl2t_CTTI/s1600/sunday71.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="212" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_oo9KWAgCFM/Ti5PmQ47RyI/AAAAAAAAATc/mlRl2t_CTTI/s320/sunday71.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-EuepuPwp_e4/Ti5PqbMa1UI/AAAAAAAAATk/wph0yhVEmK4/s1600/sunday73.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="212" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-EuepuPwp_e4/Ti5PqbMa1UI/AAAAAAAAATk/wph0yhVEmK4/s320/sunday73.jpg" width="320" /></a></div><br /><em>Where did all that detail come from?!</em><br /><br />Had I been editing a jpeg from that original, I assure you that the only thing I would have known how to do is make that shit even whiter than it already was.  Or else make everything around it as black as my soul.  Though I have to admit that a likely cause of this is just the fact that using Photoshop tools is like reaching for something in a huge, bubbling cauldron and slapping it on your picture -- you don't really know what you're doing and you're never really quite sure what will happen.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-dtsf4qr3b74/Ti5RtKqc6dI/AAAAAAAAATs/Mg_gfs-UtA0/s1600/lolol.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="213" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-dtsf4qr3b74/Ti5RtKqc6dI/AAAAAAAAATs/Mg_gfs-UtA0/s320/lolol.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">what wait oh no why</td></tr></tbody></table><br />On the other hand, the workflow for editing a raw in the Mac that I'm borrowing is pretty self-explanatory.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HDutWQ33XJ4/Ti5T4iYqylI/AAAAAAAAAT8/eQy32YMjnrI/s1600/cameraraw.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="211" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-HDutWQ33XJ4/Ti5T4iYqylI/AAAAAAAAAT8/eQy32YMjnrI/s320/cameraraw.png" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">oh, so those are the things i can do?<br />and i can see what changes they make to the picture immediately?<br />okay.</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Anyway.  My notable observations on raw are as follows:<br /><br /><ul><li>Raw files take up too much dang space. &nbsp;My 4GB memory card can handle 1,500+ fine JPEGs like a badass. &nbsp;It can hold about 400 raws.</li><li>This means that my normal methods of "TAKE AS MANY PICTURES AS YOU CAN AND MAYBE THREE OF THEM WILL BE OKAY" won't work here.</li><li>Then again, the reason why I had to take so many pictures was because so many of them turned out irreversibly poor. &nbsp;And if I could <i>edit </i>them...</li><li>Even though it sucks to have less space, I don't actually mind it -- throughout this past weekend I found myself being more thoughtful about what pictures to take, and being more vicious about which ones to immediately delete if I didn't like them. &nbsp;It's not just memory that I need to take into account -- it's the fact that every picture I save will require some minutes of editing, which, in my busy busy day is worth &nbsp; a ton. &nbsp;I'm already two days behind in my&nbsp;<a href="http://neauro.tumblr.com/tagged/30_day_challenge">San Francisco Summer thing</a>&nbsp;I'm trying to do.</li><li>Being more thoughtful in the actual picture-taking process is, to me, a refreshing change.</li><li>Plus, in the actual editing I really feel more connected and appreciative of each picture, and thus more like I've actually accomplished something meaningful for myself, etc.</li></ul><div><br /></div><div>That being said, aside from pictures which will be explicitly harvested for panorama purposes, I think I'm going to do my best to stick to raw file formats as a default from now on, the same way that I moved somewhat mysteriously from always-auto to always-manual settings. &nbsp;Still, I think it's important to have a handle on aperture/shutter speed/ISO and all that, since a raw file format can't fix blur. &nbsp;(That I know of.) &nbsp;And you know me, I'm liek totally super pro photog, so listen up.</div></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>nadine a.</div>
<div class='content'>
Haha, thanks Kathleen :D</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Kathleen Tuite</div>
<div class='content'>
Now I want to try shooting in RAW! I quietly lolled at several sentences in this post.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
