<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Misc | miscware]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-02T07:48:52-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nat]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Football: Great for the Audience]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/13/football/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-13T19:17:44-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/13/football</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past weekend I finally learned about football, something I&rsquo;ve never been terribly interested in. The most recent game I watched was Kind Of A Big Deal for the city I live in.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/sea2.jpg" alt="Rain and cars and a distant Seattle Space Needle."/></p>

<p class="caption">distant space needle.</a></p>


<p>It strikes me that football is an incredibly fun game to watch because the &ldquo;four downs&rdquo; system provides a multitude of little goals to rejoice about. Each play is rife with struggle, with a victory that can turn into loss in an instant. It reminds me of Mark Rosewater&rsquo;s description of <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/magazine/article.aspx?x=mtg/daily/mm/174">interaction and a catch-up feature</a> as things that &ldquo;every game needs.&rdquo; At each &ldquo;down,&rdquo; both teams have the potential not just to stop each other, but to improve their own standing. It&rsquo;s a powerful interval.</p>

<p>Watching the game this past weekend was the first time in my life that I really, finally <em>got</em> it. I didn&rsquo;t know there were separate offensive and defensive teams; I didn&rsquo;t know that there were people whose singular jobs were to run, or to kick, and that the had individual tutors. It&rsquo;s pretty inspiring.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/sea1.jpg" alt="Seattle Space Needle with a flag that reads '12' on top "/></p>

<p class="caption">#gohawks! and, fun fact: "the 12th man" is a copyrighted phrase. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/12th_man_(football)#Texas_A.26M_trademark_issues_and_Seattle_Seahawks_lawsuit">a phrase <em>not</em> copyrighted by us.</a></p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013 Is Off to a Busy Busy Busy Busy Start.]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/26/2013-is-off-to-busy-busy-busy-busy-start/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/26/2013-is-off-to-busy-busy-busy-busy-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I've recently started using <a href="http://www.trello.com">Trello</a> to keep track of my myriad projects, and I love it because I can use it as an always-accessible repository of lists for ideas regarding games, writing, websites, homework, and so on. It's also great for keeping track of resources like free icon sets. I've also been using it to manage and focus on what things are actually currently on my plate, and making sure I don't overextend myself.<br /><br />My prime reading time has always been during my commutes, but I have been reading less because I've discovered <a href="">IA Writer</a>, a writing app which features a simple UI, a re-arranged keyboard, and integration with iCloud (which took me forever how to use; but it's way more convenient than e-mailing myself everything). I absolutely adore it and have been using it for writing practice, which has in general alleviated my plaguing anxieties about not writing enough. I tried writing on the bus with my sketchbook but the bus's movement made my scribbles illegible; typing on my iPod makes things easier, and even a little fun.<br /><br />I have also been hard at work on my part of this year's group cosplay, Black Rock Shooter. I was initially going to go for Demon Cannon User, but then a friend dropped out due to busy-ness, and now I'm rocking Strength, for which I am actually attempting to build up strength to carry around the huge cardboard hands that A is helping me make.<br /><br />Winter quarter is also in full swing. This quarter I'm taking my first "practical" class, usability testing, and it's funny — I always thought that I would find practical classes more immediately applicable — but instead I'm finding myself missing theory courses, where you could learn a theory and apply it <em>immediately</em>, instead of waiting to gather participants and test. I'm working with a group to improve and analyze the usability of <a href="http://www.mappingvoices.org">Mapping Voices</a>, which I was interested in for the potential application of game design — for example, how can you encourage people to take action against health inequity? How can you make people feel productive taking action?<br /><br />Though it looks like our suggestions will have to hold up against a bureaucracy and generally complicated organization, I'm looking forward to contributing to a local organization!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Valentine's Day!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/14/happy-valentines-day/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/14/happy-valentines-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-L0g3kptX3tw/TzqSLgiURRI/AAAAAAAAAp8/SnmysZkNPHw/s1600/loveletter.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="240" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-L0g3kptX3tw/TzqSLgiURRI/AAAAAAAAAp8/SnmysZkNPHw/s320/loveletter.png" width="320" /></a></div><br />Celebrate it by checking out Alex's newly (and appropriately) released game, <a href="http://axcho.com/theloveletter/">The Love Letter</a>.  He also wrote about his endeavors <a href="http://evolutionlive.blogspot.com/2012/02/love-letter-released.html">here</a>.<br /><br />Other interesting fact I learned from Alex: the art is inspired partly a poster from <a href="http://ifartrainbow.com/">Enfu</a>&nbsp;-- you can tell by the outlines, which are dark blue rather than black!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Owning a Kindle in Seattle as a Student]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/01/owning-kindle-in-seattle-as-student/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/01/owning-kindle-in-seattle-as-student</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-e7bdL7k_Dc0/Tx5Y6nhukPI/AAAAAAAAAoE/Uj4vbQx1NIA/s1600/KT-slate-02-lg._V166940136_.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="308" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-e7bdL7k_Dc0/Tx5Y6nhukPI/AAAAAAAAAoE/Uj4vbQx1NIA/s320/KT-slate-02-lg._V166940136_.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Kindle-eReader-eBook-Reader-e-Reader-Special-Offers/dp/B0051QVESA">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I thought that my loyalty to books would last -- I thought I would shun anything else that lacked their comforting weight, their pulpy baleen. &nbsp;And still I found myself drawn uncomfortably to the Amazon page for the Kindle for months, thinking, <i>Should I...?</i><br /><br /><i>No way. &nbsp;There are already so many physical books! &nbsp;So many!</i><br /><br />I finally relented after realizing that you can read PDFs on a Kindle, which is nice because my course this quarter requires a <i>lot</i>&nbsp;of reading, most of which I can no longer print out for free at the CSE undergrad labs. &nbsp;Squinting at scanned inky text on a screen that can sear it into your vision long after you've actually stopped reading is unpleasant, and so, Kindle.<br /><br />I learned then quickly of the resources available to Kindle users who belong in my particular demographic, that is, a student in Seattle:<br /><br /><h3>  You can get Amazon Prime for half its normal yearly fee.</h3>Students can pay half the standard $80 fee per year for free two-day shipping and access to Amazon's Kindle Lending Library, which can be browsed on a Kindle or online <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/search/ref=sr_nr_p_n_feature_browse-b_mrr_2?rh=n%3A283155%2Cp_85%3A2470955011%2Cp_n_feature_browse-bin%3A618073011&amp;bbn=283155&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1320670642&amp;rnid=618072011?tag=publishmarket-20">here</a>.  It says that you can borrow a book a month, but I think (<em>think</em>) that you can borrow a single book per month, but return it if you want to get another book before the time is up.  I am unclear on this and cannot completely verify yet, having difficulties finding the answer and also having not loaned out anything for a complete month yet.  The collection is enormous and what you'll notice about it immediately is the presence of The Hunger Games, the poster child of the Lending Library, a little medal of, <em>Look!  There are even recent, popular books here!  For free (for $49/year)!</em><br /><br /><h3>  You can borrow ebooks from the Seattle Public Library.</h3>The waiting lists are long, but there are enough "unpopular" books to tide you over until the holds let up.  You can have holds on 25 books maximum.  You can borrow 25 books maximum, each for up to 21 days maximum.  Here's the tricky thing that took me an annoying while to figure out: returning books is not done through the Seattle Public Library's <a href="http://spl.lib.overdrive.com/">online site</a>, but through the "Manage Your Kindle" link on Amazon.com.<br /><br />Browsing the ebook collection is also frustratingly tedious -- more on that later.  Suffice to say that browsing ebooks is something I reserve for mindlessly doing between builds.<br /><br /><h3>  There are tons of public domain books available on Amazon for free.</h3>They are odds and ends of things, but I really enjoy random tidbits like <em>Character</em> and <em>Home Vegetable Gardening -a Complete and Practical Guide to the Planting and Care of All Vegetables, Fruits and Berries Worth Growing for Home Use</em>, so, <a href="http://www.blogger.com/The%20http://www.amazon.com/s?ie=UTF8&amp;node=154606011&amp;redirect=true&amp;sort=daterank&amp;field-price=0-0">there</a> you go!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goodreads Ratings]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/23/goodreads-ratings/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/23/goodreads-ratings</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--czAH4cCqME/Tx5KxR4KxbI/AAAAAAAAAn0/cI6PcDeoEXI/s1600/goodreads.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--czAH4cCqME/Tx5KxR4KxbI/AAAAAAAAAn0/cI6PcDeoEXI/s1600/goodreads.jpg" /></a></div><br />I've been a member of it since 2008, but it wasn't until recently that I found any affection for <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/">Goodreads</a>, a social networking website based on readers and writers. &nbsp;I haven't been able to find many people to interact with on it; for me, the greatest value is simply in being able to keep a list of books that I've read, and how much I like them, based on a simple scale of 1 to 5 stars.<br /><br />A scale of 1 to 5 is pretty limited, but can still mean different things to everyone, which is why I like that Goodreads has a little dialog hover helpfully over the stars when you're judging them. &nbsp;1 star, it says, stands for <i>I&nbsp;didn't like it.</i>&nbsp; 2, for <i>It was OK. &nbsp;</i>3: <i>I liked it.</i>&nbsp; 4: <i>I really liked it.</i>&nbsp; And 5: <i>It was amazing.</i><br /><br />My personal rating system goes like this:<br /><br /><ul><li>1 -- <i>I didn't like it.</i> &nbsp;This book made me ill. &nbsp;Reading it may have caused my opinion of humanity to degrade. &nbsp;I would grimace when remembering it, and anti-recommend it, fiercely. &nbsp;Examples: <i>Wild Animus, Bloodborn, Hot Gimmick S.</i></li><li>2 -- <i>It was okay.</i> &nbsp;I wouldn't read it again or recommend it, but there was some slight redeeming quality about it, even if it was just that it featured a fetish motif (ex. shapeshifters). &nbsp;Examples: <i>Other, Abandoned, Dead Until Dark.</i></li><li>3 -- <i>I liked</i>&nbsp;<i>it.</i>&nbsp; Reserved for books which kept me turning pages, but in the end were really just so-so. &nbsp;Examples: <i>Pants on Fire, A Lion Among Men, The Eye of the World.</i></li><li>4 -- <i>I really liked it.</i>&nbsp; Given to books which kept me hungry for more, and<i>&nbsp;</i>were well-written, and had me sitting back dazed for a little after finishing.&nbsp;Examples:&nbsp;<i>Delirium, Wintergirls, The Alchemist.</i></li><li>5 -- <i>It was amazing. </i>&nbsp;My label for books that <i>changed my life,</i>&nbsp;whether in terms of writing style, basic habits, or perceptions of morality/reality/x-ality. &nbsp;Examples being: <i>The Time-Traveler's Wife, Perdido Street Station, The Omnivore's Dilemma.</i></li></ul><div><br /></div><div>I read a quote somewhere I can't find now; the point of it was that it is unproductive to read a book and then wonder to yourself whether you liked it or not. &nbsp;My takeaway from the idea was that judgment is less productive than analysis -- that is, it's infinitely better to say, <i>"I liked X for Y reasons,"</i>&nbsp;both for yourself and for the writer as well, since the writer is given the opportunity to improve. &nbsp;But as Goodreads is a social network not just for readers but for writers (with little qualifying labels next to their names), I hesitate at leaving qualitative feedback. &nbsp;Writers are real! &nbsp;And they have feelings! &nbsp;I don't want to hurt those. &nbsp;Plus, popular books often have a multitude of reviews praising this or decrying that; I can't see myself adding anything of value to the discussions, especially when ratings in these cases have usually fallen into an equilibrium rating of 4 or so.<br /><br />I'll finish with a quote from <i>A Room of One's Own</i>&nbsp;by Virginia Woolf:</div><blockquote>At any rate, where books are concerned, it is notoriously difficult to fix labels of merit in such a way that they do not come off.  Are not reviews of current literature a perpetual illustration of the difficulty of judgment?  "This great book," "this worthless book," the same book is called by both names.  Praise and blame alike mean nothing.  No, delightful as the pastime of measuring may be, it is the most futile of all occupations, and to submit to the decrees of the measurers the most servile of attitudes.  So long as you write what you wish to write, that is all that matters; and whether it matters for ages or only for hours, nobody can say.</blockquote></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
