<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Game Recs | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/game-recs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-16T19:43:58-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts Re: Thomas Was Alone]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/thomas-was-alone/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T09:52:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/thomas-was-alone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/twa.png" alt="Screenshot of Thomas Was Alone"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<a href="http://www.mobygames.com/game/windows/thomas-was-alone/screenshots/gameShotId,566500/">via</a>)</p>


<p><em>Thomas Was Alone</em> was super cute, if more ambiguous than I personally like. I liked the personality given to all the different shapes, though their common heroism and conceit got a little old as the game went on, which was why Laura&rsquo;s cynicism made her my favorite (though I felt compelled inexlicably to keep calling her &ldquo;Ruth&rdquo;). I loved that the levels were tilted, the play of light, the strange colors. (Though I wonder if any colorblind users had a hard time playing?)</p>

<p>One thing I think the game could have been improved was the game&rsquo;s sense of progression; though numbers ticked up each level, after a while they became meaningless, and now that the game is finished I&rsquo;m not totally sure what I would use them for. The introduction of each of the colored shapes, Thomas&rsquo;s &ldquo;death,&rdquo; and the era of the gray shapes seemed to be the largest movements in the story, and though each was accompanied with a fun snippet of &ldquo;The AIs are gaining sentience!&rdquo; flavor I didn&rsquo;t really have a sense that things were reaching their end until the end came suddenly to meet me. Some levels seemed like little &ldquo;drabbles&rdquo; and experiments, which I completed without much more effort than would take for me to click a cow in Farmville, and it would have been cool to see something else related to AIs breaking their previous ways of being. Breaking through the borders of levels — intentionally disobeying orders — something to add to the flavor text.</p>

<p>I played <em>Thomas Was Alone</em> on a projector and if you have the opportunity to do so yourself I recommend it. All those rectangles are like way better when they&rsquo;re as big as your face.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lone Survivor & Meaningfulness]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/05/lone-survivor-meaningfulness/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/05/lone-survivor-meaningfulness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VLOhbqzGTUk/UBggO-tiRlI/AAAAAAAAB3g/4k3a6a5Q5kg/s1600/lonesurvivor.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VLOhbqzGTUk/UBggO-tiRlI/AAAAAAAAB3g/4k3a6a5Q5kg/s1600/lonesurvivor.jpg" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>0.</h2></div><div class="p1"><i>Lone Survivor </i>was the game I was most excited to obtain through a Humble Indie Bundle months ago, because the big grainy pixels looked so delicious, so fat with mood and atmosphere. And weirdness! And mysteriousness!</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Spoilers ahead.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>1.</h2></div><div class="p1">One of my favorite parts of adventure games is the characterization that rises through interaction with items. Do characters like a certain item, or dislike it? Does the item bring up deep heartbroken memories of the past? How do they parse and react, and what does their rumination say for who they are? I'm reminded of Nancy Drew's endearing enthusiasm for lifting up random objects ("This plastic DNA model will be useful!") and Phoenix Wright's skeptical amusement when things like puppies are added to his inventory.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">The most interesting item in the game for me was the toy cat, which I enjoyed petting all the time to accrue invisible "sanity" points. Engaging with the cat toy in particular puts you in the shoes and brain of the lone survivor himself, tinkering with a plush at the end of the world, just to have something light-hearted to do.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>2.</h2></div><div class="p1">Speaking of the cat plush, I loved the detail of this game — the unidentifiable flesh-like substances stretching across the wall — the way your map was dark unless you viewed it under sources of light — the specific food items like Delicious Ham, the creepy bottomless repositories of pills and Rotten Meats.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>3.</h2></div><div class="p1">A criticism of <i>Lone Survivor</i> seems to be that it was not scary enough. I played it at the height of summer and even then it was plenty terrifying, even if most of my stress and fear stemmed from being unable to hoard my bullets as obsessively as I would have liked.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Another scary part: putting your hand in that horrifying pink-red flesh-pixel hole. I <i>really </i>did not want to do that.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>4.</h2></div><div class="p1">The dream sequences were cool, and the characters therein intriguingly surreal, which I loved. Ultimately, however, I didn't feel that these scenes contributed to a larger understanding of what was going on, which was disappointing. Rather than deep, the first ending I received was vague, and a letdown. After carrying and caring for this dude I'd wanted a little more than a whiff of a broken heart. I wanted to know more about what this girl meant to the protagonist, how her departure left his life with zombie-filled corridors.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>5.</h2></div><div class="p1">I got my ending by playing as paragon as possible. I wanted to see if other endings would give me closure, so I found them on Youtube. Each one seemed vaguer than the last, and didn't interest me that much. I don't have a particular love of multiple endings and for me it's because they lack impact: I've only rarely encountered any set that comfortably resolves all issues and tension introduced in the game, and the way that such endings are reached never quite seems to match the decisions you made to get there.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">In the case of <i>Lone Survivor, </i>the decisions that you make add to an invisible calculator which eventually spits out one of these endings: for example, killing more monsters gives you endings that imply you're mentally unstable. But why? What is it about killing these things makes you this way? The worst ending can also be achieved not just by killing monsters, but "eating food when not hungry or hurt" and "sleeping for no reason" (per <a href="http://lonesurvivor.wikia.com/wiki/Endings">this wiki</a>). What's <i>that </i>connection?</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>6.</h2></div><div class="p1">This was my other favorite part: getting that white cat to come live with me. I guess it's strange to be saying that after my demands for meaningfulness, since other than the invisible points, hanging out with the cat doesn't reveal any more of the protagonist's inner story. But playing with the cat, I felt for the first time that I was doing something in the game that I personally wanted, like it was really <i>me</i> in there, and not me poking through things in a dude-shaped glove.<br /><br />Come here! Come <i>here</i>, little digital thing!<br /><br /></div><div class="p1"><i>come and be with me forever</i><br /><i><br /></i><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3tvhPIy5tDo/UilDcBOQcrI/AAAAAAAAEBc/f6aLd4GxHlk/s1600/Sunny.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3tvhPIy5tDo/UilDcBOQcrI/AAAAAAAAEBc/f6aLd4GxHlk/s1600/Sunny.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://lonesurvivor.wikia.com/wiki/Category:Characters">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><i><br /></i></div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Off the Leash]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/03/21/off-leash/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/03/21/off-leash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
is the cutest dog-based tilt runner game that I've ever played, despite being a game in which it is difficult to play and get a screenshot which captures the excitement of running full tilt (ohoho) with a growing pack of thickly-lined canines. I only wish that there was a shiba inu, but then, I always wish this for everything, even things that don't necessarily include dogs in the first place.<br /><br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Mixvu6hl3zE/T2ovQKb4dkI/AAAAAAAAAr8/-lPWr3xePpg/s640/blogger-image-1447569057.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Mixvu6hl3zE/T2ovQKb4dkI/AAAAAAAAAr8/-lPWr3xePpg/s640/blogger-image-1447569057.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of "off the leash"</td></tr></tbody></table><br />It's free to play, with purchaseable items being more (non-shiba) dogs, power-ups, and even a permanent "2x coin bonus" thing for 99 cents. &nbsp;At some point I unlocked "Tiki Surf Hut Bonus Thing Level" and searched around for it in vain, only to realize that its appearance would be a semi-random in-game&nbsp;occurrence, not something that I could summon at will from the main menu. &nbsp;Was this an example of "verbal, unexpected, informational feedback" that is so beloved of games that hold high the ideal of <a href="http://chrishecker.com/Achievements_Considered_Harmful%3F">instrinsic motivation</a>? &nbsp;Or maybe just UI that wasn't clear enough in informing me that it would reward me with such a bonus level after collecting X amount of steaks and Y number of dalmations during play? &nbsp;The world may never know.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-O6CiUATBERg/T2y5EYdhSiI/AAAAAAAAAsY/EdzBFRxnA_A/s1600/blogger-image-1979466662.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-O6CiUATBERg/T2y5EYdhSiI/AAAAAAAAAsY/EdzBFRxnA_A/s320/blogger-image-1979466662.jpg" width="213" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the crash of 38 dogs</td></tr></tbody></table></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Purple-y Play-through of Dear Esther]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/22/my-purple-y-play-through-of-dear-esther/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/22/my-purple-y-play-through-of-dear-esther</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I played Dear Esther last week, which shouldn't be a surprise since Everyone Is Talking About It. <br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-q64DenBNx5M/T0FszTbcjpI/AAAAAAAAAqc/P5c9ZcTpbSI/s1600/esther1.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-q64DenBNx5M/T0FszTbcjpI/AAAAAAAAAqc/P5c9ZcTpbSI/s320/esther1.png" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a screenshot near Dear Esther's opening</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span style="text-align: -webkit-auto;">Playing it felt like being in a </span><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_ride" style="text-align: -webkit-auto;">dark ride</a><span style="text-align: -webkit-auto;"> -- the level guides you along paths worn or fenced, and occasionally you get a glimpse of the "aerial," framed between giant stone features. Going the long way to examine scenery inevitably brings you back to the golden path, which is nice, because backpedaling would have been painful in a game with no running.</span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span style="text-align: -webkit-auto;"><br /></span></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: left;"><span style="text-align: -webkit-auto;">No running means that there's no way to rush through anything. In some ways being forced to slow down is comforting; rushing has been ingrained in me, rush to wake up, to get to work, to get back, to do homework.  But in this game taking your time is coerced, is allowed. You can slow down to look at the cyan particle spray of ocean waves hitting the shore, to look at the rot-scarred timbers framing stone steps clotted with yellowbloom brush, to look at the mysterious luminescent chemical bonds and electrical diagrams splattered on the walls.</span></div><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-TgKCtu9j37E/T0Fs2h8Ic5I/AAAAAAAAAqk/5HHiuqOVQo8/s1600/esther2.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="200" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-TgKCtu9j37E/T0Fs2h8Ic5I/AAAAAAAAAqk/5HHiuqOVQo8/s320/esther2.png" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a screenshot containing one of those creepy candles that <i>never melted</i></td></tr></tbody></table><br />I have to admit that more than once I wanted to do more than look.  I wanted to pick up the Bible on the ground and see what pages were bookmarked, I wanted to pick up medical instruments from trays of bloody water.  Which is, I guess, why I felt like this game was so much of a dark ride: you play, sitting in your cart, immersed but unable to touch anything.<br /><br />I guess one advantage of being unable to interact with things is that there's less pulling you from the immersion of the environment -- what would picking up a Bible have looked like, after all?  Like a book rising from the ground and opening magically inches from your eyes?  After a while I would have taken it for granted, but something so blatantly game-like would have been jarring the first time, would have reminded me that this world is a game.  A couple times your character acts on his or her own -- near the beginning, you duck to avoid an impromptu seagull -- when you enter dark places, your flashlight flickers on, wordlessly.  At moments like these it was easy to think that you  the player were actually perched on the optic nerves of a very un-curious person, hallucinating a Bri'ish narrator and their descent into madness.<br /><br />A feature of this game is that, though voice-overs are triggered as you make your way to certain areas, some are selected randomly to play, making for a story whose gem-glass plot-points feel jagged, don't quite fit together, rupture your reason-making.  It could make the game an interesting one the second time around, I guess -- that random number generator might dole you out a new snatch of calming Englishman script.  Though I want to consume all the text related to this story, I'm not quite tempted to play it over again, at least not just yet.<br /><br />In conclusion: it's cool that Dear experimental Esther is being received so well!  I'm glad to see people open to the new and unconventional things that video games can express, though there is some argument whether Dear Esther is a Real Game or not.<br /><br />Other articles about Dear Esther to check out: <a href="http://www.blog.radiator.debacle.us/2011/04/ludodiegesis-or-pinchbecks-unified.html">Ludodiegesis, or Pinchbeck's unified field theory of FPS games, or "please pee on my leg and tell me it's raining."</a>, <a href="http://www.brainygamer.com/the_brainy_gamer/2012/02/dear-eisenstein.html">Dear Eisenstein</a>, <a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/EMcNeill/20120215/9442/On_Dear_Esther.php">On Dear Esther</a></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Story in Trauma Team]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s1600/traumateam.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="163" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s320/traumateam.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.joystiq.com/2010/04/28/trauma-team-wii-review/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Time saved from <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/01/past-couple-days-in-series-of-instagram.html">not commuting during snowpacalypse</a>&nbsp;was spent playing Trauma Team, which I ordered (according to this hastily searched-up Amazon receipt) last March. &nbsp;(Spoilers ahead.)<br /><br />I adore the time-management micro-activities of Trauma Center, but was still surprised to find out how much I flat-out <i>enjoyed </i>Trauma Team. &nbsp;The fakey manga cutscenes re-used a lot of character art and implemented some tricks (scaling and translating a car, for example, instead of an actual animation of it driving off into the sunset), but I still enjoyed it much more than any dead-eyed mannequin gestures that seem to fill up so much of the cutscenes I've glanced in super-budget games nowadays (though to be completely honest, I haven't really sat down and played a lot of them).<br /><br />Cutscenes aside, Trauma Team did a good job of conveying story through its actual gameplay, some memorable scenes being:<br /><ol><li>The part in the mall where Maria, the "first response" character, has to take care of five dying patients on her own. &nbsp;I love getting perfect scores on these games and every time someone died I quit and started over in frustration. &nbsp;I even left the mini-game to try another story-line, and returned later with a feeling of dread -- only to realize that it was rigged. &nbsp;The patients were <i>supposed</i>&nbsp;to be near-death; once you rushed through at least one of them, back-up would arrive and restore everyone to full health, bringing a once-impossible situation to now a somewhat calming one (complete with soothing, <i>don't worry, your friends are here </i>music). &nbsp;For that moment, I really <i>was</i>&nbsp;Maria, and experiencing her prime character flaw of over-independence, of trying to do everything myself. &nbsp;(Until struck the inevitable Japanese group-focused armature of "Let's all work together!")</li><li>The part where Gabe is diagnosing the soldier, who is struggling to be-"bro" you in an attempt to make it seem you have having "<i>meaningless, friendly conversation</i>" when in reality you are in the process of diagnosing his viral hemorrhagic fever. &nbsp;In this case, the characters speaking to each other and working together were embedded in the "verbal questioning" mini-game, which was pretty elegant -- a lot more elegant than just clicking through conversation, though the mini-game itself probably lent itself to storytelling pretty easily.</li></ol><div>Sometimes you could just <i>see </i>the inconsistencies between Japanese thought and expectation of the US, and how it "really is." An easy example is when the characters were at the mall -- shopping for groceries, which is fairly typical in malls in Asia, and not so much here.<br /><br />Another example: unlike many US-developed games, this game set in America had a refreshing amount of ethnic diversity in the main character cast. &nbsp;Can you name a character who was a Mexican woman off the top of your head? &nbsp;One for whom it didn't really&nbsp;<i>matter</i>&nbsp;that she had dark skin, one who wasn't "stereotypically Mexican?" &nbsp;How about a character who is potentially Native American? The Mexican character was, unfortunately, the subject of many a boob-shot, and was also pretty frustratingly&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tsundere">tsundere</a>&nbsp;at times; and in general the females all had the same, petite facial structure. &nbsp;Personality-wise, though, they were all strong and interesting, with motives that 100% did not involve getting with the men around them. &nbsp;(Though there was a bit of Maria/That Dark Brooding guy near the end...before he went back to his lifestyle of alternating between doing surgeries and jail-time.)<br /><br />Some bonus fangirling: the best part of this game, hands-down, were Kimishima's cases. &nbsp;I <i>loved</i>&nbsp;piecing together the facts, figuring out how someone had died (though most of them were pretty straight-forward), learning about Kimishima's weird "I can hear the dead" cellphone and the fact that other characters accepted that she had such a device without complaint ("You and your voodoo cellphone..."). &nbsp;Gabe Cunningham's voice actor (apparently <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travis_Willingham">the same as for Roy in Full Metal Alchemist</a>) had <i>so much life</i>&nbsp;(the best part being when he sang "chunky~~" at the American politician). &nbsp;Also, Atlus's bold, colorful interfaces are so&nbsp;fun to interact with.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
