<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-10T08:28:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving to Octopress From Blogger]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/12/15/test/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-15T15:17:07-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/12/15/test</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After eight years using Blogger, I&rsquo;ve finally decided to move away. One of the first reasons I first started using it in high school was because Blogger was one of the only free hosting services I knew where I could also control the styling; but after several Blogger updates, and several years of telling myself I&rsquo;d eventually learn Blogger syntax well enough to style as I like, I&rsquo;ve given up. I have other things I&rsquo;d rather do than invest time parsing Blogger, and Octopres offers more built-in tools <em>and</em> flexibility: I can have <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/blogging/code/">nice code snippets</a> and have whatever extra scripts I&rsquo;d like without worrying they&rsquo;d interfere with Blogger esoterica. Additionally, after reading <a href="https://medium.com/p/c7cc156bc5d9">this article</a> I&rsquo;ve been a little more wary of data ownership, and with Octopress, I can host on Github where I know everything is mine.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve also been eyeing <a href="https://ghost.org/">ghost</a> recently and though it looks awesome, I decided against it for now for several reasons. Currently, there&rsquo;s no easy way to import posts from Blogger, and I didn&rsquo;t want to deal with the extra overhead of figuring out where to host. A couple days ago I received access to Ghost&rsquo;s subscription hosting, but I don&rsquo;t want to commit to paying money when this blog is mostly for lolzy purposes.</p>

<p>So, this is how I got my blog set up again:</p>

<h2>Get Octopress Up and Running</h2>


<p>To actually figure out how to get Octopress running, I referenced several tutorials:</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/blogging/">Octopress: Blogging Basics</a></li>
<li><a href="http://webdesign.tutsplus.com/tutorials/applications/getting-started-with-octopress/">Webdesign Tuts+: Getting started with Octopress</a></li>
<li><a href="http://blog.ialja.com/2013/03/22/goodbye-blogger-hello-octopress/">iAlja's Blog: Goodbye Blogger, Hello Octopress!</a></li>
</ol>




<h2>Convert Old Blogger Posts to Be Octopress-Readable</h2>


<p>
From one of the previous links, I learned how to convert all my old posts to a form Octopress could work with. To do it, open up your old blog in blogger, then go to <code>Settings &gt; Other &gt; Export</code> to download your blog as an XML file. Then, I used <a href="https://gist.github.com/juniorz/1564581">this script</a> to run the conversion.</p>

<p>I ran into some issues here, mostly with titles that contained quotation marks or tags that contained colons; whenever this happened I went through the XML and just removed the symbols that were causing things to explode.</p>

<h2>Deploy to Github Pages</h2>


<p>Finally, I followed <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/deploying/github/">these instructions</a> to deploy my blog for free to Github Pages. I still ran into some problems here — when I deployed, the online version of the blog on Github lacked all styles and scripts — this requried a change to the <code>root</code> in config.yml to be <code>/liwanag</code>, since on Github the blog is acccessed through the URL <a href="http://neauro.github.io/liwanag.">http://neauro.github.io/liwanag.</a> Making this change to root upsets the styles and scripts linking locally, though&hellip;so I&rsquo;ve still got to iron this out and find the magical tweaks that will allow one root value to work both locally and online. There&rsquo;s also the matter that my blog is big enough that running &ldquo;rake generate&rdquo; takes a minute or so to run&hellip;but I&rsquo;m willing to accept that for now.</p>

<h2>That's it!</h2>


<p>As one final change, I&rsquo;ve changed the name of this blog. Previously, it was &ldquo;nuubu&rdquo; — a romanization of &ldquo;noob&rdquo; spelled in Japanese, chosen offhandedly because I originally intended this blog to be my corner for new things I&rsquo;ve learned. Because &ldquo;nuubu&rdquo; may be appropriative, and because I don&rsquo;t feel particularly strongly about clinging to the identity of &ldquo;noob&rdquo; anyway, I&rsquo;ve now named it &ldquo;liwanag,&rdquo; which means &ldquo;light&rdquo; in Tagalog. To be honest, I couldn&rsquo;t really think of another name at the time, and &ldquo;liwanag&rdquo; just sounds nice and makes me think of how blog-writing (that is, writing for an unknwon audience, or &ldquo;bringing things to light&rdquo;) helps me think more clearly.</p>

<p><a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com">nuubu</a> remains active, because many of the images linked to here point to where they&rsquo;ve been uploaded on Blogger, and because I don&rsquo;t want to lose what little bit of popularity those posts have accumulated (specifically, the Rosetta Stone error, and Alpacasso). But overall I&rsquo;m excited and happy for this bright new world. ✧ʕ̢̣̣̣̣̩̩̩̩·͡˔·ོɁ̡̣̣̣̣̩̩̩̩✧</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
