<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Book Reviews | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T10:18:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Legend, Marie Lu]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/10/06/legend-marie-lu/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/10/06/legend-marie-lu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nqLi7Zg-vTo/UHDhvJBSdVI/AAAAAAAACls/J0adRNjmiLk/s1600/9275658.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nqLi7Zg-vTo/UHDhvJBSdVI/AAAAAAAACls/J0adRNjmiLk/s320/9275658.jpg" width="213" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.justinsbookblog.com/2012/03/book-review-legend-legend-1-by-marie-lu.html">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><blockquote><i>Once known as the western coast of the United States, the Republic is now a nation perpetually at war with its neighbors, the Colonies.</i><br /><i><br /></i><i>Born into an elite family in one of the Republic's wealthiest districts, fifteen-year-old June is a military prodigy. Obedient, passionate, and committed to her country, she is being groomed for success in the Republics highest circles.</i><br /><i><br /></i><i>Born into the slums of the Republic's Lake Sector, fifteen-year-old Day is the country's most wanted criminal. But his motives may not be as malicious as they seem.</i><br /><i><br /></i><i>From very different worlds, June and Day have no reason to cross paths -- until the day June's brother, Metias, is murdered, and Day becomes the prime suspect. Now, caught in the ultimate game of cat and mouse, Day is in a race for his family's survival, while June tries desperately to avenge Metias's death.</i><br /><i><br /></i><i>But in a shocking turn of events, the two uncover the truth of what has really brought them together, and the sinister lengths to which their country will go to keep its secrets.</i></blockquote><br />I tore through this book like Oreo cheesecake (which is, not un-coincidentally, my favorite type of cheesecake, which is in turn my favorite type of cake). It contained all my favorite ingredients: dystopian surroundings (also known as a delicious yet crumbly crust), two main characters who are "specialists" at their game (the sugar),  who are additionally enemies of each other <em>and also love interests ahhhh</em> (the cheese).<br /><br />That being said, though I enjoyed reading it, there were things that could have been better. There doesn't seem to be any real purpose to why the Republic is in a dystopian/corrupt state, only some hand-waving about factions like "the Colonies" and the "Patriots," all of whom struggle against one another for vague territorial reasons. The youth of the Republic are all forced to go through "Trials" to determine their future, but there's no strong underlying reason <em>why</em>. Occasionally there are references to a mysterious pre-dystopian country regarded with awe -- a flag comprised of thirteen red and white stripes with fifty dots on a blue rectangle, an ancient coin that reads <em>In God We Trust</em> -- but that's about it. Why are people fighting for this by-gone era? Why are they regarding old quarters as precious? I guess we'll figure out in the next book?<br /><br />Another thing: one of the characters later is revealed to have a "dominant ethnicity" of "Mongolian," but is still blonde-haired and blue-eyed, which is bewildering to say the least. I'm not saying that Asian people are never born without blonde hair or blue eyes, but given the context of this book in its genre and in our society, where Asian people are often absent or played by white people, this particular Mongolian character ends up feeling uncomfortably "exotic."<br /><br />The book is told from the alternating first-person perspectives of "June" and "Day," which was okay, though both characters are so similar that I'm not sure I would have been able to tell them apart if the font face and color hadn't also alternated with each voice. A significant feature of both characters is their extreme attention to detail, which is fun, but also feels misused at times; there must have been at least three people which were noted as left-handed, not because left-handedness meant anything, but just to illustrate <em>again</em> how observative the main characters were, in case you'd forgotten. Aside from that, the story is easy to read, and filled with tasty drama.<br /><br />In conclusion: Legend is good cheesecake.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
