<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Fangirling | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/fangirling/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-23T10:13:34-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Delicious Rollback]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/24/the-delicious-rollback/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/24/the-delicious-rollback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Right now I am totally in love with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julietta_Suzuki">Suzuki Julietta</a>. She is the manga-ka of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kamisama_Kiss"><em>Kamisama Hajimemashita</em></a>, which recently got propelled in my mind to 5-star status after it started acquiring a time paradox, a plot device to which I am particularly weak. (How could she have planned that?! <em>Hoowww</em>?)<br /><br />Suzuki has a great grasp of storytelling and character development, something that I really appreciate in shoujo manga. Recently I described <a href="http://www.mangahere.com/manga/kamisama_hajimemashita/c065/">Chapter 65</a> (and 66) to Andou as an example. It goes like this:<br /><br />Nanami is making talismans for the shrine, so that visitors can come and get charms for things like "traffic safety," "love," "prosperous business." Tomoe sees them and goes, "Your handwriting is awful, let's make new talismans on the nice wood that I stored away." Nanami admits that she thought that wood was trash and threw it away and feels bad that she's disappointed him and hasn't made much headway in being a good god. Later that night, she notices Tomoe leaving and follows him mistakenly across some ethereal border and is almost smashed by a giant's foot. Tomoe saves her, and they wander around the night market searching for new talisman wood. Eventually Nanami separates from Tomoe and discovers two demons bullying a child, and when she tries to intervene, the two demons go for her instead. Wracking her brain for solutions, she eventually leads them beyond the ethereal border, where they are promptly smashed. They sneer that she will get stomped on too, but Nanami smiles and opens her coat to reveal: a talisman for traffic safety.<br /><br />There's just something <em>so delighful</em> about the story coming back full circle. In a sense you should have expected it — maybe you had the fun of figuring out yourself how Nanami could have made it out of her situation — even if you didn't, your brain lights up to realize the importance of something so seemingly insignificant. The final talisman also serves to answer her insecurities about being a bad god (even if her handwriting is bad, it <em>works!</em>), and as a bonus, makes Nanami to me a little more "real" — more of a person who is reacting to things in her environment, learning about them, using them.<br /><br />It's just <em>great</em>, and by no means an isolated formula. For example, in <a href="http://www.mangahere.com/manga/karakuri_odette/v01/c001/">the first chapter of Suzuki's other work, Karakuri Odette</a>, Odette begins attending high school, much to the hesitation of the school administrators. "Don't worry," says Odette's creator, "if she ever runs into problems, she'll emit a signal to me, and I'll pick her up right away." They agree and as Odette tries to learn more about what it means to be human, she asks her creator to make adjustments to her body: first, to add the ability to eat food, and second, to subtract from her robotic physical ability so she's only as strong as an average 15-year-old. Odette finds a new friend who is sickly and occasionally has seizures, and wanders around with her to a construction site, where both Odette and the girl fall into a well. Since she asked to be weakened, Odette can no longer climb out on her own — but then the girl starts to breathe desperately and beg for medicine — so Odette says, "Look away, don't look back until I say so," and when the girl turns away <em>Odette removes her head from her body</em> — which triggers the signal, and makes her creator come running.<br /><br /><em>So good!</em> There's just something utterly delicious of a small detail turning out to mean everything. This is something that I think is a challenge to do with games. When you pick up a key in level 1, for example, it's hard to imagine that it could be used to anything other than a treasure chest. (Though, knowing that, it would be fun to purposefully subvert this and make the key into an instrument for something else.)<br /><br />I've never played A Link to the Past, but apparently there's a great example of "small detail coming back to bite you" in it. It goes kind of like this: In one of the first towns you visit, there's a man who describes a nearby building as the old home of some evil bandit who for some reason couldn't stand the light. You play on, and on, and eventually, you return to the old home, and rescue the maiden in it, who begins to follow you around as you make your escape. At some point, you set a bomb off in a room, which collapses a ceiling and lets the light in — and when the maiden walks into it, she rips her skin off and become's the bandit. <em>The bandit, the dungeon's boss, has been following you this whole time! Whoa! Ahhh!</em><br /><br />Delicious.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sword Art Online: So Pretty]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/11/14/sword-art-online-so-pretty/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/11/14/sword-art-online-so-pretty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
So I found a gifset of Sword Art Online on Tumblr and decided that I wanted to watch it, because the art is pretty and also because the characters looked familiar, probably because Sword Art Online is one of the light novels I bought (and subsequently lost) some time ago.  <br /><br />Well, no matter!<br /><br />Sword Art Online (SAO) details the adventures of Kirito, who is one of ten thousand players trapped in the newly-released "virtual reality" MMORPG of the same name. The creator of SAO, who turns out to be some kind of eccentric psychopath, removes the "Log Out" button on the first day of open play and announces that everyone will have to reach and defeat Floor 100 in order to return back to the Real World. In the meantime, if you die in the game, you die in real life.<br /><br />I was excited because Kirito has bangs (my favorite ridiculous anime hair affectation) and spends the opening looking Dark and Tormented (my favorite ridiculous anime stereotype). Additionally, the "main" female character, Asuna, appears in the opening running around and doing things.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-SVwGKD2OF2Y/UKRq787wvXI/AAAAAAAACyY/FAquBkYgszk/s1600/sao.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="387" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-SVwGKD2OF2Y/UKRq787wvXI/AAAAAAAACyY/FAquBkYgszk/s640/sao.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">go, asuna, go! clear that low bar of agency!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />[spoilers ahead]<br /><br />Inevitably this first season was full of the same old tired female character stereotypes/storylines/actions, including but not limited to:<br /><br /><ul><li>female characters that basically act as pretty receptacles and mirrors for Kirito's feelings, for example:</li><ul><li>Silica, Dragon Tamer Girl: who appeared for one episode to be Kirito's "little sister," with bonus panicked upskirts</li><li>Lisbeth, Smith Girl: who appeared for one episode to be a love interest that is irrelevant after the one episode</li></ul><li>male characters not caring that female characters don't like them or want to be near them, for example:</li><ul><li>That one guy refuses to stop being Asuna's escort, and says he'll only leave her alone if Kirito wins against him a duel (what)</li><li>The leader of Asuna's guild, who, when Asuna tells him she wants to leave the guild, says she can only leave if Kirito wins against him in a duel (what)</li></ul><li>There's also a sub-plot that involves a woman who is murdered by her husband because, in the life-threatening situation of Sword Art Online, she stopped being "cute and obedient" and became instead a "lively and active" guild leader...<em>what?</em> It's obvious that this particular guy character is horrible, but I guess I'm bewildered by this story, which seemed to come out of nowhere, and didn't really serve to teach any characters about anything. Maybe if at the end Kirito had thought something like, <i>Wow, this really makes me appreciate Asuna's fighting skill more</i>...?</li></ul><br />The things that I <em>did</em> enjoy about this anime were the little game-related details, which take on a "private joke" feeling that I think was delightful and <em>not</em> uncomfortably blatant with fanfare and winking ("Hey! That was a game reference! Get it? Eh? <em>Ehhhh</em>?"). Characters gossip about other characters who have legendary status because their "HP bar has never fallen to yellow." At some point Kirito hits a wall in anger and the wall flashes with a notification -- <code>IMMORTAL OBJECT</code> -- indicating that it's inanimate and&nbsp;indestructible&nbsp; Best part: this little moment turns out to have plot significance later. Whoa! I <em>really</em> appreciate the meaningful subtlety.<br /><br />It's also fun to view what happens to characters as they become trapped in the digital world, though I wish it were explored more, perhaps in lieu of unnecessary female character fanservice. Some people commit suicide; some dedicate themselves to fighting on "the front lines" to free everyone; some people become merchants and smiths to support the fighters. One old man, thinking that he'd never get his real-life job back anyway, decides that he'll perfect in-game fishing.<br /><br />Inevitably Kirito and Asuna fall into a relationship, an unexpectedly intense and serious romance that involves them getting married (in-game) and living together in a cabin in the woods (on the game's Floor 22) and eventually meeting a girl that they "adopt" as their daughter (who later turns out to be a game process AI). Something that's refreshing about their relationship is the trust they have in each other -- Kirito&nbsp;occasionally&nbsp;hangs behind while Asuna fights, and at one point just smiles when someone tries to warn him to get his wife out of the way of a giant attacking fish. Though they were rarer than the opposite, I appreciated the parts where Kirito gave Asuna a place to stand on her own and defend and be appreciated for her actions and thoughts and talents, which weren't all Kirito-centered (for example, her&nbsp;experimentation&nbsp;with cooking and seeing which mixture of in-game loots and essences could make real-world flavors like soy sauce).<br /><br />Given the intensity of their dedication to each other (Kirito declares to Asuna that his entire self belongs to her; Asuna says that if Kirito dies, she'll commit suicide), it's uncomfortable and bewildering why the second season of SAO, which is still on-going, keeps pushing this love triangle forward between Kirito and his sister-who-is-actually-his-cousin. I mean, this isn't going to pan out, right? Is this just an excuse to keep having unrequited romantic (slash incestuous and forbidden) tension in the show to keep people watching? Is devoted love so boring? After all that the two characters have been through together, and after the show gives you so much reason to invest in the semi-doomed lovebank of Kirito/Asuna, it's hard to see this extra, new girl as anything but annoying fan service. <br /><br />Something else a little depressing is the impending descent of Asuna into a caged bird that doesn't do much but stare forlornly into space whenever her captor, a despised fiancé in a real-world arranged marriage who is keeping her unconscious and trapped in a new MMORPG, comes to threaten her warmly with sexual assault or erasure of her memories. In the most recent episode, Asuna sneakily watched him unlock the door to her cage, which made me assume hopefully that she would try to escape on her own. Unfortunately, she just collapsed on her knees and cried, "Save me, Kirito!"<br /><br />It's not that I blame her for her circumstances or think that she could fight her way out of it if she wanted...I just don't want her to become a full-on damsel in distress. :(<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-LxyJxHtHaZ4/UKRswdDNWJI/AAAAAAAACyg/8JOOm1RLdCk/s1600/sao2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="366" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-LxyJxHtHaZ4/UKRswdDNWJI/AAAAAAAACyg/8JOOm1RLdCk/s640/sao2.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">low bar of agency: not cleared (<a href="http://kimmygawa.tumblr.com/post/34445253622/weird-guy-that-smell-asunas-hair-made-her-cry">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Having met the end of the anime that's presently out, I've been devouring the light novels, where fanservice-y upskirts are not as prominent and where Asuna is more of an active character during the "fairy" arc, escaping and fighting and doing what she can. As a series the whole thing is&nbsp;<i>really </i>fun to watch -- it's&nbsp;beautiful, and really stretches, embroiders, and <i>uses</i> its theme of video game worlds and realities.</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>cosbabyfive</div>
<div class='content'>
Asuna Yuuki is a heroine and the partner of Kirito in the Sword Art Online series. Her original avatar in <a href="http://www.cosplayfield.com/sword-art-online-alo-c-545_550.html" rel="nofollow">ALfheim Online</a>, was as Fairy Queen, Titania. She wore a white outfit, with a white long skirt, tube top showing her belly, along with a red ribbon that goes around the top part of her top that comes together to make a bow. She goes barefoot, and wears a white strip around her ankles! This <a href="http://www.cosplayfield.com/sao-alfheim-online-asuna-yuuki-cosplay-costume-p-523.html" rel="nofollow">Asuna Yuuki cosplay costume</a> looks like a long dress, and this is why I love it very much!</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hotarubi No Mori E]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
One of my favorite manga short stories, <i>Hotarubi no Mori e</i>&nbsp;by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Yuki&nbsp;</a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Midorikawa</a>, was just made into an anime film! I&nbsp;cried after reading the story, and I cried after the&nbsp;animated film ended too. One would think that already&nbsp;knowing the ending would have removed the emotion from&nbsp;the film, but I guess not.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s1600/hotarubi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s400/hotarubi.jpg" width="282" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">tears everywhere, seriously (<a href="https://minniemeorange.wordpress.com/2012/03/04/anime-movie-review-hotarubi-no-mori-e/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />[spoilers ahead]<br /><br />I haven't read much manga recently, but what stories&nbsp;I've read from Midorikawa still remain glowing in my&nbsp;memory. She always takes a single, strange premise -- <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=11498">a criminal investigator that can make people do as he says</a>, <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=6781">a boy who inherits his grandmother's "book of names" of spirits</a> -- and uses story to cast light into the unique possibilities given by that premise, really stretches and shines it out to its full potential.<br /><i><br /></i><i>Hotarubi no&nbsp;</i><i>Mori e</i> in particular is my favorite of hers, because it's so wonderfully concise, whole, and  focused. A human and a spirit meet and become friends, despite a peculiar limitation: if the spirit ever encounters human touch, he will vanish from the world.<br /><br />Significant events and points of growth in the characters' relationship revolve around the problem of contact. When the two first meet, they carry a stick between them to hold hands. One day, when the human falls from a tree, the spirit races to catch her -- before pulling back at the last moment to let her crash. Afterward, she weeps -- "Never touch me, ever!" -- and those different facets of the premise sparkle to light. You understand it without the burden of over-narration; you understand simply, just as it happens. <i>He can't protect her. He can't even comfort her</i>. You watch her sob and sob and the spirit sits close by, face hidden by his mask.<br /><br />When people say that they just <i>had</i>&nbsp;to keep reading/watching/consuming because they want to see what will happen -- this story really dazed me with that desperation. The conflict seems so <i>impossible</i>&nbsp;-- you know what's going to happen, what <i>must</i>&nbsp;happen -- but does it? Is there any other way that this story could end?<br /><br />Do yourself a favor and find out! :)</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
Where can I find this? I would like to watch/read it!</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Ascension Pre-Release Winningness]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/30/dark-ascension-pre-release-winningness/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/30/dark-ascension-pre-release-winningness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-szKW5qj_m14/TybP6QCSKkI/AAAAAAAAAoU/S9MQMemd3nY/s1600/IMG_0217%255B1%255D.JPG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-szKW5qj_m14/TybP6QCSKkI/AAAAAAAAAoU/S9MQMemd3nY/s320/IMG_0217%255B1%255D.JPG" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the coveted booster packs</td></tr></tbody></table><br />This past Saturday I went to my first sealed tournament for the pre-release of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_Ascension">Dark Ascension</a>!  We went to Greenlake Games first with a couple of friends, where every table had a nice mat and every participant received a nifty Companion Cube-looking <a href="http://irondie.com/">Irondie</a>.<br /><br />Sealed competitions go like this:<br /><ol><li>Get 6 packs of cards (in this case, 3 of Dark Ascension, 3 of Innistrad)</li><li>Open everything</li><li>Make a 40-card deck</li><li>FIGHT</li></ol>First pack rare: Geist of Saint Traft.  <em>AHHHH</em>.  And in the same pack: Instigator Gang!<br /><br />I was also excited to try and get some <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/01/mtg-lambholt-elder.html">Lambholt Elders</a> and ended up just getting three of them in all of my Dark Ascension packs (and even a holographic one!).<br /><br />In the end I created a green/white deck splashing both blue and red for Geist and Instigator.  I've never tried to use four colors before and felt super risky (oftentimes I would take a 5-mana hand just because I had all the colors in it), but when I was not completely mana-screwed I actually did fairly well!  I won three of my four sets and won six extra booster packs.<br /><br />Some memorable moments:<br /><ul><li>In one game: I attacked with Pitchburn Devils, dealt 3 damage to the other player, then next turn brought Pitchburn back with Haunted Fengraf, sacrificed him to equip Somberwald Dryad with Demonmail Hauberk, dealt 3 damage to the other player, then swung with Somberwald who was unblockable due to Forestwalk.  The last point of damage was done by casting Fling and sacrificing my 1/2 Lambholt Elder, haha.</li><li>In my last game: me and the other player were down to <em>dat wire</em>, him with a Galvanic Juggernaut that kept coming back upright with the undying death of his Young Wolf.  I took three hits for 15 damage from the Juggernaut but then was at exactly 5 health, which triggered the Fateful Hour of my Thraben Doomsayer and buffed both my Silverpelt Werewolf and Somberwald Dryad.  It was close until Andou came by to check out our game and realized that we had both forgotten all about the Fateful hour for the Village Survivors that I had out, since it was covered up by a Chant of the Skifsang -- at which point I swung with all my Vigilant creatures and it was over.</li><li>In another game: my first hand had two plains, three forests, a Thraben Doomsayer, and a Gravetiller Wurm.  Over the course of the next couple turns I spawned a human, brought Gravetiller in with Morbid, equipped him with a Demonmail Hauberk and some more Morbid counters thanks to a Hunger of the Howlpack and another human token, and, there it was: a massive 15/13 monster trampling everywhere.</li></ul><br />I have Lorin to thank for making full use of Demonmail, since he cleaned me out with it at <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2011/12/mtg-my-second-ever-draft.html">our last draft</a> and before that point I hadn't made the connection between Demonmail and how easy it made triggering Morbid since I could sacrifice a creature whenever I wished.  Andou read some of the design notes for this set to me; the point of Dark Ascension is that everything is getting dark and awful and worse, the world is teeming with monsters, and I definitely felt the design encouraging me to kill things, to take advantage of death, especially of that of meager 1/1 Human tokens.  Fateful Hour was also fun to trigger, though being at the point of death stresses me out, and in general during all the games playing with strangers I could feel my hands shaking with competitive tension.<br /><br />Later our group went over to The Dreaming to do <em>another</em> sealed tourney, but I didn't do so well in that one, so, the only memorable moment I've got is when Andou pulled a Huntmaster of the Fells and later gave it to me.  Dark Ascension werewolves, here I come!<br /><br /><br /><b>Decklist</b><br /><i>Creatures</i><br />3x Lambholt Elder<br />1x Pitchburn Devils<br />1x Instigator Gang<br />1x Geistcatcher's Rig<br />1x Village Survivors<br />1x Gravetiller Wurm<br />1x Somberwald Dryad<br />1x Thraben Doomsayer<br />1x Geist of Saint Traft<br /><br /><i>Spells/Artifacts</i><br />1x Fling<br />1x Gather the Townsfolk<br />1x Hunger of the Howlpack<br />1x Ghostly Possession<br />1x Skillful Lunge<br />1x Curse of Stalked Prey<br />1x Burning Oil<br />1x Demonmail Hauberk<br />1x Midnight Haunting<br />1x Bonds of Faith<br /><i><br /></i><i>Lands</i><br />6x Forest<br />6x Plains<br />3x Island <br />2x Mountain<br />1x Evolving Wilds<br />1x Haunted Fengraf</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Story in Trauma Team]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s1600/traumateam.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="163" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s320/traumateam.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.joystiq.com/2010/04/28/trauma-team-wii-review/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Time saved from <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/01/past-couple-days-in-series-of-instagram.html">not commuting during snowpacalypse</a>&nbsp;was spent playing Trauma Team, which I ordered (according to this hastily searched-up Amazon receipt) last March. &nbsp;(Spoilers ahead.)<br /><br />I adore the time-management micro-activities of Trauma Center, but was still surprised to find out how much I flat-out <i>enjoyed </i>Trauma Team. &nbsp;The fakey manga cutscenes re-used a lot of character art and implemented some tricks (scaling and translating a car, for example, instead of an actual animation of it driving off into the sunset), but I still enjoyed it much more than any dead-eyed mannequin gestures that seem to fill up so much of the cutscenes I've glanced in super-budget games nowadays (though to be completely honest, I haven't really sat down and played a lot of them).<br /><br />Cutscenes aside, Trauma Team did a good job of conveying story through its actual gameplay, some memorable scenes being:<br /><ol><li>The part in the mall where Maria, the "first response" character, has to take care of five dying patients on her own. &nbsp;I love getting perfect scores on these games and every time someone died I quit and started over in frustration. &nbsp;I even left the mini-game to try another story-line, and returned later with a feeling of dread -- only to realize that it was rigged. &nbsp;The patients were <i>supposed</i>&nbsp;to be near-death; once you rushed through at least one of them, back-up would arrive and restore everyone to full health, bringing a once-impossible situation to now a somewhat calming one (complete with soothing, <i>don't worry, your friends are here </i>music). &nbsp;For that moment, I really <i>was</i>&nbsp;Maria, and experiencing her prime character flaw of over-independence, of trying to do everything myself. &nbsp;(Until struck the inevitable Japanese group-focused armature of "Let's all work together!")</li><li>The part where Gabe is diagnosing the soldier, who is struggling to be-"bro" you in an attempt to make it seem you have having "<i>meaningless, friendly conversation</i>" when in reality you are in the process of diagnosing his viral hemorrhagic fever. &nbsp;In this case, the characters speaking to each other and working together were embedded in the "verbal questioning" mini-game, which was pretty elegant -- a lot more elegant than just clicking through conversation, though the mini-game itself probably lent itself to storytelling pretty easily.</li></ol><div>Sometimes you could just <i>see </i>the inconsistencies between Japanese thought and expectation of the US, and how it "really is." An easy example is when the characters were at the mall -- shopping for groceries, which is fairly typical in malls in Asia, and not so much here.<br /><br />Another example: unlike many US-developed games, this game set in America had a refreshing amount of ethnic diversity in the main character cast. &nbsp;Can you name a character who was a Mexican woman off the top of your head? &nbsp;One for whom it didn't really&nbsp;<i>matter</i>&nbsp;that she had dark skin, one who wasn't "stereotypically Mexican?" &nbsp;How about a character who is potentially Native American? The Mexican character was, unfortunately, the subject of many a boob-shot, and was also pretty frustratingly&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tsundere">tsundere</a>&nbsp;at times; and in general the females all had the same, petite facial structure. &nbsp;Personality-wise, though, they were all strong and interesting, with motives that 100% did not involve getting with the men around them. &nbsp;(Though there was a bit of Maria/That Dark Brooding guy near the end...before he went back to his lifestyle of alternating between doing surgeries and jail-time.)<br /><br />Some bonus fangirling: the best part of this game, hands-down, were Kimishima's cases. &nbsp;I <i>loved</i>&nbsp;piecing together the facts, figuring out how someone had died (though most of them were pretty straight-forward), learning about Kimishima's weird "I can hear the dead" cellphone and the fact that other characters accepted that she had such a device without complaint ("You and your voodoo cellphone..."). &nbsp;Gabe Cunningham's voice actor (apparently <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travis_Willingham">the same as for Roy in Full Metal Alchemist</a>) had <i>so much life</i>&nbsp;(the best part being when he sang "chunky~~" at the American politician). &nbsp;Also, Atlus's bold, colorful interfaces are so&nbsp;fun to interact with.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
