<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Fangirling | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/fangirling/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-25T10:01:26-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hotarubi No Mori E]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
One of my favorite manga short stories, <i>Hotarubi no Mori e</i>&nbsp;by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Yuki&nbsp;</a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Midorikawa</a>, was just made into an anime film! I&nbsp;cried after reading the story, and I cried after the&nbsp;animated film ended too. One would think that already&nbsp;knowing the ending would have removed the emotion from&nbsp;the film, but I guess not.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s1600/hotarubi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s400/hotarubi.jpg" width="282" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">tears everywhere, seriously (<a href="https://minniemeorange.wordpress.com/2012/03/04/anime-movie-review-hotarubi-no-mori-e/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />[spoilers ahead]<br /><br />I haven't read much manga recently, but what stories&nbsp;I've read from Midorikawa still remain glowing in my&nbsp;memory. She always takes a single, strange premise -- <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=11498">a criminal investigator that can make people do as he says</a>, <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=6781">a boy who inherits his grandmother's "book of names" of spirits</a> -- and uses story to cast light into the unique possibilities given by that premise, really stretches and shines it out to its full potential.<br /><i><br /></i><i>Hotarubi no&nbsp;</i><i>Mori e</i> in particular is my favorite of hers, because it's so wonderfully concise, whole, and  focused. A human and a spirit meet and become friends, despite a peculiar limitation: if the spirit ever encounters human touch, he will vanish from the world.<br /><br />Significant events and points of growth in the characters' relationship revolve around the problem of contact. When the two first meet, they carry a stick between them to hold hands. One day, when the human falls from a tree, the spirit races to catch her -- before pulling back at the last moment to let her crash. Afterward, she weeps -- "Never touch me, ever!" -- and those different facets of the premise sparkle to light. You understand it without the burden of over-narration; you understand simply, just as it happens. <i>He can't protect her. He can't even comfort her</i>. You watch her sob and sob and the spirit sits close by, face hidden by his mask.<br /><br />When people say that they just <i>had</i>&nbsp;to keep reading/watching/consuming because they want to see what will happen -- this story really dazed me with that desperation. The conflict seems so <i>impossible</i>&nbsp;-- you know what's going to happen, what <i>must</i>&nbsp;happen -- but does it? Is there any other way that this story could end?<br /><br />Do yourself a favor and find out! :)</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
Where can I find this? I would like to watch/read it!</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Ascension Pre-Release Winningness]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/30/dark-ascension-pre-release-winningness/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/30/dark-ascension-pre-release-winningness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-szKW5qj_m14/TybP6QCSKkI/AAAAAAAAAoU/S9MQMemd3nY/s1600/IMG_0217%255B1%255D.JPG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-szKW5qj_m14/TybP6QCSKkI/AAAAAAAAAoU/S9MQMemd3nY/s320/IMG_0217%255B1%255D.JPG" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the coveted booster packs</td></tr></tbody></table><br />This past Saturday I went to my first sealed tournament for the pre-release of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_Ascension">Dark Ascension</a>!  We went to Greenlake Games first with a couple of friends, where every table had a nice mat and every participant received a nifty Companion Cube-looking <a href="http://irondie.com/">Irondie</a>.<br /><br />Sealed competitions go like this:<br /><ol><li>Get 6 packs of cards (in this case, 3 of Dark Ascension, 3 of Innistrad)</li><li>Open everything</li><li>Make a 40-card deck</li><li>FIGHT</li></ol>First pack rare: Geist of Saint Traft.  <em>AHHHH</em>.  And in the same pack: Instigator Gang!<br /><br />I was also excited to try and get some <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/01/mtg-lambholt-elder.html">Lambholt Elders</a> and ended up just getting three of them in all of my Dark Ascension packs (and even a holographic one!).<br /><br />In the end I created a green/white deck splashing both blue and red for Geist and Instigator.  I've never tried to use four colors before and felt super risky (oftentimes I would take a 5-mana hand just because I had all the colors in it), but when I was not completely mana-screwed I actually did fairly well!  I won three of my four sets and won six extra booster packs.<br /><br />Some memorable moments:<br /><ul><li>In one game: I attacked with Pitchburn Devils, dealt 3 damage to the other player, then next turn brought Pitchburn back with Haunted Fengraf, sacrificed him to equip Somberwald Dryad with Demonmail Hauberk, dealt 3 damage to the other player, then swung with Somberwald who was unblockable due to Forestwalk.  The last point of damage was done by casting Fling and sacrificing my 1/2 Lambholt Elder, haha.</li><li>In my last game: me and the other player were down to <em>dat wire</em>, him with a Galvanic Juggernaut that kept coming back upright with the undying death of his Young Wolf.  I took three hits for 15 damage from the Juggernaut but then was at exactly 5 health, which triggered the Fateful Hour of my Thraben Doomsayer and buffed both my Silverpelt Werewolf and Somberwald Dryad.  It was close until A came by to check out our game and realized that we had both forgotten all about the Fateful hour for the Village Survivors that I had out, since it was covered up by a Chant of the Skifsang -- at which point I swung with all my Vigilant creatures and it was over.</li><li>In another game: my first hand had two plains, three forests, a Thraben Doomsayer, and a Gravetiller Wurm.  Over the course of the next couple turns I spawned a human, brought Gravetiller in with Morbid, equipped him with a Demonmail Hauberk and some more Morbid counters thanks to a Hunger of the Howlpack and another human token, and, there it was: a massive 15/13 monster trampling everywhere.</li></ul><br />I have Lorin to thank for making full use of Demonmail, since he cleaned me out with it at <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2011/12/mtg-my-second-ever-draft.html">our last draft</a> and before that point I hadn't made the connection between Demonmail and how easy it made triggering Morbid since I could sacrifice a creature whenever I wished.  A read some of the design notes for this set to me; the point of Dark Ascension is that everything is getting dark and awful and worse, the world is teeming with monsters, and I definitely felt the design encouraging me to kill things, to take advantage of death, especially of that of meager 1/1 Human tokens.  Fateful Hour was also fun to trigger, though being at the point of death stresses me out, and in general during all the games playing with strangers I could feel my hands shaking with competitive tension.<br /><br />Later our group went over to The Dreaming to do <em>another</em> sealed tourney, but I didn't do so well in that one, so, the only memorable moment I've got is when A pulled a Huntmaster of the Fells and later gave it to me.  Dark Ascension werewolves, here I come!<br /><br /><br /><b>Decklist</b><br /><i>Creatures</i><br />3x Lambholt Elder<br />1x Pitchburn Devils<br />1x Instigator Gang<br />1x Geistcatcher's Rig<br />1x Village Survivors<br />1x Gravetiller Wurm<br />1x Somberwald Dryad<br />1x Thraben Doomsayer<br />1x Geist of Saint Traft<br /><br /><i>Spells/Artifacts</i><br />1x Fling<br />1x Gather the Townsfolk<br />1x Hunger of the Howlpack<br />1x Ghostly Possession<br />1x Skillful Lunge<br />1x Curse of Stalked Prey<br />1x Burning Oil<br />1x Demonmail Hauberk<br />1x Midnight Haunting<br />1x Bonds of Faith<br /><i><br /></i><i>Lands</i><br />6x Forest<br />6x Plains<br />3x Island <br />2x Mountain<br />1x Evolving Wilds<br />1x Haunted Fengraf</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Story in Trauma Team]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s1600/traumateam.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="163" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s320/traumateam.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.joystiq.com/2010/04/28/trauma-team-wii-review/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Time saved from <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/01/past-couple-days-in-series-of-instagram.html">not commuting during snowpacalypse</a>&nbsp;was spent playing Trauma Team, which I ordered (according to this hastily searched-up Amazon receipt) last March. &nbsp;(Spoilers ahead.)<br /><br />I adore the time-management micro-activities of Trauma Center, but was still surprised to find out how much I flat-out <i>enjoyed </i>Trauma Team. &nbsp;The fakey manga cutscenes re-used a lot of character art and implemented some tricks (scaling and translating a car, for example, instead of an actual animation of it driving off into the sunset), but I still enjoyed it much more than any dead-eyed mannequin gestures that seem to fill up so much of the cutscenes I've glanced in super-budget games nowadays (though to be completely honest, I haven't really sat down and played a lot of them).<br /><br />Cutscenes aside, Trauma Team did a good job of conveying story through its actual gameplay, some memorable scenes being:<br /><ol><li>The part in the mall where Maria, the "first response" character, has to take care of five dying patients on her own. &nbsp;I love getting perfect scores on these games and every time someone died I quit and started over in frustration. &nbsp;I even left the mini-game to try another story-line, and returned later with a feeling of dread -- only to realize that it was rigged. &nbsp;The patients were <i>supposed</i>&nbsp;to be near-death; once you rushed through at least one of them, back-up would arrive and restore everyone to full health, bringing a once-impossible situation to now a somewhat calming one (complete with soothing, <i>don't worry, your friends are here </i>music). &nbsp;For that moment, I really <i>was</i>&nbsp;Maria, and experiencing her prime character flaw of over-independence, of trying to do everything myself. &nbsp;(Until struck the inevitable Japanese group-focused armature of "Let's all work together!")</li><li>The part where Gabe is diagnosing the soldier, who is struggling to be-"bro" you in an attempt to make it seem you have having "<i>meaningless, friendly conversation</i>" when in reality you are in the process of diagnosing his viral hemorrhagic fever. &nbsp;In this case, the characters speaking to each other and working together were embedded in the "verbal questioning" mini-game, which was pretty elegant -- a lot more elegant than just clicking through conversation, though the mini-game itself probably lent itself to storytelling pretty easily.</li></ol><div>Sometimes you could just <i>see </i>the inconsistencies between Japanese thought and expectation of the US, and how it "really is." An easy example is when the characters were at the mall -- shopping for groceries, which is fairly typical in malls in Asia, and not so much here.<br /><br />Another example: unlike many US-developed games, this game set in America had a refreshing amount of ethnic diversity in the main character cast. &nbsp;Can you name a character who was a Mexican woman off the top of your head? &nbsp;One for whom it didn't really&nbsp;<i>matter</i>&nbsp;that she had dark skin, one who wasn't "stereotypically Mexican?" &nbsp;How about a character who is potentially Native American? The Mexican character was, unfortunately, the subject of many a boob-shot, and was also pretty frustratingly&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tsundere">tsundere</a>&nbsp;at times; and in general the females all had the same, petite facial structure. &nbsp;Personality-wise, though, they were all strong and interesting, with motives that 100% did not involve getting with the men around them. &nbsp;(Though there was a bit of Maria/That Dark Brooding guy near the end...before he went back to his lifestyle of alternating between doing surgeries and jail-time.)<br /><br />Some bonus fangirling: the best part of this game, hands-down, were Kimishima's cases. &nbsp;I <i>loved</i>&nbsp;piecing together the facts, figuring out how someone had died (though most of them were pretty straight-forward), learning about Kimishima's weird "I can hear the dead" cellphone and the fact that other characters accepted that she had such a device without complaint ("You and your voodoo cellphone..."). &nbsp;Gabe Cunningham's voice actor (apparently <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travis_Willingham">the same as for Roy in Full Metal Alchemist</a>) had <i>so much life</i>&nbsp;(the best part being when he sang "chunky~~" at the American politician). &nbsp;Also, Atlus's bold, colorful interfaces are so&nbsp;fun to interact with.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Despite Finals Week and Final Projects, I Read the Hunger Games by Suzanne Collins]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/03/16/despite-finals-weeks-and-final-projects/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/03/16/despite-finals-weeks-and-final-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2BzUgZiPNVY/TYDcexwhmBI/AAAAAAAAAJc/KFoG608uCWg/s1600/hungergames.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="456" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2BzUgZiPNVY/TYDcexwhmBI/AAAAAAAAAJc/KFoG608uCWg/s640/hungergames.png" width="640" /></a></div><br />I've never been so happy to get an e-mail from the library.<br /><br />On Jenae's recommendation, I started reading the first of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hunger_Games">The Hunger Games</a>.  It took a couple months for it to arrive, but once it did, I opened it <em>and didn't close it until I was done</em> (pretty much).<br /><br />What the heck?!  Katniss seemed at first to be almost a Bella-type character -- a little snarky, a little spiteful of the people around her, such as her mother -- but unlike empty, hate-for-nothing Bella, she had reasons and whys.  And at first I thought that The Hunger Games would be nothing new -- maybe something like Battle Royale and The Running Man put together -- but somehow -- it was just <em>perfect</em>.  A suspenseful story, full-fleshed characters with a lot to fight for, <br /><br />Luckily the next two books came in more promptly (maybe because everyone always wants to read the first book?) and I finished the second at 4:30am, and the third at the following 2:30am, and then just lied there in bed, exhausted.  It's so rare that you just find books <em>this good</em>.  So rare that there's a YA book about war that I feel treats it with the gravity and heartbreak that I feel war deserves -- makes you feel the pain of people you love dying, for no reason, just so that one person can be in power and not another.  And the pain that the characters went through felt so <em>powerful</em>...<br /><br />You really should just read it yourself o___o There's only a couple books in this world like these ones.<br /><br />After reading it, I felt more inspired to write the story that I've been working on since forever, to <em>really</em> write it, to make it this good.  But, I feel so in awe.  How could I possibly ever be this good?  How would I be able to put believably put my characters through this much, believably have them get themselves out of it?</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[9 Hours, 9 Persons, 9 Doors]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2010/12/26/9-hours-9-persons-9-doors/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2010/12/26/9-hours-9-persons-9-doors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_SdPKamJbrgg/TRglhlGN08I/AAAAAAAAABA/PNpzNMGiJPM/s1600/615TUJ3mI1L._SL500_.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="287" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_SdPKamJbrgg/TRglhlGN08I/AAAAAAAAABA/PNpzNMGiJPM/s320/615TUJ3mI1L._SL500_.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://pul.se/Gamertell-Review-999-9-Hours-9-Persons-9-Doors-for-DS_Gaming-Reviews-Exclusives-Originals-Handhelds-PSP-and-PSPgo-Game-Companies-Developers-Publishers-Genres-2D-Adventure-Game-Genres-Other-2nJObgsL997,uqCjaOHySfE">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Purchased this at the last leg of autumn quarter, right before finals, at which point Amazon decided to hold a sale that made me feel better about buying this at full price since I'd be getting Rune Factory 3 for $15 alongside it.  Since all the rave reviews on it made it so that it was sold out immediately at normal prices and is now being sold for $75 new, <em>best impulse buy ever</em>.  Plus, it's the first new (which for me means it came out in the past year) game that I've bought since Persona 3.<br /><br /><span class="shh"><em>jock jock jock jock jock</em></span><br /><br />(spoilers, etc.)<br /><br />Even though I heard <a href="http://30ninjas.com/blog/999-9-hours-9-persons-9-doors-review-a-triumph-of-narrative">the story was pretty good</a>, I was completely unprepared for HOW COMPLETELY AMAZING IT WAS.  All of the characters, despite being pretty average for an anime cast (one loli-ish girl, one intensely well-endowed woman, one trustworthy-looking old guy, one slim main character with long brown hair and bangs, etc.), turned out to be super interesting, even the girl characters, though I found the three of them in general to be rotating between three states:<br /><ol><li>being coddled (as with Clover being sulky about Snake, or June being head-patted or cooed at)</li><li>being grumbled at/teased for being bitchy (as with Lotus, everywhere...<span class="shh">though I did really like how she turned out to be a programmer, wooo</span>)</li><li>being held hostage (all three of them)</li></ol>Also, at the end, everyone was pretty much disambiguated except for Lotus; the only thing that's explained about her background is that she's a mother, and other than her daughters being a part of the original experiment, her connection with the game nine years ago doesn't seem to be as strong.  Seven was the detective who saved all the children, Ace was the object of revenge, Junpei was there for the ~*time-bending craziness*~ -- but why Lotus?  Her children weren't even prominent characters in the game nine years ago; they're only mentioned, and their actions have no weight on the story at all.<br /><br />Plus, if Lotus is a mother who is a programmer and also well-read enough to know about prosopagnosia and the various morphic resonance experiments, why the hell is she dressed like a dancer?<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_SdPKamJbrgg/TRgvOsmT63I/AAAAAAAAABI/lvzJDGdQGrs/s1600/999-9-hours-9-persons-9-doors-20101216021437355.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="287" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_SdPKamJbrgg/TRgvOsmT63I/AAAAAAAAABI/lvzJDGdQGrs/s320/999-9-hours-9-persons-9-doors-20101216021437355.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://ds.ign.com/articles/114/1140602p2.html">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I mean, I'm not saying that being scantily clad, being a programmer, being well-read, being the bitch of the story, and being a mother are mutually exclusive -- just that they're all character traits that aren't supported or explained at all, which makes Lotus completely flat.  In one otherwise great and well-thought-out narrative you have one character, a female, who is essentially just there so you can break up your visual novel and intense puzzle-ing with boobs.  But -- but it's fine, right?  She hits the men characters and knows about proso-whatever, so it's not like she's just there to be seen as sexual, right?<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_SdPKamJbrgg/TRgx4c-zoDI/AAAAAAAAABQ/r3HJmZldBeE/s1600/lotus2.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="192" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_SdPKamJbrgg/TRgx4c-zoDI/AAAAAAAAABQ/r3HJmZldBeE/s320/lotus2.jpg" width="256" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">DUNNO, BRO. (<a href="http://voiceactingalliance.com/board/showthread.php?t=60911">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />That was pretty much the only problem I had with a story that otherwise had me playing for nearly a week straight and throughout the night/morning by the time I reached the True Ending, though that was less a fault of compelling gameplay and more because I suddenly became terrified of everything and couldn't sleep until around 3am.<br /><br />Other notes:<br /><ul><li>The puzzles were really great, though if you click things enough times the characters will start to explain things/give them away.  I suppose this is good for the people who would just give up in exasperation if a game is too hard (the casual players everyone tries to cater to nowadays?) but it did mean that the game is considerably easier than Nancy Drew PC games, lululu</li><li>Super great localization...everything sounds really natural and there are even video game references, <em>waaaat</em></li><li>MINDBLOWING/INTERTWINING STORYLINES FTW &lt;3</li></ul></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
