<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Manga Recs | miscware]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/manga-recs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-05T17:09:36-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nat]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Manga: Noragami | ノラガミ, ADACHI Toka]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/25/noragami-rec/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-25T11:16:27-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/25/noragami-rec</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/animango/noragami.jpg" alt="Cover of volume 10 of Noragami, showing its three main protagonists"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/14290364-champion">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>At the boundary between this realm and another, there live eight million gods, dead spirits who serve the gods, and other assorted spirits who help and meddle in the affairs of humans. A sweet middle school girl named Mutsumi has been enduring bullying from her classmates, and she goes to the restroom by herself to cry. Scrawled on the bathroom wall is a phone number and the message, "I will solve your troubles."
<br/><br/>

After Mutsumi calls the number, she encounters a homeless, unemployed figure who proclaims himself a "god." Crude, unpredictable, and worthless, he does not answer people's prayers and no one acknowledges him. However, he has one sole power, the ability to cut all who pass between this world and the next. (<a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=56588">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>The previous manga description is strange because the character &ldquo;Mutsumi&rdquo; only appears in the first chapter&hellip;but, eh.</p>

<p>Noragami, the first story both written and illustrated by the ADACHI Toka team, <em>is my new favorite manga</em>.</p>

<p>The basic elements of the story are Shinto-style gods; their &ldquo;shinki,&rdquo; who are spirits of deceased humans who can take on the form of weaponry/animals/etc.; and &ldquo;ayakashi,&rdquo; or phantoms, the Bad Animal Things that exist invisibly in the world of humans. The main protagonists are Yato, a &ldquo;stray god&rdquo; without a shrine; Hiyori, a high school girl who, due to a car accident, is a &ldquo;half-ayakashi&rdquo; capable of astral projection; and Yukine, Yato&rsquo;s shinki, who can take the form of a sword. The story starts with Yato&rsquo;s desire to obtain a shrine for his own and delves into the ideas of what it means to trust humans and what it means to live to obtain (or be the source of) happiness.</p>

<p>[mild spoilers ahead]</p>

<p>Reasons why you should read it:</p>

<ul>
<li>The character development is incredible. Even characters like Yukine, who seemed poised to be ultra-generic gruff teenage shounen, grows into a kind of character I rarely see amongst teenage boys: both jealous and compassionate when it comes to people he cares about, easily hurt and full of pride and determination.</li>
<li>Though it starts with a lot of characters explaining painfully exact and detailed world-building to each other, the story continues on to fleshes out every aspect and angle of what you're told about. We start with a single god having a single shinki (Yato and Yukine), and then explore what it means for a god to have multiple shinki (as in the case of Vaisravana and her family), and what it means for a shinki to have multiple gods (as in the case of "Nora"). Each of these aspects come with examinations of the emotions and motivations of all the characters involved. <em>Ahhh it's so good</em></li>
<li>After the first big infodump, the story also introduces "new ideas" very smoothly. When the idea of "what happens when a god dies" is brought in, it continues to be picked up and played with by later events. <em>Which is so fantastic.</em></li>
<li>The art is beautiful! It has more of a "realistic" feel, like <em>Death Note</em>, and the characters are visually varied. <em>The characters are actually varied.</em></li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul>
<li>Hiyori isn't terribly interesting yet; she's struggled with wanting to maintain her relationship with Yato, but otherwise doesn't seem to have any personal problems to overcome, which is unfortunate. Whereas Yato and Yukine both have had their share of personal obstacles, Hiyori seems to be taking a "Fruits Basket Tohru-like" role in being "the one that supports everyone (almost) unconditionally." Still, she does call out other characters on their toxic behavior, takes none of that behavior herself, and has cool heroic moments where she saves both Yato and Yukine from their various problems (and <em>not</em> just by encouraging them to talk it out or merely offering phrases like "I believe in you!"...though those happen too).</li>
<li>Still, I have a lot of faith in this manga and I'm looking forward to Hiyori getting more development in the future.</li>
</ul>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
