<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Manga Recs | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/manga-recs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-23T10:13:34-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recently Consumed Delicious Anime and Manga]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/04/yay-anime/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-04T14:07:09-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/02/04/yay-anime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been getting <em>really</em> into anime and manga again, which happens occasionally. The last time this happened was with <a href="http://blog.neauro.com/2012-11-14-sword-art-online-so-pretty">Sword Art Online</a>, an anime I loved until the second season, which led the story down into an incestuous love triangle and a hideous, totally unncessary sexual assault scene.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s an overview of some anime/manga I&rsquo;ve found recently.</p>

<h2>Anime: Kuragehime / 海月姫 / Princess Jellyfish</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/animango/kuragehime_anime.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://sleepisfortheweak.org/reviews/micros/princessjellyfish">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>Amamizukan is an apartment complex where no boys are allowed. Tsukimi, a girl who adores jellyfish, lives there happily with her friends who all have nerdy obsessions of their own. Their peaceful lives gradually start to change when a beautiful woman helps Tsukimi out of a pinch. She stays overnight at the apartments—but it turns out "she" is really a "he". (<a href="http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/anime.php?id=11282">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Complete. Genre: Jousei/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>H has been heavily encouraging me to watch this series for years and I finally set aside time for it after finding it on Netflix!</p>

<p>Reasons why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>It's legitimately hilarious. Even A, who generally despises anime, enjoyed it. <em>This is really saying something.</em></li>
<li>There are varied female characters! With varied appearances and varied interests!</li>
<li>Kuranosuke's crossdressing/femme presentation isn't used by the main cast as something to belittle him.</li>
<li>Surprisingly, it's the only story I've ever consumed where I didn't really mind the love triangle and felt like I was rooting for both sides of it.</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul> <li>The ending is pretty sudden.</li>
</ul>




<h2>Manga: Kuragehime / 海月姫 / Princess Jellyfish, HIGASHIMURA Akiko</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/animango/kuragehime_manga.jpg" alt="Picture from Kuragehime manga"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.mangareader.net/kuragehime">via</a>)</p>




<blockquote>Kuragehime follows Tsukimi Kurashita, an 18-year-old who moved from Kagoshima to Tokyo to become an illustrator. Tsukimi is a jellyfish otaku who comes to live in a shared bath and toilet, women-only apartment, Amamizukan. Other tenants include fujoshi, NEETs and others who consider fashion their natural enemy, calling themselves "Amars". One day, Tsukimi meets a fashionable and beautiful girl, Kuranosuke Koibuchi, who saves a jellyfish that is about to die at a pet shop. She later discovers that Kuranosuke is merely cross-dressing in order to evade inheritance of his father's occupation as a politician. (<a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=38146">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Ongoing. Genre: Jousei/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>Being dissatisfied with the anime&rsquo;s ending, I chased up the manga.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should read it:</p>

<ul><li>Though the rendering of events isn't as funny as in the anime, it's still pretty cute.</li>
<li>(spoilers) <span class="spoiler">The manga doesn't make it look as if Shuu is falling in love with the woman sexually blackmailing him, which is good.</span></li>
<li>The author also has short manga detailing events in her own life, and they're *such funny wow*.</li>
</ul>




<h2>Manga: Dengeki Daisy / 電撃デイジー, MOTOMI Kyousuke</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/animango/dengeki_daisy.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://dengekidaisy.wikia.com/wiki/List_of_Chapters">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>After orphan Teru Kurebayashi loses her beloved older brother, she finds solace in the messages she exchanges with Daisy, an enigmatic figure who can only be reached through the cell phone her brother left her. Meanwhile, Teru meets and forms a strange friendship with mysterious Tasuku Kurosaki, her school's janitor. For some reason, Kurosaki always seems to be around whenever Teru needs help which leads Teru to wonder: Could Daisy be a lot closer than she thinks?</br></br>

As the mystery of Daisy unfolds, Teru also discovers that there may have been a lot more to the life and death of her brother than she ever dreamed...and that the man she thought was her friend just might have all the answers.(<a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=13582">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Ongoing. Genre: Shoujo/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>This was recommended to me by Tumblr friends.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should read it:</p>

<ul><li>It's <em>so cute wow</em>. If you need a heavy dose of thick, syrupy shoujo, this is it. <em>This is it.</em></li>
<li>Teru The Protagonist is an awesome female lead, and though there are some "damsel" moments, she mostly has impressive/fun moments where she saves herself and the entire day just when the author leads you to expect the opposite. (Wow such subversive!)</li>
<li>Teru also has friendships with other girls, both of whom she confides in and supports throughout the series.</li>
<li>There's a girl who could totally be slut-shamed, <em>and she isn't</em>.</li>
<li>This series is the first I've seen to depict a relationship growing significantly through communicating with each other digitally, which is pretty tight.</li>
<li>The main male lead is a HACKER! :'D</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li>It's really cheesy. <em>Really cheesy</em>. When you're not getting cavities, you're drowning in cheese. Though really, depending on your mood, this is kind of a plus.</li></ul>




<h2>Manga: Kamisama Hajimemashia | 神様はじめました / Kamisama Kiss, SUZUKI Julietta</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/animango/kh_manga.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.zerochan.net/1311703">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote> Momozono Nanami’s dad, a man with a penchant for gambling, disappeared after accumulating a huge amount of debt. Thus, she was chased out of her house by the debt collectors. When she met a timid guy being chased by a dog, he told her that he’d give her his house. She believed his persuasive talk, but when she went to his house… it turned out to be a shrine. Moreover, a guy with fox ears appeared, which made Nanami even more confused. What will become of homeless and confused Nanami? (<a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=24388">via</a>) </blockquote>


<p>Status: Ongoing. Genre: Shoujo/Supernatural/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve actually been reading this for a while, but it&rsquo;s worth another shout-out because I&rsquo;ve been re-reading it and it&rsquo;s one of my favorite series to date, right up there with <em>Full Metal Panic!</em>.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should read it:</p>

<ul><li>The supernatural premise is fun, and the majority of the characters have a lot of charm. (The only one I can't totally get behind is Mizuki, mostly because he seems the most unnecessary to the plot.)</li>
<li>Nanami The Protagonist gets stuff done! Woo!</li>
<li>Tomoe is a well-developed male lead. He has bangs, a dark past, animal ears, cooking skills — everything you could ever possibly desire on this imperfect earth.</li>
<li>I really love Suzuki-sensei's unconventional-looking art style.</li>
<li>*Time paradox!*</li></ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li>Recent chapters (specifically, 92 and 107) have had some uncomfortable dubcon scenes. Ultimately Suzuki-sensei has handled these scenes in an <em>alright</em> way...but I wish she'd have her characters call out and condemn the problematic aspects head-on.</li>
<li>The story recently has also been slowing down and felt uncomfortably off-pace, though I'm not giving up on it just yet.</li></ul>




<h2>Anime: Kamisama Hajimemashita / 神様はじめました / Kamisama Kiss</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/animango/kh_anime.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://mysticalcrimsonsky.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/kamisama-hajimemashita-new-image-revealednew-movie-for-2013/">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>After her father having run away due to gambling debts, and being evicted from her apartment, Nanami meets Mikage, a strange man who is afraid of dogs. Nanami "saves" Mikage from a dog and tells him her story. He gives Nanami his house as a thank you for saving him. Nanami accepts the offer, due to having nowhere else to go. Mikage draws her up a map showing her where to go. Upon arriving, she finds that it is a rundown shrine. Nanami is then almost killed by Tomoe, who was expecting Mikage to finally return after his 20 year absence. She is then greeted by both Onikiri and Kotetsu, as the new land god of the shrine. Unable to accept Nanami as the new land god, Tomoe mocks her then leaves the shrine, which, without Tomoe's power transforms back into a run-down state. Not wanting to rob Tomoe of his home and realizing that her powers as a god are too weak anyway Nanami leaves, but eventually is brought back by Tomoe after she seals a contract with him, making him her familiar. (<a href="http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/anime.php?id=14441">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>
Status: Complete. Genre: Shoujo/Supernatural/Romance/Comedy.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>Nanami's voice actress is perfectly casted. <em>Perfectly.</em></li>
<li>If you enjoyed the manga, you'd probably also enjoy seeing some of the scenes animated?</li></ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li>Nanami has less agency in the anime, and I don't Recent chapters (specifically, 92 and 107) have had some uncomfortable dubcon scenes. Ultimately Suzuki-sensei has handled these scenes in an <em>alright</em> way...but I wish she'd have her characters call out and condemn the problematic aspects head-on.</li>
<li>The story recently has also been slowing down and felt uncomfortably off-pace, though I'm not giving up on it just yet.</li></ul>




<h2>Anime: Free! Iwatobi Swim Club</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/animango/free.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.crunchyroll.com/anime-news/2013/09/25-1/second-season-of-free-anime-teased">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>Four boys named Haruka, Makoto, Nagisa and Rin all participated in a swimming tournament shortly before graduating elementary school and later parted ways. Years later, they reunite when Rin challenges Haruka to a race and wins. Not wanting to be defeated so easily, Haruka gathers Makoto and Nagisa and a new recruit named Rei to form the Iwatobi High School Swimming Club. (<a href="http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/anime.php?id=15291">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Complete. Genre: Comedy/Sports&hellip;?</p>

<p>How could I not watch this? After all, it&rsquo;s <a href="http://knowyourmeme.com/memes/events/swimming-anime"><em>the series that Tumblr made</em></a>.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>The animation is pretty. I even read on Tumblr that the actual swimming movements were pretty accurate. <em>Neat</em>.</li></ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li>The story is just alright.</li>
<li>Queer-baiting (used extensively here) is boring.</li></ul>




<h2>Anime: Kyoukai no Kanata / 境界の彼方 / Beyond the Boundary</h2>


<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/animango/knk.jpg" alt="Screenshot from Kuragehime anime"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.zerochan.net/1570806">via</a>)</p>


<blockquote>Akihito Kanbara is a high school sophomore in the literature club who believes himself to be a "Meganest", and although he appears to be human, he is actually half Yōmu, which makes him invulnerable to wounds, due to the fact that he can heal so quickly, and also immortal. One day, Akihito meets freshman Mirai Kuriyama when it appears as if she is about to attempt suicide by jumping off of the school rooftop. Mirai is isolated because of her ability to manipulate blood, which is considered heresy even among other members of the underworld, so she is shunned. Soon after Akihito saves Mirai, disturbing events begin to arise. (<a href="http://www.animenewsnetwork.com/encyclopedia/anime.php?id=15546">via</a>)</blockquote>


<p>Status: Complete. Genre: Action/Romance/Comedy/Fantasy.</p>

<p>I was lured into watching this anime because of the gorgeous animation and my instant affinity for the main character, who has red glasses not totally unlike my own. Also, &ldquo;meganest&rdquo; in the description above stands for the fact that Akihito is really into women who wear glasses.</p>

<p>Reasons why you should watch it:</p>

<ul><li>Like <em>Free!</em>, also by Kyoto Animation, the animation (especially with the fight scenes) is gorgeous.</li>
<li>If, like me, you are a sucker for the forbidden romance between a "demon-type person" and "demon-slayer-type person" — well, here it is.</li>
<li>I love the ending song, which is Stereo Dive Foundation's <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NaHx6oENn9s">Daisy</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>Unfortunately:</p>

<ul><li><a href="http://seventhstyle.com/2013/08/10/kyoukai-no-kanata-goes-moeblob-in-anime-pv/">The moeblob is strong with this one.</a></li>
<li>The ending was rushed and I...still don't really get what happened.</li>
<li>The two main male characters are overly obsesssed with their fetishes. It's annoying at least and disturbing at worst, especially since the girl characters they're focusing their fetishes on are clearly uncomfortable.</li>
<li>To be honest, this series as a whole fell flat for me, but the eyecandy was quite filling.</li></ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Delicious Rollback]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/24/the-delicious-rollback/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/02/24/the-delicious-rollback</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Right now I am totally in love with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julietta_Suzuki">Suzuki Julietta</a>. She is the manga-ka of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kamisama_Kiss"><em>Kamisama Hajimemashita</em></a>, which recently got propelled in my mind to 5-star status after it started acquiring a time paradox, a plot device to which I am particularly weak. (How could she have planned that?! <em>Hoowww</em>?)<br /><br />Suzuki has a great grasp of storytelling and character development, something that I really appreciate in shoujo manga. Recently I described <a href="http://www.mangahere.com/manga/kamisama_hajimemashita/c065/">Chapter 65</a> (and 66) to Andou as an example. It goes like this:<br /><br />Nanami is making talismans for the shrine, so that visitors can come and get charms for things like "traffic safety," "love," "prosperous business." Tomoe sees them and goes, "Your handwriting is awful, let's make new talismans on the nice wood that I stored away." Nanami admits that she thought that wood was trash and threw it away and feels bad that she's disappointed him and hasn't made much headway in being a good god. Later that night, she notices Tomoe leaving and follows him mistakenly across some ethereal border and is almost smashed by a giant's foot. Tomoe saves her, and they wander around the night market searching for new talisman wood. Eventually Nanami separates from Tomoe and discovers two demons bullying a child, and when she tries to intervene, the two demons go for her instead. Wracking her brain for solutions, she eventually leads them beyond the ethereal border, where they are promptly smashed. They sneer that she will get stomped on too, but Nanami smiles and opens her coat to reveal: a talisman for traffic safety.<br /><br />There's just something <em>so delighful</em> about the story coming back full circle. In a sense you should have expected it — maybe you had the fun of figuring out yourself how Nanami could have made it out of her situation — even if you didn't, your brain lights up to realize the importance of something so seemingly insignificant. The final talisman also serves to answer her insecurities about being a bad god (even if her handwriting is bad, it <em>works!</em>), and as a bonus, makes Nanami to me a little more "real" — more of a person who is reacting to things in her environment, learning about them, using them.<br /><br />It's just <em>great</em>, and by no means an isolated formula. For example, in <a href="http://www.mangahere.com/manga/karakuri_odette/v01/c001/">the first chapter of Suzuki's other work, Karakuri Odette</a>, Odette begins attending high school, much to the hesitation of the school administrators. "Don't worry," says Odette's creator, "if she ever runs into problems, she'll emit a signal to me, and I'll pick her up right away." They agree and as Odette tries to learn more about what it means to be human, she asks her creator to make adjustments to her body: first, to add the ability to eat food, and second, to subtract from her robotic physical ability so she's only as strong as an average 15-year-old. Odette finds a new friend who is sickly and occasionally has seizures, and wanders around with her to a construction site, where both Odette and the girl fall into a well. Since she asked to be weakened, Odette can no longer climb out on her own — but then the girl starts to breathe desperately and beg for medicine — so Odette says, "Look away, don't look back until I say so," and when the girl turns away <em>Odette removes her head from her body</em> — which triggers the signal, and makes her creator come running.<br /><br /><em>So good!</em> There's just something utterly delicious of a small detail turning out to mean everything. This is something that I think is a challenge to do with games. When you pick up a key in level 1, for example, it's hard to imagine that it could be used to anything other than a treasure chest. (Though, knowing that, it would be fun to purposefully subvert this and make the key into an instrument for something else.)<br /><br />I've never played A Link to the Past, but apparently there's a great example of "small detail coming back to bite you" in it. It goes kind of like this: In one of the first towns you visit, there's a man who describes a nearby building as the old home of some evil bandit who for some reason couldn't stand the light. You play on, and on, and eventually, you return to the old home, and rescue the maiden in it, who begins to follow you around as you make your escape. At some point, you set a bomb off in a room, which collapses a ceiling and lets the light in — and when the maiden walks into it, she rips her skin off and become's the bandit. <em>The bandit, the dungeon's boss, has been following you this whole time! Whoa! Ahhh!</em><br /><br />Delicious.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
