<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Magic the Gathering | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/magic-the-gathering/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T19:51:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Selesnya Hat]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/12/30/selesnya-hat/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/12/30/selesnya-hat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EYe_xhDQLEY/UODqJDGJpiI/AAAAAAAAC-I/wSIBPodiaAg/s1600/hat.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EYe_xhDQLEY/UODqJDGJpiI/AAAAAAAAC-I/wSIBPodiaAg/s640/hat.jpg" width="474" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">with bonus ears</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Hat! Fleece! Felt! The tree came out a little lopsided but I think it was good for a first try. I intended for it to have more of a chullo-shape but in the end confused myself and ended up just going back to the familiar rectangular shape the yields triangle ears.<br /><br />I have a lot more brown and white fleece left which I hope to use for future corgi- or shiba-related endeavors!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RTR Pre-Release!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/30/rtr-pre-release/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/30/rtr-pre-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
I went with Selesnya because of course. Playstyle-wise (and flavor-wise), I resonate with it more. Plus I love the security of green's fixing.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-uBFjufDIWRo/UGj3cpTY-kI/AAAAAAAACkk/CsSHHZ4wVDA/s1600/selesnya.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="556" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-uBFjufDIWRo/UGj3cpTY-kI/AAAAAAAACkk/CsSHHZ4wVDA/s640/selesnya.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">for the conclave!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I have to say I <i>really</i>&nbsp;enjoyed the set-up of RTR's pre-release, especially with the boxes and stickers and even a free little spin-down in guild colors (which I unfortunately lost somehow after my last match :( ). Izzet and Golgari were the first sold out at the pre-release that I attended, though I was so sure people would be eating up <a href="http://magiccards.info/query?q=archon+of+the+triumvirate&amp;v=card&amp;s=cname">the Azorius promo</a>. Selesnya and Rakdos were left for last, but after having the opportunity to play against all the guilds, Rakdos really seems to be the strongest in this format, to me, given that it can make use of <a href="http://magiccards.info/query?q=carnival+hellsteed&amp;v=card&amp;s=cname">Carnival Hellsteed</a> right off the bat (attacking as a&nbsp;<i>first strike 6/5 wat</i>), has many not-bad commons, and can even make use of Golgari's scavenge creatures (imagine scavenging counters onto <a href="http://gatherer.wizards.com/Pages/Card/Details.aspx?multiverseid=270349">Daggerdrome Imp</a> or something...wah!)<br /><br />My decklist:<br /><br /><i>Creatures</i><br />2x Azorius Arrester<br />2x Centaur's Herald<br />2x Centaur Healer<br />2x Gatecreeper Vine<br />1x Fencing Ace<br />1x Seller of Songbirds<br />1x Rubbleback Rhino<br /><i><br /></i><i>Spells/Artifacts</i><br />1x Street Spasm<br />1x Druid's Deliverance<br />2x Trostani's Judgment<br />1x Eyes in the Skies<br />1x Coursers' Accord<br />1x Call of the Conclave<br />1x Mana Bloom<br />1x Avenging Arrow<br />1x Explosive Impact<br />1x Sundering Growth<br />1x Seek the Horizon<br />1x Collective Blessing (mwahaha)<br />1x Izzet Keyrune<br /><br /><i>Land/Gates</i><br />5x Forest<br />4x Plains<br />1x Mountain<br />2x Selesnya Guildgate<br />2x Transguild Promenade<br />1x Izzet Guildgate<br />1x Grove of the Guardian<br /><i><br /></i>Populate is <i>so fun</i>. Out of all of the pre-release promos, <a href="http://magiccards.info/query?q=grove+of+the+guardian&amp;v=card&amp;s=cname">Grove of the Guardian</a> definitely felt like it was the one with the most synergy with its colors and keywords. The number of times I was able to pop and then populate an 8/8 token and was not insubstantial. And once I managed it, no one was able to bring it/them down, though one Golgari opponent kept fishing for his <a href="http://magiccards.info/query?q=abrupt+decay&amp;v=card&amp;s=cname">Abrupt Decay</a>, in vain. I'm glad that I decided to stick straight with a populate theme, though cracking a <a href="http://magiccards.info/rtr/en/183.html">Niv-Mizzet</a> in my first pack and an <a href="http://magiccards.info/query?q=epic+experiment&amp;v=card&amp;s=cname">Epic Experiment</a> in my second did make it so I was <i>really</i>&nbsp;tempted to splash both red and blue, which I'm glad I didn't.<br /><br />Something I missed was the keywords for RTR playing into some world story. Innistrad's keywords (transforming, morbid, etc.) really spoke to the general atmosphere of the world and its creatures, as well as providing interesting play. I guess the "story" of RTR really may just involve guilds all fighting each other, but it would be nice if there was something a little more than that, which you can soak up without delving into pages of a wiki.<br /><br />I ended up going three and one, and drew a Trostani in one of my reward packs! Constructed Populate deck, here I come~<br /><br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-LzGKc_AeqDA/UGj3dMkD5dI/AAAAAAAACks/Nkzs_H9VFx4/s1600/boosters.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="478" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-LzGKc_AeqDA/UGj3dMkD5dI/AAAAAAAACks/Nkzs_H9VFx4/s640/boosters.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">wooooo</td></tr></tbody></table><br /></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RTR: Precinct Captain]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/12/rtr-precinct-captain/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/12/rtr-precinct-captain</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Ohn7c0TVqzE/UFCekFRGjMI/AAAAAAAACfc/Y4TdZqzfKHg/s1600/Precinct-Captain.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Ohn7c0TVqzE/UFCekFRGjMI/AAAAAAAACfc/Y4TdZqzfKHg/s640/Precinct-Captain.jpg" width="456" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://mtgsalvation.com/return-to-ravnica-spoiler.html#6467">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><blockquote><i>Creature - Human Soldier </i><br /><i>First strike</i><br /><i>Whenever Precinct Captain deals combat damage to a player, put a 1/1 white Soldier creature token onto the battlefield.</i><br /><br /><a href="http://mtgsalvation.com/return-to-ravnica-spoiler.html#6467">via MTG Salvation</a>&nbsp;</blockquote><br />Oh yay, finally a human who's a person of color in RTR :'D<br /><br />Oh wait<br /><br />Wait, does she stand for the token?<br /><br />As in...<i>token black woman</i>?<br /><br />@__@<br /><br />I want to make some joke about how it can't be because "white Soldier," but I'm too tired of <a href="http://forums.mtgsalvation.com/attachment.php?attachmentid=135278&amp;d=1346743269">zombie trolls</a>, <a href="http://forums.mtgsalvation.com/attachment.php?attachmentid=135225&amp;d=1346644986">sphinxes</a>, <a href="http://forums.mtgsalvation.com/attachment.php?attachmentid=134534&amp;stc=1&amp;d=1346042458">elf shamans</a>, <a href="http://forums.mtgsalvation.com/attachment.php?attachmentid=135373&amp;stc=1&amp;d=1346990652">elephant soldiers</a>, and whatever the heck a <a href="http://forums.mtgsalvation.com/attachment.php?attachmentid=135129&amp;d=1346558716">shred-freak</a>&nbsp;is being easier to make up than <i>a non-white human doing something other than existing namelessly in the background</i>.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ravnica Guild Popularity Contest]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/10/ravnica-guild-popularity-contest/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/10/ravnica-guild-popularity-contest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-S3g0jRylQ1A/UE4fWvHOgMI/AAAAAAAACbc/JITahodS8LA/s1600/ravnica.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="514" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-S3g0jRylQ1A/UE4fWvHOgMI/AAAAAAAACbc/JITahodS8LA/s640/ravnica.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of <a href="http://guildsofravnica.com/">guildsofravnica.com</a></td></tr></tbody></table><br />I've been following the developments of the new block of Magic cards, my fervor for them having not waned with the passing of werewolf creatures. It helps that the next block is Ravnica, which I had always admired for its gorgeous lands; an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ecumenopolis">ecumenopolis</a>, it's the sort of world I would be hard-pressed to find alternatives for (unlike Innistrad's "gothic horror" world, for example).<br /><br />One social network advertising construct that WOTC is employing to hype up the release is this <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/tcg/productarticle.aspx?x=mtg/tcg/guilds/leaderboard">guild leaderboard</a>&nbsp;thing where you can join a guild of your choice and start earning points for it by participating in certain activities, like answering daily online quizzes. "Which card art has better sound effects?" "Which card art is better for doing chores?"<br /><br />Here's an unattractive but functional pie chart of the current points breakdown:<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kw0fBjSarQQ/UE4iFz6D0SI/AAAAAAAACcY/MBqAXxsOsNQ/s1600/ravnicapoints.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="341" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kw0fBjSarQQ/UE4iFz6D0SI/AAAAAAAACcY/MBqAXxsOsNQ/s400/ravnicapoints.jpg" width="400" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">with bonus mismatched guild colors, aaahhh</td></tr></tbody></table><br />It's cute and interesting how the top four guilds (red/blue Izzet, white/blue Azorious, blue/black Dimir, and blue/green Simic) all have blue. Assuming that the majority of people joined guilds thinking, <i>Yes, this guild personifies me,</i>&nbsp;does this mean that Magic players tend towards self-identifying as blue, which <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magic:_The_Gathering#Colors_of_Magic">Wikipedia</a> reminds me is "the color of intellect, reason, illusion, logic, knowledge, manipulation, and trickery"? I guess it makes sense -- I mean, you'd imagine that a strategic trading card game would draw in people really into logic/knowledge/manipulation/trickery/etc.<br /><br />If the most popular guilds are the ones that Magic players might see their own characteristics in, then what are the characteristics that players <i>don't</i>&nbsp;identify with, the ones of the least popular guilds? (Where "popularity" means not just joining the guild, but adoring it enough to complete arbitrary online activities for it?)<br /><br />Third from last, <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/tcg/productarticle.aspx?x=mtg/tcg/guilds/orzhov">Orzhov</a>:<br /><br /><blockquote><i>The Orzhov guild is founded on the beliefs that <b>wealth is power</b>, that structure breeds wealth, and that guilt creates structure. The guild is run like a combination <b>religion, credit-lending agency, and crime syndicate</b>. [...] Most Ravnicans see the Orzhov for the <b>corrupt organization</b> they are, but many are lured in by their promises of wealth, prestige, and longevity.</i></blockquote><br />Second from last, <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/tcg/productarticle.aspx?x=mtg/tcg/guilds/rakdos">Rakdos</a>:<br /><br /><blockquote><i>The Rakdos Cult is a large group of hedonists, <b>sadists, criminals, and psychopaths</b>...&nbsp;[...]The Rakdos Cult combines an instinctual bloodlust and desire for power. They’re sadistic and cruel simply for the fun of it. <b>Opportunistic violence</b> is their modus operandi. Mayhem and personal enjoyment is their goal...</i></blockquote><br />And finally, the Very Last, <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/tcg/productarticle.aspx?x=mtg/tcg/guilds/gruul">Gruul</a>:<br /><br /><blockquote><i>The Gruul are a loose affiliation of <b>savage clans who squat in Ravnica’s alleyways</b>, abandoned zones, and overgrown ruins. [...] Warfare among the Gruul is constant and almost ritualistic; the Gruul believe that <b>only the strong should survive and rule</b>. The Gruul are the most <b>anti-civilization</b> and <b>disenfranchised</b> of all of Ravnica’s guilds, and as such are the most ill at ease in a world covered by city.</i></blockquote><br />I guess it's nice that the guilds that are flat-out described as being filled with sadists and criminals are the least popular? And maybe the unpopularity of Orzhov is a sort of Occupy Ravnica thing? It's a little saddening to me that Gruul is the least popular, though. Out of the three of last-placers, it's the one that doesn't outright use negative words like "corrupt" or "violence;" on the whole, Gruul seems to embody poverty ("squat in Ravnica's alleyways;" "disenfranchised") and "savageness," which historically is used to point at people and say, "You don't know the same things I know and deem important; therefore, you are unintelligent and backward (and I'm never going to join your guild)!"<br /><br />Then again, it could just be a flavor thing; out of all the guilds, even to me Gruul seems unimaginative, compared to, say, <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/tcg/productarticle.aspx?x=mtg/tcg/guilds/izzet">Izzet</a>, which was intended to "provide solutions for public works projects (sewers, boilers, roadways), but...often produce mana geysers, spatial rifts, or arcane portals instead."<br /><br />Anyway~ After taking the quiz myself, I ended up as <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/tcg/productarticle.aspx?x=mtg/tcg/guilds/selesnya">Selesnya</a>. After taking the quiz a second time, I ended up <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/tcg/productarticle.aspx?x=mtg/tcg/guilds/simic">Simic</a>. Since both are sort of nature-y and less manifest destiny then the other guilds, I have to say neither of these results were unexpected. The flavor pages for both guilds also feature mostly women characters, which is pretty cool. Selesnya even has <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/images/guildquiz/guildpage/GuildImage_Selesnya_03.jpg">a non-white-looking humanoid creature</a>! (I'm still waiting for a non-white human creature; apparently, despite being denizens of <i>an entire planet</i>&nbsp;converted into a city, all humans are white. Shrug. Sigh.)</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Throbbing Core of Privilege -- Creature Enchantment]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/05/30/throbbing-core-of-privilege-creature/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/05/30/throbbing-core-of-privilege-creature</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-vw7Cohhh9SQ/T6Kq2Yt_v3I/AAAAAAAAA1Q/NOjV4rZYrIQ/s1600/privilege.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-vw7Cohhh9SQ/T6Kq2Yt_v3I/AAAAAAAAA1Q/NOjV4rZYrIQ/s640/privilege.png" width="483" /></a></div><br />Andou made this hilarious MTG card the other day. &nbsp;Why does it have 20/20? &nbsp;<i>Who knows.</i><br /><i><br /></i><br />Kelly points out that it is missing Lifelink.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
