<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ios | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/ios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-10T08:28:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dragon Flight, by Next Floor]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/09/10/dragon-flight-by-next-floor/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/09/10/dragon-flight-by-next-floor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-OO6Fgnn7kNU/UE4O8ZEDLCI/AAAAAAAACag/yGjzQ0zMHrQ/s640/blogger-image-1812206283.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-OO6Fgnn7kNU/UE4O8ZEDLCI/AAAAAAAACag/yGjzQ0zMHrQ/s640/blogger-image-1812206283.jpg" /></a></div><br />I haven't been playing iOS games recently, I guess due to a general boredom with the growing free-to-play population. The exception is <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/app/dragon-flight/id530610467?mt=8">Dragon Flight</a> by Next Floor, a simple dragon-themed shooter. Long story short: put your finger over the character, swipe left and right to eliminate rows of evil/cute monsters, collect the coins and jewels upon expelled upon monsters' expiration.<br /><br />Coins gathered mid-fray can be used to purchase increasingly expensive upgrades, which make your bullets cooler-looking and faster at killing things, which is nice. The system is clean-cut: farm dragons, upgrade to farm dragons better, farm more dragons. In the background is a high score based on how many meters you were able to cross before dying, which provides a pretty sensible long-term goal in each individual, short game. There are also power-ups you can collect mid-fray ("shoot twice as many bullets;" "become invincible and shoot forward for two seconds or so;" etc.) which mix things up a little.<br /><br />About the only bewildering thing to me is the other score system, which allots you points based on the types of dragons you killed, white dragons yielding like 100 points and tougher, yellow ones yielding 500 (or something). And sometimes when you kill a dragon a "2x" or "3x" or something pops up overhead? I'm still not sure what this means, though presumably it rewards the player for going on streaks of killing only a certain color of dragon, which is difficult to plan out when rows of randomly-arranged dragons appear and rush away in the space of seconds. I've been musing about what purpose having both a score based on "This is how far you went!" and a "This is how many points you won!" score might serve. For example, in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tetris#Scoring">Tetris</a>,&nbsp;clearing lines as soon as possible help you stay in the game longer (and keeps your stress level low), whereas making a "tetris" or clearing four lines at once rewards more points.<br /><br />Anyway, I haven't found my answer yet, but it may be because all I care about is farming dragons (<i>give me that 8000 coin dragon egg dammit omg</i>).<br /><br />Other slightly annoying thing: placing your finger directly over the player-character to navigate her obstructs her from view, which means it can be hard to catch falling treasure. Because the screen reads movement no matter where your finger is, I experimented with navigating the player-character while holding my finger near the top of the screen, but then I couldn't see where I was shooting. I haven't thought of any possible alternatives yet for this, other than tilt-based controlling, which seems like it would be too slow for twitchy treasure-catching.<br /><br />Anyway~ Dragon Flight is a simple and satisfying time-waster, but I can't wait until I can replace it with gardening and Return to Ravnica :D</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Off the Leash]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/03/21/off-leash/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/03/21/off-leash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
is the cutest dog-based tilt runner game that I've ever played, despite being a game in which it is difficult to play and get a screenshot which captures the excitement of running full tilt (ohoho) with a growing pack of thickly-lined canines. I only wish that there was a shiba inu, but then, I always wish this for everything, even things that don't necessarily include dogs in the first place.<br /><br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Mixvu6hl3zE/T2ovQKb4dkI/AAAAAAAAAr8/-lPWr3xePpg/s640/blogger-image-1447569057.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-Mixvu6hl3zE/T2ovQKb4dkI/AAAAAAAAAr8/-lPWr3xePpg/s640/blogger-image-1447569057.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of "off the leash"</td></tr></tbody></table><br />It's free to play, with purchaseable items being more (non-shiba) dogs, power-ups, and even a permanent "2x coin bonus" thing for 99 cents. &nbsp;At some point I unlocked "Tiki Surf Hut Bonus Thing Level" and searched around for it in vain, only to realize that its appearance would be a semi-random in-game&nbsp;occurrence, not something that I could summon at will from the main menu. &nbsp;Was this an example of "verbal, unexpected, informational feedback" that is so beloved of games that hold high the ideal of <a href="http://chrishecker.com/Achievements_Considered_Harmful%3F">instrinsic motivation</a>? &nbsp;Or maybe just UI that wasn't clear enough in informing me that it would reward me with such a bonus level after collecting X amount of steaks and Y number of dalmations during play? &nbsp;The world may never know.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-O6CiUATBERg/T2y5EYdhSiI/AAAAAAAAAsY/EdzBFRxnA_A/s1600/blogger-image-1979466662.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-O6CiUATBERg/T2y5EYdhSiI/AAAAAAAAAsY/EdzBFRxnA_A/s320/blogger-image-1979466662.jpg" width="213" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the crash of 38 dogs</td></tr></tbody></table></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Triple Town: An Addictive Tragedy]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/10/triple-town-addictive-tragedy/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/10/triple-town-addictive-tragedy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<a href="http://www.spryfox.com/">Spry Fox</a> recently released their game Triple Town on iOS!  It lags a bit and takes time to load, but it's a wonderful, addictive match-3-esque game.  It's freemium; the first thousand or so "steps" are free, and you can purchase more steps with coins you earn as you complete levels.  Or, you can purchase the game for $3.99 in the App Store.<br /><br />You match three "Grass" to make a "Bush;" three "Bush" to make a "Tree;" three "Tree" to make a "House;" and so on.  Bears emerge randomly and three of them, trapped between landscape features, become gravestones that coalesce into a "Church."  A starting board is a mostly-clear glade of grass and stones; successful boards are freckled with red-bricked civilization.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-_Y2LY7M-xcQ/TzFgCE8mlvI/AAAAAAAAApE/7zu4Cj_O_LI/s640/blogger-image-1126259615.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-_Y2LY7M-xcQ/TzFgCE8mlvI/AAAAAAAAApE/7zu4Cj_O_LI/s640/blogger-image-1126259615.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a screenshot of Triple Town</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I remember testing a bit of this game at the first <a href="http://www.seattleindies.org/">Seattle Indies</a> meet-up, and hearing Dan Cook tell me about how TT is at its heart <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/danctheduck/status/168044325006086144">a tragedy</a>.  The world starts bare and green, and inevitably you fill it with your colonization, reducing native bears to treasure-yielding clusters of churches.  I both appreciate this level of depth and am uncomfortable with this limited level of engagement of the important, sad, and real history of imperialism which still oppresses people today.  In this game there is nothing but to be the colonizer.  There is no success reachable through means alternative to keeping bears exactly where you want them, preventing movement until finally they homogenize into something beneficial to you.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-OFKgNppvbDc/TzFgCoQT5tI/AAAAAAAAApM/iOp5cEdbdg8/s640/blogger-image--987295304.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-OFKgNppvbDc/TzFgCoQT5tI/AAAAAAAAApM/iOp5cEdbdg8/s640/blogger-image--987295304.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">occupy, bears!!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Games go on until the entire board is filed with items, at which point any bears you have become gravestones and your score is tallied. &nbsp;Even when you lose, you still come away with something, whereas your "opponent", the bears, will always die.<br /><br />It's a wonderful game,&nbsp;<i>just</i> a game, <i>just</i> a brown bear and a gray headstone. &nbsp;But it does make me aware that some people can simply enjoy this game for what it is, even muse of its tragedy, and never have to feel like it's their own.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minesweeper Search]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/12/14/minesweeper-search/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/12/14/minesweeper-search</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Since it was free on iTunes some time ago (and then again yesterday), I downloaded <a href="http://www.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=5922851514316195975">Minesweeper of Wizard</a>.  I never did learn how to play Minesweeper with any complexity beyond a simple random-peck method until my smiley-face guy suddenly had dead "X" eyes, but it turns out Minesweeper is simple enough.  When you click a square and it reveals a number to you, that number is representative of how many bombs are located in the neighboring squares.  I have to admit that I am probably more pro at this game than I ever could have been before thanks to a course I took in computer vision, a.k.a. Find The Neighbors of a Pixel and Do Something 101.<br /><br />Minesweeper of Wizard ties several stages of minesweeping up around a loose story.  You are a wizard. &nbsp;You need to surface the world from darkness.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-0G4Gn3p79E8/TujWTjn9fxI/AAAAAAAAAjQ/1RtjlSvsoAs/s1600/IMG_0124.PNG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-0G4Gn3p79E8/TujWTjn9fxI/AAAAAAAAAjQ/1RtjlSvsoAs/s320/IMG_0124.PNG" width="214" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">adorable graphics</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Each stage is graded from one to five stars depending on how fast you completed the game.  And it was because of this that I stopped playing on level 5.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--NRRW00EqKM/TujWZLVNKUI/AAAAAAAAAjc/1gnSUumJQbk/s1600/IMG_0144.PNG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/--NRRW00EqKM/TujWZLVNKUI/AAAAAAAAAjc/1gnSUumJQbk/s320/IMG_0144.PNG" width="214" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">i hate you</td></tr></tbody></table><br />The type of person/player that I am is emotionally uncomfortable with passing onto next levels until I have completed things 100%.  I did pretty well on the first four levels, but for some reason I just <em>cannot</em> get more than four stars on that fifth level.  I started with a finish time of 1:20, played the level over and over again, managed to whittle my time all the way down to 0:40 -- and what do I get?  4 stars.<br /><br /><em>IMPERFECTION.</em><br /><br />Andou pointed out that some people can finish Minesweeper in a matter of eyeblinks, and yes, it's true that I did somehow manage to improve and cut my time down by more than half.  But still, this is <em>level 5</em>. How hard are the other levels going to be?! &nbsp;And it's not just your pure logic that factors into your time -- the game itself is the first I've played for iOS that actually feels non-responsive, and also lags.<br /><br />Minesweeper thirst having awakened, I went off to find a new app.  The one that I liked the best of the free apps I found is <a href="http://www.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=5922851514316195975">Minesweeper Free+ by Cookie Balloon</a>.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-trQOMYR9Ado/TujWsJ2LLCI/AAAAAAAAAjo/rQ9cbk5IPOc/s1600/IMG_0126.PNG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="214" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-trQOMYR9Ado/TujWsJ2LLCI/AAAAAAAAAjo/rQ9cbk5IPOc/s320/IMG_0126.PNG" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Minesweeper Free+</td></tr></tbody></table><b>Pros:</b><br /><ul><li>Chrome/Glowy graphics are nice.</li><li>No lag!</li><li>It provides multiple board sizes (easy, medium, hard).</li><li>It's exactly what it is.</li></ul><br /><b>Cons:</b><br /><ul><li>The little "flag a square!" button on the top-right is teensy and hard to press, and there's no visual feedback on the board that shows whether it's been selected or not.  Result: I often try to flag a square where I know a bomb is, and instead just set it off. :(</li><li>The message for "YOU WIN!" feels a little anti-climatic/un-victorious.  I just spent like 7 minutes poking this puzzle!  I wish there was a score or some other way that it tallied up how you did...maybe show a Bejeweled Blitz-esque graph or something of your progress second by second...ah well.</li></ul><div><br /></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q71ixkULEes/TujXCYKvWBI/AAAAAAAAAjw/8UDWL720Qio/s1600/IMG_0134.PNG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" height="213" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Q71ixkULEes/TujXCYKvWBI/AAAAAAAAAjw/8UDWL720Qio/s320/IMG_0134.PNG" width="320" /></a></div><div><br /></div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mega Mall Tummy]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/12/08/mega-mall-tummy/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2011/12/08/mega-mall-tummy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-JYTjhDrZSfM/TuEaWCCf_1I/AAAAAAAAAi8/ScxR2jxrSVk/s1600/IMG_0140__m3.PNG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="213" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-JYTjhDrZSfM/TuEaWCCf_1I/AAAAAAAAAi8/ScxR2jxrSVk/s320/IMG_0140__m3.PNG" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">year 3, month 3</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Things I love about Mega Mall Story:<br /><ul><li>The pixel-y art.  It's not the sharpest thing around, but seeing little cakes float above my mall shoppers as they purcahse is pretty endearing.</li><li>Also endearing: the characters themselves. "<em>I like stores where I can buy food.</em>" Suddenly, these pixels have hopes and dreams.  Suddenly I am investing in communities, not just raw consumerism!</li><li>How the game doesn't force things to become obsolete as you unlock new, better stores -- just more complex.</li></ul><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-h9BGXxILsqs/TuEaWtCKCmI/AAAAAAAAAjE/or5ESzU08R4/s1600/IMG_0142__m5.PNG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="213" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-h9BGXxILsqs/TuEaWtCKCmI/AAAAAAAAAjE/or5ESzU08R4/s320/IMG_0142__m5.PNG" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">year 3, month 5</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I have to say Tummy Mall is doing pretty well.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
