<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movie Review | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/movie-review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T19:24:11-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hotarubi No Mori E]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/10/22/hotarubi-no-mori-e</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
One of my favorite manga short stories, <i>Hotarubi no Mori e</i>&nbsp;by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Yuki&nbsp;</a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yuki_Midorikawa">Midorikawa</a>, was just made into an anime film! I&nbsp;cried after reading the story, and I cried after the&nbsp;animated film ended too. One would think that already&nbsp;knowing the ending would have removed the emotion from&nbsp;the film, but I guess not.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s1600/hotarubi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9xC2N3Su410/UIXweCUhwMI/AAAAAAAACq4/dbbR2tLSPQg/s400/hotarubi.jpg" width="282" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">tears everywhere, seriously (<a href="https://minniemeorange.wordpress.com/2012/03/04/anime-movie-review-hotarubi-no-mori-e/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />[spoilers ahead]<br /><br />I haven't read much manga recently, but what stories&nbsp;I've read from Midorikawa still remain glowing in my&nbsp;memory. She always takes a single, strange premise -- <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=11498">a criminal investigator that can make people do as he says</a>, <a href="http://www.mangaupdates.com/series.html?id=6781">a boy who inherits his grandmother's "book of names" of spirits</a> -- and uses story to cast light into the unique possibilities given by that premise, really stretches and shines it out to its full potential.<br /><i><br /></i><i>Hotarubi no&nbsp;</i><i>Mori e</i> in particular is my favorite of hers, because it's so wonderfully concise, whole, and  focused. A human and a spirit meet and become friends, despite a peculiar limitation: if the spirit ever encounters human touch, he will vanish from the world.<br /><br />Significant events and points of growth in the characters' relationship revolve around the problem of contact. When the two first meet, they carry a stick between them to hold hands. One day, when the human falls from a tree, the spirit races to catch her -- before pulling back at the last moment to let her crash. Afterward, she weeps -- "Never touch me, ever!" -- and those different facets of the premise sparkle to light. You understand it without the burden of over-narration; you understand simply, just as it happens. <i>He can't protect her. He can't even comfort her</i>. You watch her sob and sob and the spirit sits close by, face hidden by his mask.<br /><br />When people say that they just <i>had</i>&nbsp;to keep reading/watching/consuming because they want to see what will happen -- this story really dazed me with that desperation. The conflict seems so <i>impossible</i>&nbsp;-- you know what's going to happen, what <i>must</i>&nbsp;happen -- but does it? Is there any other way that this story could end?<br /><br />Do yourself a favor and find out! :)</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>axcho</div>
<div class='content'>
Where can I find this? I would like to watch/read it!</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
