<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Pokemon | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/pokemon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-23T10:13:34-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cultural Differences Across Pokemon X & Y Websites]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s1600/pokemonxy.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s640/pokemonxy.jpg" width="510" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshots of the websites for Pokemon X &amp; Y<br />Japan (above), Netherlands (bottom)</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1">A couple weeks ago we analyzed the marketing sites for Pokemon X and Y across different countries. It turns out that all sites for Pokemon X and Y are the same — except for the one in Japan, which is shown at the top of the screenshot above.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">The differences between the Japanese site and the rest-of-the-world sites include:</div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><h4>Feature Descriptions</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain more information about the game, for example, direct links to features like the Pokemon Global Link; on the Japanese site, these are internal.</div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Hype</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites feature a large image carousel on their homepage, which shows other features of the game, all shown to excite:&nbsp;<i>Discover the Might of Mega-Evolved Pokemon! A New World of Amazing Pokemon!</i></div><div><i><br /></i></div><div>In contrast, the front page of the Japanese site merely says:&nbsp;<i>Pokemon, heading to a brand new dimension</i>! (Referring, I think, to the 3D?)</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Obvious Marketing</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain immediate links to buy the game, as well as the 3DS; the Japanese site does not. (According to Julius, the 2DS isn't even available in Japan, perhaps because "Everyone there already has a 3DS!")</div></div><div><h4><br /></h4><h4>JavaScript</h4><div>The Japanese site has very little Javascript, and each page looks to be straight HTML. Additionally, text is often baked straight into the images, rather than being left as straight text, which is often the case in websites due to accessibility issues. (Text on images cannot be easily parsed by screenreaders. Some users also prefer to render text on websites to be more readable, for example, through the excellent&nbsp;<a href="http://www.beelinereader.com/">BeeLine</a>&nbsp;app.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Description vs. Instruction</h4><div>The Japanese site is more descriptive of the story and characters of the game; the non-Japanese site is more instructive of how to play the Pokemon game.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div class="p1">We chalked up the majority of the differences the fact that Pokemon is more popular in Japan; Japanese game-players may not need to be particularly taught about Pokemon, or persuaded to buy it. But, this exercise makes me more interested in other facets of Japanese web design. Why is there so much baked-in text, why aren't there fancy hover menu states, why is the design so flat compared to the chrome and bevels of the non-Japanese sites? Is web accessibility less important in the Japanese corner of the internet, or is it handled in a way that's different in the US?</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">One final note: out class lecture that week was done by Kate Edwards, current Executive Director of IGDA, who shared some cool stories regarding the "culturization" problems she's encountered when helping to ship games across international borders. Something she noted was that, in the Netherlands, "adult" games don't need to be localized into Dutch because the adults there prefer to play the games in English. So, the fact that the Pokemon X and Y site text is all written in Dutch…</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><br /><div class="p1">…well…you can totally still enjoy the world of Kalos as a grown-up grad student with a full-time job. Just saying!</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
