<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Phoenix Wright | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/phoenix-wright/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-10T08:28:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts Re: Phoenix Wright: Dual Destinies]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/phoenix-wright/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-23T11:03:14-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2013/12/23/phoenix-wright</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/aceattorney5.png" alt="Apollo Justice, Phoenix Wright, and Athena Cykes from Phoenix Wright: Dual Destinies"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.joystiq.com/2013/10/24/phoenix-wright-dual-destinies-review-f8ea4d29/">via</a>)</p>


<p>After NaNoWriMo finished, my pastime of choice during my commute became playing through <em>Phoenix Wright: Dual Destinies</em>.</p>

<p>[ spoilers ahead ]</p>

<p>Athena was a cool protagonist, though scenes where she was relegated to &ldquo;cyncial dude&rsquo;s naive, enthusiastic female sidekick&rdquo; were yawny. (Come on! Maya and Trucy are already these characters, we don&rsquo;t need more of them.) Ultimately it&rsquo;s nice to see that Athena has her own reasons for entering the attourneyforce, and though they were man-centered they were also totally platonic, which was nice. Athena&rsquo;s devoting to &ldquo;saving&rdquo; Blackquill also mirrored her desire to save her best friend, Juniper Woods, which meant her dramatic, heroic tendencies at least were in character.</p>

<p>Mostly I was happy to see old characters again, even Apollo Justice, who I disliked before but liked in <em>Dual Destinies</em>, probably because he was now a familiar face, haha. What I wanted most out of this game was to see Maya again, but I guess a note from her will do in lieu of <em>nothing</em>.</p>

<p>I also liked <em>Dual Destinies</em>&lsquo; execution of &ldquo;telling the end at the beginning.&rdquo; One of my favorite parts was realizing that Apollo had had an eyepatch over his eye even <em>before the courtroom explosion</em> — it was a fun/cute manipulation of the audience&rsquo;s assumptions that that particular bandage was just part of his injuries.</p>

<p>Good examples of &ldquo;the end at the beginning&rdquo; does <em>not</em>, however, include all the times that the game felt obliged to either tell you who the antagonist was, or make it clearly obvious, and PWDD&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://www.awkwardzombie.com/index.php?page=0&comic=123013">serious case of the hand-holdies</a>&rdquo; led to me to really only loving the game&rsquo;s final case, and feeling shruggy about the others. It would have been nice if each case had contributed more to each character&rsquo;s development as well; &ldquo;Ninetails Vale&rdquo; in particular didn&rsquo;t feel tied to anything in the larger story, and as a standalone wasn&rsquo;t terribly interesting to me either.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
