<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Project | miscware]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/project/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-02T07:48:52-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nat]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HCI Project: Kibisis]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/06/08/hci-project-kibisis/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/06/08/hci-project-kibisis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NquxxzjkWqk/Te_y1h2ACEI/AAAAAAAAAQU/Sc6yjlD-UkA/s1600/kibisis_logo.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="97" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-NquxxzjkWqk/Te_y1h2ACEI/AAAAAAAAAQU/Sc6yjlD-UkA/s320/kibisis_logo.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">logo by joy kim!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />For Introduction to HCI, we had a quarter-long project to design a ubiquitous technology.  I think that everyone ended up doing mobile phone applications, including us.  We designed <a href="http://www.cs.washington.edu/education/courses/cse440/11sp/projects/kibisis/process.html">Kibisis</a>, which is a mobile payment application.  Its main themes are:<br /><br /><ul><li>Connect your credit cards, debit cards, checking and savings accounts, etc. to one application, so that you can consolidate all your methods of payment</li><li>Keep track of your loans and debts to your friends, useful especially for college students who may split rent or loan money to their friends for dinner</li><li>Transfer your money directly, remotely, and securely from your Kibisis account to the Kibisis account of other people, removing the need to stop by banks to cash checks, or to get exact amounts of cash and then meet up to hand it off</li></ul><br />Listed above (and <a href="http://www.cs.washington.edu/education/courses/cse440/11sp/projects/kibisis/process.html">here</a>, again) is the website for our project, which contains all the reports we wrote, which details our testing and design process.  I made the website -- it was a lot of fun.  I really enjoy designing websites, though I concede that I could use more practice and more artsyness.  Probably more practice with Photoshop and Illustrator would help as well.  Every time I try to use Illustrator, I can never figure out how to make even the slightest mark on the canvas.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-X2B2h-qoEoQ/Te_0xOLbovI/AAAAAAAAAQc/WowuNtNZacU/s1600/kibisis_process.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="188" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-X2B2h-qoEoQ/Te_0xOLbovI/AAAAAAAAAQc/WowuNtNZacU/s320/kibisis_process.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">still, i'm really proud of this page somehow</td></tr></tbody></table><br />As we were working on this product, <a href="https://squareup.com/">some other similar</a> ones popped up, which was pretty interesting.<br /><br />Kibisis was the best group project I've ever had. :D And definitely a good way to close out undergrad years!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Across: Kongregate Release]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/05/23/get-across-kongregate-release/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2011/05/23/get-across-kongregate-release</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-FS01GyXZtMU/TdtOqq5GybI/AAAAAAAAAOM/KqG4OmKmecU/s1600/kongregate_users.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="197" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-FS01GyXZtMU/TdtOqq5GybI/AAAAAAAAAOM/KqG4OmKmecU/s320/kongregate_users.png" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the first 200-some players of our silly capstone game</td></tr></tbody></table><br />It's been about 24 hours since <a href="http://www.kongregate.com/games/getAcross/get-across">our first online release of Get Across</a>.  Our capstone class recommends moving from Newgrounds, to Kongregate, but then to Facebook, but it's taken us such a long time to learn Player.IO that we skipped straight to Kongregate, as <a href="http://playerio.com/documentation/quickconnect/kongregate">Player.IO already supports this.</a>.<br /><br />Still, our release was (to me) a little rushed, and I would have loved nothing better than to clutch the game even tighter and keep anyone from seeing it at all.  We have presentations on Tuesday on what our first round of releasing reveals to us about the game, and I haven't parsed through the data that we've collected yet, but an onslaught of a mysterious error regarding null quest objects made me really self-conscious about what was going on.  <em>I don't want anyone to play a game that is still buggy.  Nononononono!</em><br /><br />It's hard to debug from Player.IO's error log, though it is very informative concerning what errors popped up, whether they were serverside or clientside, when they happened, and how often.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UwlYNphQNgA/TdtRshfzMqI/AAAAAAAAAOU/u3pc3S_SXdQ/s1600/playerio_errorlog.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="186" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-UwlYNphQNgA/TdtRshfzMqI/AAAAAAAAAOU/u3pc3S_SXdQ/s320/playerio_errorlog.png" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">just look at those graphs, dude!</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Some of the players on Kongregate have been really helpful in leaving comments about their thoughts and the bugs they've encountered; but there are about 6 of these comments, and 200+ registered players, most of whom didn't really make it through the tutorial levels.  I have a good guess why: <em>the tutorials take forever to load</em>.<br /><br />I'm not sure why, but I'm guessing it might be because we have a lot of objects in the database, and a lot of the properties of those objects are nested objects or arrays, which must take longer to retrieve.  Seeing as tutorial levels are pretty essential for hooking in initial players, I'm hoping to make it so that the tutorial levels are completely static and client-side -- no saving data into the database, nothing.  If a player comes back, they'll just have to start over.  Hopefully this will make it so that we only really save "real" player data in the database as well, and keep out the clutter.<br /><br />So even though I really wouldn't have wanted to release the game this soon, this little bit of playtesting illuminated something that we otherwise would have learned at the last awful minute, for the final Facebook release.  Which is nice.<br /><br />As a sidenote, the last push I made to Get Across before the release were updated character sprites for our classes, "Cook," "Crafter," and "Planter."  Charlie drew the first set, which were endearingly derpy --<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-BpSQDmsoKDg/TdtS8xpShpI/AAAAAAAAAOc/xeVTMU2HQDw/s1600/old_classes.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left:1em; margin-right:1em"><img border="0" height="131" width="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-BpSQDmsoKDg/TdtS8xpShpI/AAAAAAAAAOc/xeVTMU2HQDw/s320/old_classes.png" /></a></div><br />And these are the more recent ones --<br /><br /><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-X1nWWgR4z_E/TdtTFRAwnII/AAAAAAAAAOk/QkC5Sdg-LI0/s1600/getacross_classes.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left:1em; margin-right:1em"><img border="0" height="131" width="320" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-X1nWWgR4z_E/TdtTFRAwnII/AAAAAAAAAOk/QkC5Sdg-LI0/s320/getacross_classes.png" /></a></div><br />Hopefully more character customization will come soon, though it's hard to say what we'll have time for.  2 weeks left to polish up the back-end code and the mechanics!</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
