<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Games | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-18T10:18:09-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts Re: Phoenix Wright: Dual Destinies]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/23/phoenix-wright/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-23T11:03:14-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/23/phoenix-wright</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/aceattorney5.png" alt="Apollo Justice, Phoenix Wright, and Athena Cykes from Phoenix Wright: Dual Destinies"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://www.joystiq.com/2013/10/24/phoenix-wright-dual-destinies-review-f8ea4d29/">via</a>)</p>


<p>After NaNoWriMo finished, my pastime of choice during my commute became playing through <em>Phoenix Wright: Dual Destinies</em>.</p>

<p>[ spoilers ahead ]</p>

<p>Athena was a cool protagonist, though scenes where she was relegated to &ldquo;cyncial dude&rsquo;s naive, enthusiastic female sidekick&rdquo; were yawny. (Come on! Maya and Trucy are already these characters, we don&rsquo;t need more of them.) Ultimately it&rsquo;s nice to see that Athena has her own reasons for entering the attourneyforce, and though they were man-centered they were also totally platonic, which was nice. Athena&rsquo;s devoting to &ldquo;saving&rdquo; Blackquill also mirrored her desire to save her best friend, Juniper Woods, which meant her dramatic, heroic tendencies at least were in character.</p>

<p>Mostly I was happy to see old characters again, even Apollo Justice, who I disliked before but liked in <em>Dual Destinies</em>, probably because he was now a familiar face, haha. What I wanted most out of this game was to see Maya again, but I guess a note from her will do in lieu of <em>nothing</em>.</p>

<p>I also liked <em>Dual Destinies</em>&lsquo; execution of &ldquo;telling the end at the beginning.&rdquo; One of my favorite parts was realizing that Apollo had had an eyepatch over his eye even <em>before the courtroom explosion</em> — it was a fun/cute manipulation of the audience&rsquo;s assumptions that that particular bandage was just part of his injuries.</p>

<p>Good examples of &ldquo;the end at the beginning&rdquo; does <em>not</em>, however, include all the times that the game felt obliged to either tell you who the antagonist was, or make it clearly obvious, and PWDD&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="http://www.awkwardzombie.com/index.php?page=0&comic=123013">serious case of the hand-holdies</a>&rdquo; led to me to really only loving the game&rsquo;s final case, and feeling shruggy about the others. It would have been nice if each case had contributed more to each character&rsquo;s development as well; &ldquo;Ninetails Vale&rdquo; in particular didn&rsquo;t feel tied to anything in the larger story, and as a standalone wasn&rsquo;t terribly interesting to me either.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cultural Differences Across Pokemon X & Y Websites]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/04/cultural-differences-across-pokemon-x-y</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s1600/pokemonxy.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IZKxZeym4hI/UnhNh5LTGHI/AAAAAAAAER8/ijPCNF5uWhM/s640/pokemonxy.jpg" width="510" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshots of the websites for Pokemon X &amp; Y<br />Japan (above), Netherlands (bottom)</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1">A couple weeks ago we analyzed the marketing sites for Pokemon X and Y across different countries. It turns out that all sites for Pokemon X and Y are the same — except for the one in Japan, which is shown at the top of the screenshot above.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">The differences between the Japanese site and the rest-of-the-world sites include:</div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><h4>Feature Descriptions</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain more information about the game, for example, direct links to features like the Pokemon Global Link; on the Japanese site, these are internal.</div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Hype</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites feature a large image carousel on their homepage, which shows other features of the game, all shown to excite:&nbsp;<i>Discover the Might of Mega-Evolved Pokemon! A New World of Amazing Pokemon!</i></div><div><i><br /></i></div><div>In contrast, the front page of the Japanese site merely says:&nbsp;<i>Pokemon, heading to a brand new dimension</i>! (Referring, I think, to the 3D?)</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Obvious Marketing</h4><div>Non-Japanese sites contain immediate links to buy the game, as well as the 3DS; the Japanese site does not. (According to Julius, the 2DS isn't even available in Japan, perhaps because "Everyone there already has a 3DS!")</div></div><div><h4><br /></h4><h4>JavaScript</h4><div>The Japanese site has very little Javascript, and each page looks to be straight HTML. Additionally, text is often baked straight into the images, rather than being left as straight text, which is often the case in websites due to accessibility issues. (Text on images cannot be easily parsed by screenreaders. Some users also prefer to render text on websites to be more readable, for example, through the excellent&nbsp;<a href="http://www.beelinereader.com/">BeeLine</a>&nbsp;app.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><h4>Description vs. Instruction</h4><div>The Japanese site is more descriptive of the story and characters of the game; the non-Japanese site is more instructive of how to play the Pokemon game.</div></div><div><br /></div><div><br /></div><div class="p1">We chalked up the majority of the differences the fact that Pokemon is more popular in Japan; Japanese game-players may not need to be particularly taught about Pokemon, or persuaded to buy it. But, this exercise makes me more interested in other facets of Japanese web design. Why is there so much baked-in text, why aren't there fancy hover menu states, why is the design so flat compared to the chrome and bevels of the non-Japanese sites? Is web accessibility less important in the Japanese corner of the internet, or is it handled in a way that's different in the US?</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">One final note: out class lecture that week was done by Kate Edwards, current Executive Director of IGDA, who shared some cool stories regarding the "culturization" problems she's encountered when helping to ship games across international borders. Something she noted was that, in the Netherlands, "adult" games don't need to be localized into Dutch because the adults there prefer to play the games in English. So, the fact that the Pokemon X and Y site text is all written in Dutch…</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><br /><div class="p1">…well…you can totally still enjoy the world of Kalos as a grown-up grad student with a full-time job. Just saying!</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lone Survivor & Meaningfulness]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/05/lone-survivor-meaningfulness/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/05/lone-survivor-meaningfulness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VLOhbqzGTUk/UBggO-tiRlI/AAAAAAAAB3g/4k3a6a5Q5kg/s1600/lonesurvivor.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-VLOhbqzGTUk/UBggO-tiRlI/AAAAAAAAB3g/4k3a6a5Q5kg/s1600/lonesurvivor.jpg" /></a></div><div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>0.</h2></div><div class="p1"><i>Lone Survivor </i>was the game I was most excited to obtain through a Humble Indie Bundle months ago, because the big grainy pixels looked so delicious, so fat with mood and atmosphere. And weirdness! And mysteriousness!</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Spoilers ahead.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>1.</h2></div><div class="p1">One of my favorite parts of adventure games is the characterization that rises through interaction with items. Do characters like a certain item, or dislike it? Does the item bring up deep heartbroken memories of the past? How do they parse and react, and what does their rumination say for who they are? I'm reminded of Nancy Drew's endearing enthusiasm for lifting up random objects ("This plastic DNA model will be useful!") and Phoenix Wright's skeptical amusement when things like puppies are added to his inventory.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">The most interesting item in the game for me was the toy cat, which I enjoyed petting all the time to accrue invisible "sanity" points. Engaging with the cat toy in particular puts you in the shoes and brain of the lone survivor himself, tinkering with a plush at the end of the world, just to have something light-hearted to do.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>2.</h2></div><div class="p1">Speaking of the cat plush, I loved the detail of this game — the unidentifiable flesh-like substances stretching across the wall — the way your map was dark unless you viewed it under sources of light — the specific food items like Delicious Ham, the creepy bottomless repositories of pills and Rotten Meats.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>3.</h2></div><div class="p1">A criticism of <i>Lone Survivor</i> seems to be that it was not scary enough. I played it at the height of summer and even then it was plenty terrifying, even if most of my stress and fear stemmed from being unable to hoard my bullets as obsessively as I would have liked.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">Another scary part: putting your hand in that horrifying pink-red flesh-pixel hole. I <i>really </i>did not want to do that.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>4.</h2></div><div class="p1">The dream sequences were cool, and the characters therein intriguingly surreal, which I loved. Ultimately, however, I didn't feel that these scenes contributed to a larger understanding of what was going on, which was disappointing. Rather than deep, the first ending I received was vague, and a letdown. After carrying and caring for this dude I'd wanted a little more than a whiff of a broken heart. I wanted to know more about what this girl meant to the protagonist, how her departure left his life with zombie-filled corridors.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>5.</h2></div><div class="p1">I got my ending by playing as paragon as possible. I wanted to see if other endings would give me closure, so I found them on Youtube. Each one seemed vaguer than the last, and didn't interest me that much. I don't have a particular love of multiple endings and for me it's because they lack impact: I've only rarely encountered any set that comfortably resolves all issues and tension introduced in the game, and the way that such endings are reached never quite seems to match the decisions you made to get there.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">In the case of <i>Lone Survivor, </i>the decisions that you make add to an invisible calculator which eventually spits out one of these endings: for example, killing more monsters gives you endings that imply you're mentally unstable. But why? What is it about killing these things makes you this way? The worst ending can also be achieved not just by killing monsters, but "eating food when not hungry or hurt" and "sleeping for no reason" (per <a href="http://lonesurvivor.wikia.com/wiki/Endings">this wiki</a>). What's <i>that </i>connection?</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><h2>6.</h2></div><div class="p1">This was my other favorite part: getting that white cat to come live with me. I guess it's strange to be saying that after my demands for meaningfulness, since other than the invisible points, hanging out with the cat doesn't reveal any more of the protagonist's inner story. But playing with the cat, I felt for the first time that I was doing something in the game that I personally wanted, like it was really <i>me</i> in there, and not me poking through things in a dude-shaped glove.<br /><br />Come here! Come <i>here</i>, little digital thing!<br /><br /></div><div class="p1"><i>come and be with me forever</i><br /><i><br /></i><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3tvhPIy5tDo/UilDcBOQcrI/AAAAAAAAEBc/f6aLd4GxHlk/s1600/Sunny.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3tvhPIy5tDo/UilDcBOQcrI/AAAAAAAAEBc/f6aLd4GxHlk/s1600/Sunny.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://lonesurvivor.wikia.com/wiki/Category:Characters">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><i><br /></i></div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Animal Crossing, & Not-Aloneness]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/07/17/exploring-animal-crossing-not-aloneness/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/07/17/exploring-animal-crossing-not-aloneness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-d2YWebFafi4/Uec6kxIgGhI/AAAAAAAADto/r1NyCt50kJI/s1600/tumblr_mp8o0yg4OF1qdycalo2_400.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-d2YWebFafi4/Uec6kxIgGhI/AAAAAAAADto/r1NyCt50kJI/s1600/tumblr_mp8o0yg4OF1qdycalo2_400.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">My character, Hito, and Felicity</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1">I haven't written much because I've started summer classes and also spending most of my recreation time in Shiba, which is the name of my Animal Crossing town. For my birthday weekend (some month ago now), I went all-out and scoured my hometown until I found the last remaining Animal Crossing Nintendo 3DS bundle, tucked away in the back of the Toys R Us game section.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">I've never played an Animal Crossing game and have to admit that the lack of farming bewildered me. <i>What? How can I really enjoy personalizing and caring for my world if I'm not diligently watering radishes every day? </i>Even when I started, I doubted I would really enjoy playing such a weird-looking human (the eyes too bright; the lower eyelashes so long!) rather than a cool, adorable animal. I started playing and suddenly it was two and a half hours later, exactly. (I know because of the 3DS Activity Log.)</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">So, what <i>is </i>compelling? For me, it's the exploration: being new to the franchise, every swing of the net or fishing pole in the first couple weeks brought me something new and cool to look at, and I imagine this capitalistic wandering is something like what my childhood would have been like if I had been a boy, or allowed outside to play and examine the foliage around my house. Though I'm sure I'll exhaust the novelty at some point, there's also, like Harvest Moon, a sense of <i>ichigo ichie </i>that brings a preciousness even to the cicadas that are fucking everywhere, just because they'll only be here until about mid-September or so — and then I'll have brand new things to check out.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1"><i>New Leaf </i>also does a fantastic job of connecting you to other people, in part through the capabilities of the 3DS, which I've never appreciated until now. Through the camera, you can share and import designs that other people have made, pixel-art style, including outfits from&nbsp;<a href="http://www.ign.com/wikis/animal-crossing-new-leaf/QR_Codes">Attack on Titan and Zelda</a> games and paths you can lay down to mimic having more&nbsp;<a href="http://newleafpatterns.tumblr.com/post/55173572156">water</a> in your town.</div><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1">Additionally, entire towns or houses can be shared through the "Dreamsuite" or through Streetpass; the former I've used to visit some uncomfortably terrifying towns (such as the infamous Aika and Hitokui), and the latter I'm excited to use each night when I get back home, perusing the homes of people I've passed throughout the day and hoping for good furniture to hoard for rooms I don't have yet. (Thus far I have both a "backyard" room and a "kaitenzushi and pastry restaurant" room planned…)</div><div class="p1"><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4XJdiXu1r8c/Uec75b8J2QI/AAAAAAAADt8/iDV0OAEbbpw/s1600/HNI_0087.JPG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4XJdiXu1r8c/Uec75b8J2QI/AAAAAAAADt8/iDV0OAEbbpw/s1600/HNI_0087.JPG" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">hito in...hitokui @__@<br />("kui" means "to eat")</td></tr></tbody></table><div class="p1"><br /></div><div class="p1">Part of this novelty is the 3DS's Streetpass itself — my digital headnod at the three people I Streetpass every morning on the bus — and part of it is just the weird delight of meeting people backward and inside-out — knowing, for example, that a fellow commuter is a strict interior designer and Nintendo fan (as shown by their vivid prize room), or that another also loves Attack on Titan (as shown by their "Scouting Legion" painting), before I know either of their names or genders.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">I'm not too much of a social gamer — I don't like playing competitively, and prefer to play games when I am completely alone — but I appreciate this variety of socialness, or rather not-aloneness, a way to get to interact with and get to know people in a low-stress, low-troll atmosphere.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">I've started reserving&nbsp;<a href="http://neauro.tumblr.com/">my Tumblr</a> for more "slice of life" updates and it's there that you can find more <a href="http://neauro.tumblr.com/tagged/acnl">screenshots of my Shiba adventures</a>, as well as my encounters with my villagers, who are acquiring quite the vocabulary.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gxj-vKhwHM8/Uec6tGQ5r7I/AAAAAAAADtw/GsYAGZyo68M/s1600/tumblr_moxg28e8Tq1qdycalo1_400.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gxj-vKhwHM8/Uec6tGQ5r7I/AAAAAAAADtw/GsYAGZyo68M/s1600/tumblr_moxg28e8Tq1qdycalo1_400.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">Julian is my favorite villager</td></tr></tbody></table></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bioshock Infinite & Forgiveness]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/04/22/bioshock-infinite-forgiveness/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/04/22/bioshock-infinite-forgiveness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9uZ6HN-IXTs/UXYTGzatClI/AAAAAAAADhA/KAfV2urg_hk/s1600/Bioshock-Infinite-Review1-620x350.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9uZ6HN-IXTs/UXYTGzatClI/AAAAAAAADhA/KAfV2urg_hk/s1600/Bioshock-Infinite-Review1-620x350.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.geekbinge.com/2013/04/18/bioshock-infinite-review/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><h2><br /></h2><h2>0.</h2>Bioshock Infinite spoilers ahead.<br /><br /><br /><h2>1.</h2>I finished <i>Bioshock Infinite</i> this weekend. I enjoyed it I guess. I play so few first-person shooters that I might as well go for the newest, most-polished one if I’m going to play anything while waiting (wistfully) for the next Metroid Prime. I have a penchant for headshots that seems to surprise people, but it is faster and cleaner and ultimately less squicky than melee in this game, which consists of scooping flesh from the faces of your opponents with a rotating hook-thingy. I saw the pink-red eye sockets of my first victim and felt ill and decided to go guns from then on, despite my usual powerful desire to greedily hoard any item I acquire in a game, including ammo.<br /><br /><br /><h2>2.</h2>The racism was also squicky. People seem to be very happy to engage in racism when it’s not real life, and defend its use as an edgy plot device. Ultimately I'm just exhausted by it, exhausted by black people apologizing to you over sudsy puddles, exhausted by Chinese people shouting for mercy in pidgin English before being disemboweled. I’m exhausted by the obsession of recreating racist worlds.<br /><br />In <i>Bioshock Infinite</i> you play as Booker Dewitt, and Booker doesn’t really care about racism one way or another. Oh, no, wait — I once ran into a black person who apologized for smoking in the back of a building, and Booker said something like, "Do what you want, I don’t care." That's Booker for you: except in combat, and except for the couple of times when he shouts after his sidekick, Elizabeth, Booker is cool as a cucumber. The setting of Columbia — the racism, the religion — slides off him like water off a duck's back.<br /><br /><br /><h2>3.</h2>Columbia (and its racism?) seems to be the system installed by its founder, a man named Comstock. Comstock later turns out to be you, which made something twist around in my stomach. <em>What?</em> How could Booker be Comstock? What in this story ever alluded to the idea that Booker could ever turn out to be Comstock? Booker is like a duck that’s been floating around in an indoor swimming pool, suddenly being told that with one little nudge he could have been the creator of that indoor swimming pool. Okay, not the best analogy, but look at him! He's a <em>duck</em>! How could he have gone from not caring about a black guy smoking in the back of a building, to someone who likens black people to dogs and says they should be thankful for the food and shelter given to them by their slavers?<br /><br /><br /><h2>4.</h2>There's really something to be said about how completely wonderful it feels when your brain finds patterns. I screamed with happiness when we ended up in Rapture again. I grabbed Andou's shoulder when Elizabeth looked over and said, "There's always a man, a city, and a lighthouse." My brain was like, <em>Hey, I know that! I thought that that beginning was all just homage, but it was on purpose! There's always a lighthouse!</em><br /><br />So that's what I wish I could pull in from an alternate dimension of game development: that Booker could have hesitated over racism — that he had had a chance to show that he could have been power-hungry, or obsessed with redemption, or obsessed with power enough to show how a the slightest nudge could have made him a Comstock monster. It would have been nice to see Booker reject his baptism and, when Elizabeth said there existed an alternate universe in which Booker accepted, to realize exactly what that meant. <br /><br /><br /><h2>5.</h2>Here was another fun part of the game's story: the first mention of quantum physics. Both Andou and I leaped and began to freak out. Oh my gosh, quantum physics. Quantum mechanics. Schrödinger's Cat. Is Columbia an epic experiment? Are we alive and dead?<br /><br />That paradox was so delicious that in some ways I wish that it had been everything, that somehow the setting could have abandoned its blaring, boring, meaningless racism and instead mused and ruminated on the significance or futility of our choices, and the consequences and not-consequences that bloom simultaneously after each. (Spare or kill? Bird or cage?)<br /><br />Booker already seems like a character set up perfectly for the agony of decision and regret: he kills Native Americans at Wounded Knee and seems to spiral downward from there, attempting (in one timeline) Christianity to clean away his presumed guilt. His room is cluttered with evidence of gambling, drinking. <em>Get the girl</em>, the game chants, <em>and wipe away the debt</em> — and imagine if Anna was some orphan he attempted to save, if she was a symbol of him trying desperately to do something good in his life, even if it meant the massacre of Columbia's peons.<br /><br /><br /><h2>6.</h2>Heck, the racism would have been way more interesting if it had been flavored with Booker's hypothetical thirst for forgiveness. Maybe the Booker that gets baptized can't deal with his being a murderer, and redefines people of color to be less than human to cope. Baptized Booker can't wait for his death to redeem him, so he takes heaven into his own hands, and decides who is saved and who is Sodom.<br /><br />As for the Booker that doesn't get baptized, maybe he encounters Anna on the way home, and uses her as his redemption instead. "I don't care how many people die," Booker could snarl at one point, "if it means that you are safe," if it means that his debts can be wiped away. Who are these Columbians anyway? Cult freaks — less than human.<br /><br />Ultimately both Bookers end up throwing away others for their own "Good." So how important was that baptism, in the end? How malleable is fate, after all is said and done?<br /><br /><br /><h2>7.</h2>There has to be room for Daisy Fitzeroy in this alternate dimension wish-fulfillment narrative as well, because I loved her before she was revealed to be an empty cliche of an Angry Black Woman. Maybe she could represent what it takes to forgive people who have transgressed against you, or what it takes to even decide whether or not people deserve to be forgiven.<br /><br />"Even you can be good again, Booker," Daisy might say if you made the right conversation choices. "Find forgiveness serving others." They can glance over at Elizabeth pointedly.<br /><br />"I'll have my debts forgiven, alright," Booker might mutter, still gruff.<br /><br /><br /><h2>8.</h2>All this forgiveness stuff could totally make Elizabeth's final standoff with her "mother" more impactful too. Maybe it could even tie in with Elizabeth's recurring issues with her supposed parents, her fury with them, how they "should" have been. How do Comstock and Booker try to protect her? How do their hopes and dreams live on through her, even when they die? Get it? Alive and dead at the same time? Eh? Ehhhh?<br /><br /><br /><h2>9.</h2>Yeah. A nugget of forgiveness would have been sick.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
