<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Game Design | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/game-design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T19:51:07-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Football: Great for the Audience]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/13/football/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-13T19:17:44-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/13/football</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past weekend I finally learned about football, something I&rsquo;ve never been terribly interested in. The most recent game I watched was Kind Of A Big Deal for the city I live in.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/sea2.jpg" alt="Rain and cars and a distant Seattle Space Needle."/></p>

<p class="caption">distant space needle.</a></p>


<p>It strikes me that football is an incredibly fun game to watch because the &ldquo;four downs&rdquo; system provides a multitude of little goals to rejoice about. Each play is rife with struggle, with a victory that can turn into loss in an instant. It reminds me of Mark Rosewater&rsquo;s description of <a href="http://www.wizards.com/magic/magazine/article.aspx?x=mtg/daily/mm/174">interaction and a catch-up feature</a> as things that &ldquo;every game needs.&rdquo; At each &ldquo;down,&rdquo; both teams have the potential not just to stop each other, but to improve their own standing. It&rsquo;s a powerful interval.</p>

<p>Watching the game this past weekend was the first time in my life that I really, finally <em>got</em> it. I didn&rsquo;t know there were separate offensive and defensive teams; I didn&rsquo;t know that there were people whose singular jobs were to run, or to kick, and that the had individual tutors. It&rsquo;s pretty inspiring.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/sea1.jpg" alt="Seattle Space Needle with a flag that reads '12' on top "/></p>

<p class="caption">#gohawks! and, fun fact: "the 12th man" is a copyrighted phrase. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/12th_man_(football)#Texas_A.26M_trademark_issues_and_Seattle_Seahawks_lawsuit">a phrase <em>not</em> copyrighted by us.</a></p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Invent-o-thon]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/inventathon/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T16:09:18-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/08/inventathon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A is starting a certificate program in game design this quarter and I&rsquo;ve been helping him with his card game, Invent-o-thon.</p>

<p>The prompt being something related to <em>Victorian Combat</em>, he first went around researching what people &ldquo;first thought of when they think about the Victorian Era,&rdquo; and I was happy to hammer in the presence of Ada Lovelace, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace">The World&rsquo;s First Computer Programmer</a>. Because I&rsquo;m more interested in stories, I also talked with him about stories — in particular, making noteworthy experiences that people are excited to talk to each other about after the fact. Or, in general, creating situations in which people&rsquo;s imaginations are prompted and stretch and fill in ridiculous gaps.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/playtest1.jpg" alt="What is a faith-powered tummy mobile?"/></p>

<p class="caption">what is a faith-powered tummy mobile FIGURE IT OUT DO IT</p>


<p>A obtained a bunch of card sleeves and post-it notes for our paper prototyping. The point of the game is to create an invention over several rounds, then present it at &ldquo;showtime&rdquo; to everyone and roll dice to see if your invention explodes. Thus far, players construct machines using three decks: one deck to describe a &ldquo;power source&rdquo; (like &ldquo;electric&rdquo;), one deck to describe a &ldquo;subject&rdquo; (like &ldquo;kittens&rdquo;), and one deck to describe the actual invention (like &ldquo;generator&rdquo;).</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/playtest1_cards.JPG" alt="Playtest cards"/></p>

<p class="caption">physically impossible bathtub packer</p>


<p>We also gathered friends to do a playtest at a cafe.</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/playtest2.jpg" alt="Playtest cards"/></p>

<p class="caption">kind of pathetic pleasure chamber...and others</p>


<p>One of the most valuable things learned from prototyping was which cards were compelling and funny, and which cards weren&rsquo;t — descriptive cards that seemed perfectly fine, like &ldquo;hydro-powered&rdquo; or &ldquo;solar-powered,&rdquo; were just not as fun to use as &ldquo;perfectly ordinary&rdquo; or &ldquo;rather moist&rdquo; and never quite made it to showtime. It makes sense that something like &ldquo;perfectly ordinary&rdquo; lights up more parts of your story-minded brain than &ldquo;hydro-powered,&rdquo; and overall could have more flavor. (What&rsquo;s a &ldquo;perfectly ordinary kitten-mobile&rdquo;?)</p>

<p>I sketched out some possibilities for card designs&hellip;</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/cardsketch.jpg" alt="Sketches of cards"/></p>

<p class="caption">sketches of cards</p>


<p>&hellip;and A also reined in his sister for some concept art of character roles that players could have that affected their inventions. For example, someone who was Benjamin Franklin might be able to totally swap inventions with someone else before showtime. (Oo! Sick burn!)</p>

<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/inventothon/concept.jpg" alt="Concept art of Nikola Tesla"/></p>

<p class="caption">concept art of Nikola Tesla</p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dragon Flight, by Next Floor]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/10/dragon-flight-by-next-floor/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/09/10/dragon-flight-by-next-floor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-OO6Fgnn7kNU/UE4O8ZEDLCI/AAAAAAAACag/yGjzQ0zMHrQ/s640/blogger-image-1812206283.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-OO6Fgnn7kNU/UE4O8ZEDLCI/AAAAAAAACag/yGjzQ0zMHrQ/s640/blogger-image-1812206283.jpg" /></a></div><br />I haven't been playing iOS games recently, I guess due to a general boredom with the growing free-to-play population. The exception is <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/app/dragon-flight/id530610467?mt=8">Dragon Flight</a> by Next Floor, a simple dragon-themed shooter. Long story short: put your finger over the character, swipe left and right to eliminate rows of evil/cute monsters, collect the coins and jewels upon expelled upon monsters' expiration.<br /><br />Coins gathered mid-fray can be used to purchase increasingly expensive upgrades, which make your bullets cooler-looking and faster at killing things, which is nice. The system is clean-cut: farm dragons, upgrade to farm dragons better, farm more dragons. In the background is a high score based on how many meters you were able to cross before dying, which provides a pretty sensible long-term goal in each individual, short game. There are also power-ups you can collect mid-fray ("shoot twice as many bullets;" "become invincible and shoot forward for two seconds or so;" etc.) which mix things up a little.<br /><br />About the only bewildering thing to me is the other score system, which allots you points based on the types of dragons you killed, white dragons yielding like 100 points and tougher, yellow ones yielding 500 (or something). And sometimes when you kill a dragon a "2x" or "3x" or something pops up overhead? I'm still not sure what this means, though presumably it rewards the player for going on streaks of killing only a certain color of dragon, which is difficult to plan out when rows of randomly-arranged dragons appear and rush away in the space of seconds. I've been musing about what purpose having both a score based on "This is how far you went!" and a "This is how many points you won!" score might serve. For example, in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tetris#Scoring">Tetris</a>,&nbsp;clearing lines as soon as possible help you stay in the game longer (and keeps your stress level low), whereas making a "tetris" or clearing four lines at once rewards more points.<br /><br />Anyway, I haven't found my answer yet, but it may be because all I care about is farming dragons (<i>give me that 8000 coin dragon egg dammit omg</i>).<br /><br />Other slightly annoying thing: placing your finger directly over the player-character to navigate her obstructs her from view, which means it can be hard to catch falling treasure. Because the screen reads movement no matter where your finger is, I experimented with navigating the player-character while holding my finger near the top of the screen, but then I couldn't see where I was shooting. I haven't thought of any possible alternatives yet for this, other than tilt-based controlling, which seems like it would be too slow for twitchy treasure-catching.<br /><br />Anyway~ Dragon Flight is a simple and satisfying time-waster, but I can't wait until I can replace it with gardening and Return to Ravnica :D</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[PSCS] Game Design Class 5: Sound and Music]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/06/pscs-game-design-class-5-sound-and/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/02/06/pscs-game-design-class-5-sound-and</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<i>This quarter I am facilitating a game design class at Puget Sound Community School for fun and lols. &nbsp;This is my story.</i><br /><br /><i>Other weeks can be found <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/search/label/pscs">here</a>.</i><br /><br />Last week's game was <a href="http://www.newgrounds.com/portal/view/587905">/ ESCAPE \</a>. &nbsp;It's a simple yet compelling game; you press the escape key to wall-jump, timing it right so you don't get&nbsp;electrocuted&nbsp;by spikes embedded by the walls or the huge laser approaching you from the bottom.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Y_rajI-3FEw/T0pxVu3Q9mI/AAAAAAAAArg/iUKjsetx2c4/s1600/escapescreen.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Y_rajI-3FEw/T0pxVu3Q9mI/AAAAAAAAArg/iUKjsetx2c4/s400/escapescreen.png" width="300" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of / ESCAPE \</td></tr></tbody></table><br />The students said they could feel a sense of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)">flow</a>, and that when they lost, it was in a way so brief and shameless that they found themselves launching right back into the game again without really feeling like they had ever "stopped" playing. &nbsp;The fact that the music continued to play on even after death contributed to this, and someone pointed out that the background music made them want to tap ESC to the beat, which was relevant, because the topic of the day was sound.<br /><br />I started with asking what games they felt had strong "sound design," whatever that means, and people listed off games like Metroid and Limbo for its sense of loneliness, Bioshock for its background music immersing you into its bygone pseudo-golden era. &nbsp;Andou supplied me with a particularly moving section of Limbo with which to show the class and everyone shuddered appreciatively.<br /><br /><br /><br /><center><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/i3wmQb7LWZc" width="560"></iframe></center><br /><br />Some applications of sound that I found presented on the internets, as well as some that we brainstormed:<br /><br /><ul><li>Sound can make you feel emotional -- sad, afraid, victorious</li><li>Sound can be used as positive or negative feedback -- <i>You did something right!</i> &nbsp;Or, <i>NO, STOP IT</i></li><li>Sound can be used to give NPCs life, i.e. when they look over at your character dashing by them in a loud rush</li><li>Sound can be used as a reward, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TgjHZa6Ag58">a la Zelda</a></li></ul>I also found and presented parts of&nbsp;<a href="http://cruiseelroy.net/2011/06/portal-2-music/">this very lovely breakdown</a>&nbsp;of what makes the music in Portal 2 so delightful and downright wonderful, which was good especially for me since I consider myself not extremely music-savvy, and I think would be hard-pressed at times to think about music and the effect that it's having on me and my psyche. &nbsp;Contrast with Andou, who at any given moment during a game or movie will remark something like, "Oh look, it's an intimate moment because romantic music is playing," and I'll realize that oh right, there <i>is</i>&nbsp;music playing.<br /><br />Following that article, I talked about encoded and embodied sounds, the ~*Universal Language*~ of music and how music in games, rather than speaking about the actions occurring <i>now</i>, may be more important in telling the player what will happen <i>next</i>: in the case of Limbo especially, blaring horns signal significant events, echoing splashes mean you're moving deeper into an enormous lonely world.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xpmvxtRvu9E/TzDJwo1gXCI/AAAAAAAAAo0/XXvw6iYdY3Q/s1600/wordloops.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="512" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xpmvxtRvu9E/TzDJwo1gXCI/AAAAAAAAAo0/XXvw6iYdY3Q/s640/wordloops.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a screenshot of wordloops</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I finished by showing them the game <a href="http://axcho.com/">Alex</a>&nbsp;programmed for the most recent Global Game Jam; something called <a href="http://axcho.com/wordloops">Wordloops</a>, based on this year's theme of "ouroboros."&nbsp;&nbsp;The idea is that you connect words together, starting the next word on the letter the previous word ended with, and after you fill certain criteria you "complete the loop" and proceed on to Loop N+1. &nbsp;Alex told me that it's much better to make loops of small words, since you're trying to get the most loops out of 3 minutes of play, but I personally found it really satisfying to make nice, long, wandering loops, and one of the students helped me see why: it's because when you type a letter, a sound plays, and that sound goes higher the more letters you play. &nbsp;It's the sound of <i>increasing</i>, <i>progressing,</i>&nbsp;<i>getting better</i>. &nbsp;And it's at odds with the idea that<i>&nbsp;the smaller loop is best</i>.<br /><br />Sounds!<br /><b><br /></b><br /><b>Sources</b><br /><ul><li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/2263/gdc_2005_report_what_makes_music_.php">Gamasutra: GDC 2005 Report: What Makes Music for Games 'Music For Games'</a></li><li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/2232/postcard_from_gdc_2005_gdc_mobile_.php">Gamasutra:&nbsp;Postcard From GDC 2005: GDC Mobile - Novel Ways to Use Audio in Games</a></li><li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/2189/enhancing_the_impact_of_music_in_.php">Gamasutra: Enhancing the Impact of Music in Drama-Oriented Games</a></li></ul></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[PSCS] Game Design Class 4: Winning, Hardcore vs Casual, and Gameplay Depth]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/30/pscs-game-design-class-week-4/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2012/01/30/pscs-game-design-class-week-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<i>This quarter I am facilitating a game design class at Puget Sound Community School for fun and lols. &nbsp;This is my story.</i><br /><br /><i>Other weeks can be found <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/search/label/pscs">here</a>.</i><br /><br />I'm a little belated with this post, if not just because I personally felt "meh" about it (which probably means that it might have been worse for the students themselves). &nbsp;Firstly, we critiqued Making Monkeys.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eyjfrSSrYVU/Tyd9DbYC5xI/AAAAAAAAAoc/HBrzqgLtUhs/s1600/makingmonkeys.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="460" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eyjfrSSrYVU/Tyd9DbYC5xI/AAAAAAAAAoc/HBrzqgLtUhs/s640/makingmonkeys.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of making monkeys, by <a href="http://greg-anims.com/">greg-anims</a></td></tr></tbody></table><br />The general consensus was that it was fun, unique, challenging. &nbsp;We pointed out the nice progression of the levels -- each one had something new to learn -- and talked about the types of rewards and goals in the design: the short-term win of the coffee cup, the long-term win of the entire game with your progress laid out visibly. &nbsp;The little narratives acted as both a silly reward for the previous level and a hint for the upcoming level. &nbsp;Some students found bugs but I didn't write any of them down, so they're Lost in Time and Space now.<br /><br />I couldn't think of a topic that I felt like discussing, so I chose <a href="http://onlyagame.typepad.com/only_a_game/2006/03/performance_met.html">this article</a> at random from a list of game design resources <a href="http://evolutionlive.blogspot.com/">Alex</a> gave me and just tried to talk about it, whiteboard and all. &nbsp;It was not too compelling and people were distracted, probably because "me talking" wasn't that intriguing.<br /><br />I switched topics then to the difference between "hardcore" and "casual" gaming, just to see what people thought of it (again referencing <a href="http://onlyagame.typepad.com/only_a_game/2007/08/game-literacy.html">another article from Only a Game</a>). &nbsp;Some of the students were adamant that the labels didn't mean anything, that "people just love games" and stereotypes seek to destroy the simple, human integrity of us all, to which I agree, kinda. &nbsp;I've always felt something snubby about declarations of <i>I'm a hardcore gamer </i>when all the game companies I've worked at have legitimate, game-loving audiences who can play just as much as any COD player, just doesn't relish the violence or complexity of it.<br /><br />An interesting term I learned in relation to the hardcore/casual duality was the idea of "game literacy;" that maybe an important delineation between hardcore and casual is not necessarily the time spent playing, or the motivations, but the breadth of game knowledge in general, and the ease with which one could pick up another game.<br /><br />Another idea was "game depth," and I tried to tie this together with ideas of winning and losing from earlier -- what happens in games when you "never really lose," but just have opportunities to achieve better, a la Angry Birds? &nbsp;What kind of decisions can you make in a game that is shallow, and one that has depth? &nbsp;How important are those decisions to the game itself? &nbsp;In Angry Birds, you can choose your angle and your velocity; in Tetris, your rotatation and speed; in a game like Magic, you can choose your deck, your strategy, your technique. &nbsp;It always seems like games with depth are "better," but I adore Limbo and concede that it's shallow gameplay-wise -- you solve the puzzles, you get to the end, that's it. &nbsp;I love story, but "Game" in its unique form is something that can be cooked and devoured a thousand times and still taste different the thousand and first.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
