<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Game Design | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/game-design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T19:24:11-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dragon Flight, by Next Floor]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/09/10/dragon-flight-by-next-floor/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/09/10/dragon-flight-by-next-floor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-OO6Fgnn7kNU/UE4O8ZEDLCI/AAAAAAAACag/yGjzQ0zMHrQ/s640/blogger-image-1812206283.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-OO6Fgnn7kNU/UE4O8ZEDLCI/AAAAAAAACag/yGjzQ0zMHrQ/s640/blogger-image-1812206283.jpg" /></a></div><br />I haven't been playing iOS games recently, I guess due to a general boredom with the growing free-to-play population. The exception is <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/app/dragon-flight/id530610467?mt=8">Dragon Flight</a> by Next Floor, a simple dragon-themed shooter. Long story short: put your finger over the character, swipe left and right to eliminate rows of evil/cute monsters, collect the coins and jewels upon expelled upon monsters' expiration.<br /><br />Coins gathered mid-fray can be used to purchase increasingly expensive upgrades, which make your bullets cooler-looking and faster at killing things, which is nice. The system is clean-cut: farm dragons, upgrade to farm dragons better, farm more dragons. In the background is a high score based on how many meters you were able to cross before dying, which provides a pretty sensible long-term goal in each individual, short game. There are also power-ups you can collect mid-fray ("shoot twice as many bullets;" "become invincible and shoot forward for two seconds or so;" etc.) which mix things up a little.<br /><br />About the only bewildering thing to me is the other score system, which allots you points based on the types of dragons you killed, white dragons yielding like 100 points and tougher, yellow ones yielding 500 (or something). And sometimes when you kill a dragon a "2x" or "3x" or something pops up overhead? I'm still not sure what this means, though presumably it rewards the player for going on streaks of killing only a certain color of dragon, which is difficult to plan out when rows of randomly-arranged dragons appear and rush away in the space of seconds. I've been musing about what purpose having both a score based on "This is how far you went!" and a "This is how many points you won!" score might serve. For example, in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tetris#Scoring">Tetris</a>,&nbsp;clearing lines as soon as possible help you stay in the game longer (and keeps your stress level low), whereas making a "tetris" or clearing four lines at once rewards more points.<br /><br />Anyway, I haven't found my answer yet, but it may be because all I care about is farming dragons (<i>give me that 8000 coin dragon egg dammit omg</i>).<br /><br />Other slightly annoying thing: placing your finger directly over the player-character to navigate her obstructs her from view, which means it can be hard to catch falling treasure. Because the screen reads movement no matter where your finger is, I experimented with navigating the player-character while holding my finger near the top of the screen, but then I couldn't see where I was shooting. I haven't thought of any possible alternatives yet for this, other than tilt-based controlling, which seems like it would be too slow for twitchy treasure-catching.<br /><br />Anyway~ Dragon Flight is a simple and satisfying time-waster, but I can't wait until I can replace it with gardening and Return to Ravnica :D</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[PSCS] Game Design Class 5: Sound and Music]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/06/pscs-game-design-class-5-sound-and/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/02/06/pscs-game-design-class-5-sound-and</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<i>This quarter I am facilitating a game design class at Puget Sound Community School for fun and lols. &nbsp;This is my story.</i><br /><br /><i>Other weeks can be found <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/search/label/pscs">here</a>.</i><br /><br />Last week's game was <a href="http://www.newgrounds.com/portal/view/587905">/ ESCAPE \</a>. &nbsp;It's a simple yet compelling game; you press the escape key to wall-jump, timing it right so you don't get&nbsp;electrocuted&nbsp;by spikes embedded by the walls or the huge laser approaching you from the bottom.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Y_rajI-3FEw/T0pxVu3Q9mI/AAAAAAAAArg/iUKjsetx2c4/s1600/escapescreen.png" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="400" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-Y_rajI-3FEw/T0pxVu3Q9mI/AAAAAAAAArg/iUKjsetx2c4/s400/escapescreen.png" width="300" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of / ESCAPE \</td></tr></tbody></table><br />The students said they could feel a sense of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)">flow</a>, and that when they lost, it was in a way so brief and shameless that they found themselves launching right back into the game again without really feeling like they had ever "stopped" playing. &nbsp;The fact that the music continued to play on even after death contributed to this, and someone pointed out that the background music made them want to tap ESC to the beat, which was relevant, because the topic of the day was sound.<br /><br />I started with asking what games they felt had strong "sound design," whatever that means, and people listed off games like Metroid and Limbo for its sense of loneliness, Bioshock for its background music immersing you into its bygone pseudo-golden era. &nbsp;Andou supplied me with a particularly moving section of Limbo with which to show the class and everyone shuddered appreciatively.<br /><br /><br /><br /><center><iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/i3wmQb7LWZc" width="560"></iframe></center><br /><br />Some applications of sound that I found presented on the internets, as well as some that we brainstormed:<br /><br /><ul><li>Sound can make you feel emotional -- sad, afraid, victorious</li><li>Sound can be used as positive or negative feedback -- <i>You did something right!</i> &nbsp;Or, <i>NO, STOP IT</i></li><li>Sound can be used to give NPCs life, i.e. when they look over at your character dashing by them in a loud rush</li><li>Sound can be used as a reward, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TgjHZa6Ag58">a la Zelda</a></li></ul>I also found and presented parts of&nbsp;<a href="http://cruiseelroy.net/2011/06/portal-2-music/">this very lovely breakdown</a>&nbsp;of what makes the music in Portal 2 so delightful and downright wonderful, which was good especially for me since I consider myself not extremely music-savvy, and I think would be hard-pressed at times to think about music and the effect that it's having on me and my psyche. &nbsp;Contrast with Andou, who at any given moment during a game or movie will remark something like, "Oh look, it's an intimate moment because romantic music is playing," and I'll realize that oh right, there <i>is</i>&nbsp;music playing.<br /><br />Following that article, I talked about encoded and embodied sounds, the ~*Universal Language*~ of music and how music in games, rather than speaking about the actions occurring <i>now</i>, may be more important in telling the player what will happen <i>next</i>: in the case of Limbo especially, blaring horns signal significant events, echoing splashes mean you're moving deeper into an enormous lonely world.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xpmvxtRvu9E/TzDJwo1gXCI/AAAAAAAAAo0/XXvw6iYdY3Q/s1600/wordloops.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="512" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-xpmvxtRvu9E/TzDJwo1gXCI/AAAAAAAAAo0/XXvw6iYdY3Q/s640/wordloops.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">a screenshot of wordloops</td></tr></tbody></table><br />I finished by showing them the game <a href="http://axcho.com/">Alex</a>&nbsp;programmed for the most recent Global Game Jam; something called <a href="http://axcho.com/wordloops">Wordloops</a>, based on this year's theme of "ouroboros."&nbsp;&nbsp;The idea is that you connect words together, starting the next word on the letter the previous word ended with, and after you fill certain criteria you "complete the loop" and proceed on to Loop N+1. &nbsp;Alex told me that it's much better to make loops of small words, since you're trying to get the most loops out of 3 minutes of play, but I personally found it really satisfying to make nice, long, wandering loops, and one of the students helped me see why: it's because when you type a letter, a sound plays, and that sound goes higher the more letters you play. &nbsp;It's the sound of <i>increasing</i>, <i>progressing,</i>&nbsp;<i>getting better</i>. &nbsp;And it's at odds with the idea that<i>&nbsp;the smaller loop is best</i>.<br /><br />Sounds!<br /><b><br /></b><br /><b>Sources</b><br /><ul><li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/2263/gdc_2005_report_what_makes_music_.php">Gamasutra: GDC 2005 Report: What Makes Music for Games 'Music For Games'</a></li><li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/2232/postcard_from_gdc_2005_gdc_mobile_.php">Gamasutra:&nbsp;Postcard From GDC 2005: GDC Mobile - Novel Ways to Use Audio in Games</a></li><li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/2189/enhancing_the_impact_of_music_in_.php">Gamasutra: Enhancing the Impact of Music in Drama-Oriented Games</a></li></ul></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[PSCS] Game Design Class 4: Winning, Hardcore vs Casual, and Gameplay Depth]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/01/30/pscs-game-design-class-week-4/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/01/30/pscs-game-design-class-week-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<i>This quarter I am facilitating a game design class at Puget Sound Community School for fun and lols. &nbsp;This is my story.</i><br /><br /><i>Other weeks can be found <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/search/label/pscs">here</a>.</i><br /><br />I'm a little belated with this post, if not just because I personally felt "meh" about it (which probably means that it might have been worse for the students themselves). &nbsp;Firstly, we critiqued Making Monkeys.<br /><br /><table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eyjfrSSrYVU/Tyd9DbYC5xI/AAAAAAAAAoc/HBrzqgLtUhs/s1600/makingmonkeys.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="460" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eyjfrSSrYVU/Tyd9DbYC5xI/AAAAAAAAAoc/HBrzqgLtUhs/s640/makingmonkeys.jpg" width="640" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">screenshot of making monkeys, by <a href="http://greg-anims.com/">greg-anims</a></td></tr></tbody></table><br />The general consensus was that it was fun, unique, challenging. &nbsp;We pointed out the nice progression of the levels -- each one had something new to learn -- and talked about the types of rewards and goals in the design: the short-term win of the coffee cup, the long-term win of the entire game with your progress laid out visibly. &nbsp;The little narratives acted as both a silly reward for the previous level and a hint for the upcoming level. &nbsp;Some students found bugs but I didn't write any of them down, so they're Lost in Time and Space now.<br /><br />I couldn't think of a topic that I felt like discussing, so I chose <a href="http://onlyagame.typepad.com/only_a_game/2006/03/performance_met.html">this article</a> at random from a list of game design resources <a href="http://evolutionlive.blogspot.com/">Alex</a> gave me and just tried to talk about it, whiteboard and all. &nbsp;It was not too compelling and people were distracted, probably because "me talking" wasn't that intriguing.<br /><br />I switched topics then to the difference between "hardcore" and "casual" gaming, just to see what people thought of it (again referencing <a href="http://onlyagame.typepad.com/only_a_game/2007/08/game-literacy.html">another article from Only a Game</a>). &nbsp;Some of the students were adamant that the labels didn't mean anything, that "people just love games" and stereotypes seek to destroy the simple, human integrity of us all, to which I agree, kinda. &nbsp;I've always felt something snubby about declarations of <i>I'm a hardcore gamer </i>when all the game companies I've worked at have legitimate, game-loving audiences who can play just as much as any COD player, just doesn't relish the violence or complexity of it.<br /><br />An interesting term I learned in relation to the hardcore/casual duality was the idea of "game literacy;" that maybe an important delineation between hardcore and casual is not necessarily the time spent playing, or the motivations, but the breadth of game knowledge in general, and the ease with which one could pick up another game.<br /><br />Another idea was "game depth," and I tried to tie this together with ideas of winning and losing from earlier -- what happens in games when you "never really lose," but just have opportunities to achieve better, a la Angry Birds? &nbsp;What kind of decisions can you make in a game that is shallow, and one that has depth? &nbsp;How important are those decisions to the game itself? &nbsp;In Angry Birds, you can choose your angle and your velocity; in Tetris, your rotatation and speed; in a game like Magic, you can choose your deck, your strategy, your technique. &nbsp;It always seems like games with depth are "better," but I adore Limbo and concede that it's shallow gameplay-wise -- you solve the puzzles, you get to the end, that's it. &nbsp;I love story, but "Game" in its unique form is something that can be cooked and devoured a thousand times and still taste different the thousand and first.</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Ascension Pre-Release Winningness]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/01/30/dark-ascension-pre-release-winningness/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/01/30/dark-ascension-pre-release-winningness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-szKW5qj_m14/TybP6QCSKkI/AAAAAAAAAoU/S9MQMemd3nY/s1600/IMG_0217%255B1%255D.JPG" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="320" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-szKW5qj_m14/TybP6QCSKkI/AAAAAAAAAoU/S9MQMemd3nY/s320/IMG_0217%255B1%255D.JPG" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">the coveted booster packs</td></tr></tbody></table><br />This past Saturday I went to my first sealed tournament for the pre-release of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_Ascension">Dark Ascension</a>!  We went to Greenlake Games first with a couple of friends, where every table had a nice mat and every participant received a nifty Companion Cube-looking <a href="http://irondie.com/">Irondie</a>.<br /><br />Sealed competitions go like this:<br /><ol><li>Get 6 packs of cards (in this case, 3 of Dark Ascension, 3 of Innistrad)</li><li>Open everything</li><li>Make a 40-card deck</li><li>FIGHT</li></ol>First pack rare: Geist of Saint Traft.  <em>AHHHH</em>.  And in the same pack: Instigator Gang!<br /><br />I was also excited to try and get some <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/01/mtg-lambholt-elder.html">Lambholt Elders</a> and ended up just getting three of them in all of my Dark Ascension packs (and even a holographic one!).<br /><br />In the end I created a green/white deck splashing both blue and red for Geist and Instigator.  I've never tried to use four colors before and felt super risky (oftentimes I would take a 5-mana hand just because I had all the colors in it), but when I was not completely mana-screwed I actually did fairly well!  I won three of my four sets and won six extra booster packs.<br /><br />Some memorable moments:<br /><ul><li>In one game: I attacked with Pitchburn Devils, dealt 3 damage to the other player, then next turn brought Pitchburn back with Haunted Fengraf, sacrificed him to equip Somberwald Dryad with Demonmail Hauberk, dealt 3 damage to the other player, then swung with Somberwald who was unblockable due to Forestwalk.  The last point of damage was done by casting Fling and sacrificing my 1/2 Lambholt Elder, haha.</li><li>In my last game: me and the other player were down to <em>dat wire</em>, him with a Galvanic Juggernaut that kept coming back upright with the undying death of his Young Wolf.  I took three hits for 15 damage from the Juggernaut but then was at exactly 5 health, which triggered the Fateful Hour of my Thraben Doomsayer and buffed both my Silverpelt Werewolf and Somberwald Dryad.  It was close until Andou came by to check out our game and realized that we had both forgotten all about the Fateful hour for the Village Survivors that I had out, since it was covered up by a Chant of the Skifsang -- at which point I swung with all my Vigilant creatures and it was over.</li><li>In another game: my first hand had two plains, three forests, a Thraben Doomsayer, and a Gravetiller Wurm.  Over the course of the next couple turns I spawned a human, brought Gravetiller in with Morbid, equipped him with a Demonmail Hauberk and some more Morbid counters thanks to a Hunger of the Howlpack and another human token, and, there it was: a massive 15/13 monster trampling everywhere.</li></ul><br />I have Lorin to thank for making full use of Demonmail, since he cleaned me out with it at <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2011/12/mtg-my-second-ever-draft.html">our last draft</a> and before that point I hadn't made the connection between Demonmail and how easy it made triggering Morbid since I could sacrifice a creature whenever I wished.  Andou read some of the design notes for this set to me; the point of Dark Ascension is that everything is getting dark and awful and worse, the world is teeming with monsters, and I definitely felt the design encouraging me to kill things, to take advantage of death, especially of that of meager 1/1 Human tokens.  Fateful Hour was also fun to trigger, though being at the point of death stresses me out, and in general during all the games playing with strangers I could feel my hands shaking with competitive tension.<br /><br />Later our group went over to The Dreaming to do <em>another</em> sealed tourney, but I didn't do so well in that one, so, the only memorable moment I've got is when Andou pulled a Huntmaster of the Fells and later gave it to me.  Dark Ascension werewolves, here I come!<br /><br /><br /><b>Decklist</b><br /><i>Creatures</i><br />3x Lambholt Elder<br />1x Pitchburn Devils<br />1x Instigator Gang<br />1x Geistcatcher's Rig<br />1x Village Survivors<br />1x Gravetiller Wurm<br />1x Somberwald Dryad<br />1x Thraben Doomsayer<br />1x Geist of Saint Traft<br /><br /><i>Spells/Artifacts</i><br />1x Fling<br />1x Gather the Townsfolk<br />1x Hunger of the Howlpack<br />1x Ghostly Possession<br />1x Skillful Lunge<br />1x Curse of Stalked Prey<br />1x Burning Oil<br />1x Demonmail Hauberk<br />1x Midnight Haunting<br />1x Bonds of Faith<br /><i><br /></i><i>Lands</i><br />6x Forest<br />6x Plains<br />3x Island <br />2x Mountain<br />1x Evolving Wilds<br />1x Haunted Fengraf</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Story in Trauma Team]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2012/01/24/story-in-trauma-team</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s1600/traumateam.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" height="163" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hF7YgN3Sz78/Tx5OhSPLPuI/AAAAAAAAAn8/GiVkHn416xw/s320/traumateam.jpg" width="320" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.joystiq.com/2010/04/28/trauma-team-wii-review/">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br />Time saved from <a href="http://nuubu.blogspot.com/2012/01/past-couple-days-in-series-of-instagram.html">not commuting during snowpacalypse</a>&nbsp;was spent playing Trauma Team, which I ordered (according to this hastily searched-up Amazon receipt) last March. &nbsp;(Spoilers ahead.)<br /><br />I adore the time-management micro-activities of Trauma Center, but was still surprised to find out how much I flat-out <i>enjoyed </i>Trauma Team. &nbsp;The fakey manga cutscenes re-used a lot of character art and implemented some tricks (scaling and translating a car, for example, instead of an actual animation of it driving off into the sunset), but I still enjoyed it much more than any dead-eyed mannequin gestures that seem to fill up so much of the cutscenes I've glanced in super-budget games nowadays (though to be completely honest, I haven't really sat down and played a lot of them).<br /><br />Cutscenes aside, Trauma Team did a good job of conveying story through its actual gameplay, some memorable scenes being:<br /><ol><li>The part in the mall where Maria, the "first response" character, has to take care of five dying patients on her own. &nbsp;I love getting perfect scores on these games and every time someone died I quit and started over in frustration. &nbsp;I even left the mini-game to try another story-line, and returned later with a feeling of dread -- only to realize that it was rigged. &nbsp;The patients were <i>supposed</i>&nbsp;to be near-death; once you rushed through at least one of them, back-up would arrive and restore everyone to full health, bringing a once-impossible situation to now a somewhat calming one (complete with soothing, <i>don't worry, your friends are here </i>music). &nbsp;For that moment, I really <i>was</i>&nbsp;Maria, and experiencing her prime character flaw of over-independence, of trying to do everything myself. &nbsp;(Until struck the inevitable Japanese group-focused armature of "Let's all work together!")</li><li>The part where Gabe is diagnosing the soldier, who is struggling to be-"bro" you in an attempt to make it seem you have having "<i>meaningless, friendly conversation</i>" when in reality you are in the process of diagnosing his viral hemorrhagic fever. &nbsp;In this case, the characters speaking to each other and working together were embedded in the "verbal questioning" mini-game, which was pretty elegant -- a lot more elegant than just clicking through conversation, though the mini-game itself probably lent itself to storytelling pretty easily.</li></ol><div>Sometimes you could just <i>see </i>the inconsistencies between Japanese thought and expectation of the US, and how it "really is." An easy example is when the characters were at the mall -- shopping for groceries, which is fairly typical in malls in Asia, and not so much here.<br /><br />Another example: unlike many US-developed games, this game set in America had a refreshing amount of ethnic diversity in the main character cast. &nbsp;Can you name a character who was a Mexican woman off the top of your head? &nbsp;One for whom it didn't really&nbsp;<i>matter</i>&nbsp;that she had dark skin, one who wasn't "stereotypically Mexican?" &nbsp;How about a character who is potentially Native American? The Mexican character was, unfortunately, the subject of many a boob-shot, and was also pretty frustratingly&nbsp;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tsundere">tsundere</a>&nbsp;at times; and in general the females all had the same, petite facial structure. &nbsp;Personality-wise, though, they were all strong and interesting, with motives that 100% did not involve getting with the men around them. &nbsp;(Though there was a bit of Maria/That Dark Brooding guy near the end...before he went back to his lifestyle of alternating between doing surgeries and jail-time.)<br /><br />Some bonus fangirling: the best part of this game, hands-down, were Kimishima's cases. &nbsp;I <i>loved</i>&nbsp;piecing together the facts, figuring out how someone had died (though most of them were pretty straight-forward), learning about Kimishima's weird "I can hear the dead" cellphone and the fact that other characters accepted that she had such a device without complaint ("You and your voodoo cellphone..."). &nbsp;Gabe Cunningham's voice actor (apparently <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Travis_Willingham">the same as for Roy in Full Metal Alchemist</a>) had <i>so much life</i>&nbsp;(the best part being when he sang "chunky~~" at the American politician). &nbsp;Also, Atlus's bold, colorful interfaces are so&nbsp;fun to interact with.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
