<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tumblr | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/categories/tumblr/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://neauro.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-08T20:13:04-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://neauro.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Tumblr: Delightful UX]]></title>
    <link href="http://neauro.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/delightful-ux/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-07T14:39:07-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://neauro.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/delightful-ux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/delightful-ux.png" alt="Screenshot of delightful-ux.tumblr.com"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com">via</a>)</p>


<p>For whatever reason, <a href="http://tumblr.com">Tumblr</a> is becoming my social media site of choice, probably because its humor appeals to me so much. I also love that it supports people easily creating blogs that cater to specific topics &mdash; like <a href="http://medievalpoc.tumblr.com/">people of color in medieval art</a>, or <a href="http://moviecode.tumblr.com/">source code in TV and films</a>, or <a href="http://tabcloseddidntread.com/">intrusive pop-ups</a>.</p>

<p>Anyway, I&rsquo;ve made my own tumblr for gathering examples of <a href="http//delightful-ux.tumblr.com">delightful user experience</a>, which is my main interest when it comes to the wide world of human-centered design. Even though I love it, I&rsquo;m still muddy on what comprises a delightful user experience, and thus far have tossed in examples of <a href="http://adobe.breach.il.ly/#/about">useful websites with friendly wording</a>, as well as <a href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com/post/71660750263/hells-pizza-coffin-box-new-zealand-based-hell">pizza box designs with unnecessary but awesome utility</A>, and <a href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com/post/71681828062/australian-sharks-send-tweets-to-warn-swimmers">sharks with Twitter accounts</a>.</p>

<p>For now, when deciding whether to add an example, I ask myself, &ldquo;Could this Thing accomplish what it currently accomplishes, but in a more boring way?&rdquo; Or, &ldquo;Does this Thing solve for an action that is not-that-fun to do?&rdquo; And if the answer to either is &ldquo;yes!&rdquo; — lo, thusly do I deem it delightful.</p>

<p>I understand that second question might still catch Things that are not entirely playful — but I&rsquo;m not going to stress out about differentiating between design that&rsquo;s good and design that fulfills some nebulously defined good feel.</p>

<p>If you have encountered a good feel recently yourself, feel free to <a href="http://delightful-ux.tumblr.com/submit">submit</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
