<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Book Review | liwanag]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/categories/book-review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-16T19:43:58-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.neauro.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[nadine a.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books: His Fair Assassin, Robin LaFevers]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/15/his-fair-series/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-15T09:57:36-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2014/01/15/his-fair-series</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/dark_triumph_cover.jpg" alt="Cover of Dark Triumph"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9943270-dark-triumph">via</a>)</p>




<blockquote>Seventeen-year-old Ismae escapes from the brutality of an arranged marriage into the sanctuary of the convent of St. Mortain, where the sisters still serve the gods of old. Here she learns that the god of Death Himself has blessed her with dangerous gifts—and a violent destiny. If she chooses to stay at the convent, she will be trained as an assassin and serve as a handmaiden to Death. To claim her new life, she must destroy the lives of others.
<br/><br/>

Ismae’s most important assignment takes her straight into the high court of Brittany—where she finds herself woefully under prepared—not only for the deadly games of intrigue and treason, but for the impossible choices she must make. For how can she deliver Death’s vengeance upon a target who, against her will, has stolen her heart?
<Br/><br/>

— Grave Mercy</blockquote>




<blockquote>
When Sybella arrived at the doorstep of St Mortain half mad with grief and despair the convent were only too happy to offer her refuge - but at a price. The sisters of this convent serve Death, and with Sybella naturally skilled in both the arts of death and seduction, she could become one of their most dangerous weapons.
<br/><br/>
But her assassin's skills are little comfort when the convent returns her to the life that nearly drove her mad. Her father's rage and brutality are terrifying, and her brother's love is equally monstrous. But when Sybella discovers an unexpected ally she discovers that a daughter of Death may find something other than vengeance to live for...
<Br/><br/> 
— Dark Triumph</blockquote>


<p>A coworker lent me <em>Grave Mercy</em> and <em>Dark Triumph</em>, the books currently released in the <em>His Fair Assassin</em> trilogy, and I devoured them both in less than a week. They were delicious.</p>

<p>The books are set in Brittany, at a time when it is fighting for its independence against the French. There&rsquo;s a lot of political intrigue, and, as Goodreads is fond of saying, &ldquo;magical assassin nuns,&rdquo; who are the main characters of the books. Overall, they&rsquo;re fun characters to read about, poisons and daggers and conflicts and struggles all. They navigate politics, relationships, and their own identities and duties.</p>

<p>(TW) As a warning, these books contain a lot of sexual assault, especially the second book, whose protagonist, Sybella, is a survivor. Whereas sexual assault in stories is something I often eyeroll at due to its prevalent use as a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=toa_vH6xGqs">grimdark fridging mechanism</a>, the use of sexual assault in <em>His Fair Assassin</em> wasn&rsquo;t trivialized, dramaticized, or used to further the motivations of another character. Sexual assault is a horrible act, and when victim-blaming occurs it is struck down as wrong. Both books explore women making choices about their sexuality, with consenting, supportive partners.</p>

<p>(It seems weird to even write the above paragraph. Like, shouldn&rsquo;t this just be <em>the way it is</em>? It seems strange to praise a book so highly for meeting what should be common guidlines for decency. Anyway. <em>His Fair Assassin</em> nails it.)</p>

<p>Something that I felt these books were lacking were that they took for granted my knowledge of European history. For example, why is Brittany rebelling against France? I wonder if Brittany&rsquo;s rebellion is just something that Everyone is aware of already; even so, it would have been nice to have in-book examples of why a French takeover would be so bad. It would&rsquo;ve also been nice to see more reasons why everyone was so willing to devote their lives to a twelve-year-old duchess. That everyone was unerringly adoring of her and willing to die for her sake was strange to me, and descriptions of her being &ldquo;wiser than her years&rdquo; didn&rsquo;t quite stand up on its own as a reason to rally behind her, especially when the world is so patriarchal.</p>

<p>This series was one of the rare cases where I loved the second book more than the first. Though I&rsquo;m not totally sure where LaFevers will go with her third book — as its protagonist, Annith, has thus far been a predictably innocent character — I&rsquo;m excited for it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire, Kristin Cashore]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/16/fire/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-16T12:36:17-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/16/fire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/cover_fire.jpg" alt="Fire cover"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6137154-fire?from_search=true">via</a>)</p>




<blockquote><p>It is not a peaceful time in the Dells. The young King Nash clings to his throne while rebel lords in the north and south build armies to unseat him. The mountains and forests are filled with spies and thieves and lawless men.</p>

<p>This is where Fire lives. With a wild, irresistible appearance and hair the color of flame, Fire is the last remaining human monster. Equally hated and adored, she had the unique ability to control minds, but she guards her power, unwilling to steal the secrets of innocent people. Especially when she has so many of her own.</p>

<p>Then Prince Brigan comes to bring her to King City, The royal family needs her help to uncover the plot against the king. Far away from home, Fire begins to realize there's more to her power than she ever dreamed. Her power could save the kingdom.</p>

<p>If only she weren't afraid of becoming the monster her father was.</p></blockquote>


<p>[spoilers below]</p>

<p><em>Fire</em> was alright. I liked the strangeness of monsters and their many colors; I liked all the politics, the twist that Fire had killed her own father and the general confusion of royal bloodlines. As in <em><a href="/blog/2013-12-16-graceling/"/>Graceling</a></em>, the non-drama of sexual relationships is a relief. While reading, I hated Archer for being a posessive male character that we are meant to sympathize with; but thinking back, I don&rsquo;t think that his possessive behavior was ever excused by the story&hellip;except, I guess, for Fire&rsquo;s musing about how her innate monster beauty may have compelled Archer to become as horribly possessive as he was. This is uncomfortable because of its similarity to modern &ldquo;victim-blaming&rdquo; narratives, even if <em>Fire</em> explores Fire&rsquo;s strange ability to compel all humans when they look at her, not just men. It&rsquo;s also nice to see a romance not totally typical of YA: a non-virgin woman who falls in love with a man who already has a child.</p>

<p>One downside is that the voice of Fire herself doesn&rsquo;t differ too much from Katsa&rsquo;s in <em>Graceling</em>. Fire feels like a parallel universe Katsa, whose story ultimately isn&rsquo;t as interesting. One of the main reasons I was so attracted to the <em>Graceling</em> was — well — the Graces — and since the Dell doesn&rsquo;t have them, and since Katsa&rsquo;s world doesn&rsquo;t have monsters, this book feels like it&rsquo;s set in an entirely different universe. There&rsquo;s none of the excitement of familiarity, the fun of adding to the breadth and meaning of <em>Graceling</em>&rsquo;s world. The one connection between <em>Graceling</em> and <em>Fire</em> is Leck, but we barely know him from the first book, and I&rsquo;m not interested in any mysteries about how he came to be, since by the end of <em>Graceling</em> he&rsquo;s already dead. Leck&rsquo;s descent into sadism in <em>Fire</em> isn&rsquo;t particularly complex, either; he is shown to be a sociopath from the very beginning, and all interactions that he has with Fire feel tacked on and separate from Fire&rsquo;s own character growth. Had there been more of a commonality with <em>Graceling</em>, <em>Fire</em> would have been more of a hit with me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graceling, Kristin Cashore]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/16/graceling/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-16T11:26:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/12/16/graceling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="book-cover" src="/images/cover_graceling.jpg" alt="Graceling cover"/></p>

<p class="caption">(<A href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3236307-graceling">via</a>)</p>




<blockquote><p>Katsa has been able to kill a man with her bare hands since she was eight - she's a Graceling, one of the rare people in her land born with an extreme skill. As niece of the king, she should be able to live a life of privilege, but Graced as she is with killing, she is forced to work as the king's thug.</p>

<p>When she first meets Prince Po, Graced with combat skills, Katsa has no hint of how her life is about to change.</p>

<p>She never expects to become Po's friend.</p>

<p>She never expects to learn a new truth about her own Grace - or about a terrible secret that lies hidden far away...</p></blockquote>


<p>[spoilers below]</p>

<p>I finished <em>Graceling</em> and its companions in less than a week. I liked them — I liked the fairytale-ish turn of phrases (&ldquo;she had one eye blue and one eye green&rdquo;), the strangeness and OPness of Graces, the nondrama of sexual relationships. In <em>Graceling</em>, I can see how Katsa comes to like Po, and how her attraction to him is unique to her and her situation — being unable to trust that she wouldn&rsquo;t hurt anyone, he gives her a situation in which she can finally be herself.</p>

<p>The pacing was a little strange. One chapter near the beginning is devoted to exposition about the world, and is incredibly difficult to read through: there are so many new names to remember, so much information that gets in the way of the action I wanted to return to. The ending of the story drops suddenly as well: after Katsa primes the pirates to be ready for Leck&rsquo;s possible attack, it turns out Leck has already arrived at her supposed safehaven. Some of the motivations were tough for me to understand as well. How did Katsa and Po know so abruptly that Bitterblue was to be protected, at the cost of their own life? If Katsa was so adamant about not having children, why did she feel so strongly protective of Bitterblue? (I understand that you can not want to have children, and still like them; but there wasn&rsquo;t much other evidence for why Katsa would take to Bitterblue so strongly, especially given the distance with which she seemed to hold other acquaintances.) Why was Po ashamed of being blind? In fact, what was the purpose of those chapters at the end where the main Leck-related conflict has already been resolved, and all that&rsquo;s left is to angst about Po&rsquo;s blindness?</p>

<p>Overall <em>Graceling</em> was an entertaining read, and all the more fun because Katsa&rsquo;s &ldquo;true&rdquo; Grace was hinted at pretty well and it was fun to figure out for yourself what her talent actually was. I&rsquo;m also a fan of how she worked out what sort of relationship that she wanted with Po in the end, though, like with Brave, I felt a little dissonance with what she perceived marriage to be. It&rsquo;s strange to read fantasy and sit tight for explanations of multiple kingdoms and magic powers — and yet never be told why there are such conservative constructions of marriage, and why they have remained unchallenged. The limitations that we have in Real Life — patriarchy, religious morals — aren&rsquo;t elaborated on in <em>Graceling</em> and some other fantasy novels. It&rsquo;s strange to read books where misogyny exists because that&rsquo;s &ldquo;just the the way it is,&rdquo; even if characters challenge it later.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Allegiant, Veronica Roth]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/19/allegiant/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-19T20:40:01-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/11/19/allegiant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well! It&rsquo;s over.</p>

<p>I download <em>Allegiant</em> from the Seattle Public Library&rsquo;s eBook collection as soon as it became available, and read it over the course of a couple days, despite the looming presence of NaNoWriMo (which I&rsquo;ve been keeping track of in <a href="http://neauro.tumblr.com/tagged/nnwm2013">my Tumblr</a>).</p>

<p>[spoilers ahead]</p>

<p>To be honest, I don&rsquo;t have much to say about it. The writing wasn&rsquo;t that interesting. There are a smattering of issues that other reviews have already discussed — such as how Tris and Four&rsquo;s voices were barely distinguishable from each other, something especially tough to deal with when reading on a Kindle. In some places <em>Allegiant</em> felt repetitive. Tris was repeatedly described as either &ldquo;small&rdquo; or &ldquo;pale,&rdquo; and it felt like eyes carried many of the discussions in this book. (Though I admit I&rsquo;m not overly fond in the first place of eyes described as communicating incredibly detailed emotions.)</p>

<blockquote>Now she looks pale and small, but her eyes make me think of wide-open skies that I have never actually seen, only dreamed of.</blockquote>




<blockquote>There is a wavering expression in her eyes, like she is a heap of leaves about to be scattered by the wind.</blockquote>




<blockquote>He has kept his eyes averted since I sat in the chair and they cut the strip of plastic binding my wrists together. For just for a moment, his eyes touch mine, and I know it’s time to start lying.</blockquote>




<blockquote>Her fingers are on his throat, taking his pulse, and her eyes are wide and empty. […] Her dark eyes are wide with fear as she says, “Are you hurt?”</blockquote>




<blockquote>She looks up at me, her eyes clear and eager.</blockquote>




<blockquote>She smiles, but her eyes are glassy, like a dormant part of her is fighting its way out and spilling over.</blockquote>


<p>I wasn&rsquo;t too interested in the big reveal of genetic tampering. Because it was just barely related to any events or concepts introduced in earlier books, it felt totally out of the blue. I could force a connection if I tried hard enough — maybe all the genetic stuff plays into the significance in earlier books about how &ldquo;one choice can define you&rdquo; —  but ultimately the genetic experiments felt unpleasantly disconnected and abrupt. Reveals are exciting and fun when you anticipate them, when you look back and realize that all the signs pointed toward them; not when they just slap you in the face under the guise of being totally mind-blowing.</p>

<p>I was also disappointed that two of the more obvious characters of color — Tori Wu, and Uriah — were killed off. Uriah&rsquo;s death acted solely as a catalyst for more of Four&rsquo;s angst, which he had enough of already, between worrying about his parents and worrying about his genetic purity. Tori&rsquo;s death accomplished nothing but the sorrow of a secondary character I hardly knew. Their deaths felt like a lazy way to get a rise out of the reader by taking away characters that had always been &ldquo;good people.&rdquo;</p>

<p>This is the way that I feel about Tris&rsquo;s death as well. Her final reason for sacrificing herself wasn&rsquo;t related to anything else that she desired so desperately in the book: for her community to not die, for her to be with Four. I do like the twist in her character — how she first chose Dauntless, and then, in the end, chose again to be selfless Abegnation — but because I didn&rsquo;t see how it fit into an overall theme for the third book, this too felt like a cheap way to get me to have emotions about what was going on.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve tried a couple times now to explain more about why the ending of Allegiant was so disappointing to me, but I&rsquo;ve found <a href="http://myallegiantreview.blogspot.com/2013/11/breaking-down-ending-to-allegiant.html">this blog post</a> that has already done all of the (super comprehensive) work.</p>

<p>The fact that this ending has, for many readers, &ldquo;ruined the entire series&rdquo; also reminds me of <a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/daniel_kahneman_the_riddle_of_experience_vs_memory.html">this TED Talk</a>, in which the speaker talks about how the end of an experience can ruin the entire thing.</p>

<blockquote>But now there is another question: "How much did these patients think they suffered?" And here is a surprise. The surprise is that Patient A had a much worse memory of the colonoscopy than Patient B. The stories of the colonoscopies were different, and because a very critical part of the story is how it ends. And neither of these stories is very inspiring or great -- but one of them is this distinct ... (Laughter) but one of them is distinctly worse than the other. And the one that is worse is the one where pain was at its peak at the very end; it's a bad story. How do we know that? Because we asked these people after their colonoscopy, and much later, too, "How bad was the whole thing, in total?" And it was much worse for A than for B, in memory.</blockquote>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Thought My Father Was God: And Other True Tales, NPR National Story Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/16/i-thought-my-father-was-god-and-other/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.neauro.com/blog/2013/09/16/i-thought-my-father-was-god-and-other</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
<table align="center" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="tr-caption-container" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; text-align: center;"><tbody><tr><td style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-oYqP_v-5c7M/UjerqjIrGlI/AAAAAAAAECE/M4ABcNm-wNw/s1600/50617.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"><img border="0" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-oYqP_v-5c7M/UjerqjIrGlI/AAAAAAAAECE/M4ABcNm-wNw/s320/50617.jpg" /></a></td></tr><tr><td class="tr-caption" style="text-align: center;">(<a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50617.I_Thought_My_Father_Was_God_and_Other_True_Tales_from_NPR_s_National_Story_Project">source</a>)</td></tr></tbody></table><br /><blockquote>The true-life stories in this unique collection provide "a window into the American mind and heart" (<i>The Daily News</i>). One hundred and eighty voices - male and female, young and old, from all walks of life and all over the country - talk intimately to the reader. Combining great humor and pathos this remarkable selection of stories from the thousands submitted to NPR's Weekend <i>All Things Considered</i> National Story Project gives the reader a glimpse of America's soul in all its diversity.</blockquote><br /><div class="p1"><i>I Thought My Father was God </i>is a compilation of short stories submitted by listeners to NPR's National Story Project, and is fantastic. The events of each story are poignant in their mundanity; the fact that some of these stories were carried throughout the years and then threaded into words gives them a special impact, even if the events themselves are ordinary.</div><div class="p2"><br /></div><div class="p1">I was the third to be passed this book, after S and A, who read it over the course of several weeks. They found the stories too emotionally heavy to read more than a handful at a time; I found them too delicious to restrain myself. Each story is a good example of how small moments in someone's life can resonate through years, through actions, through all parts of you; each one reminds me of the impact my own actions can make, however small, and reminds me the the lives of people around me are larger than the glances we exchange as we pass by on the sidewalk.</div><br /><div class="p1">My favorite story is <i>Iceman of Market Street</i>, especially given recent discussions about <a href="http://grist.org/cities/the-dark-side-of-startup-city/">the dark side of San Francisco's transformations</a>.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
